<DOC    id="ENG_NW_001278_20130117_F00012AFP">
<DATE_TIME>2013-01-17T15:24:01</DATE_TIME>
<HEADLINE>
China Focus: Government economy drive cools holiday hospitality sector
</HEADLINE>
<AUTHOR>姬少亭,蔡敏,杨丁淼</AUTHOR>
<TEXT>
China Focus: Government economy drive cools holiday hospitality sector

HEFEI, Jan. 17 (Xinhua) -- Young couple Zhang Ben and Wu Luanluan were surprised at being able to hold their wedding banquet in a hotel that simultaneously hosted two political sessions on the same day.

The openings of the local people's congress and people's political consultative conference would normally have been grand affairs taking over the whole of a venue like the one Zhang and Ben used in Fuyang City in central China's Anhui Province earlier this month.

However, with much-publicized central government orders for officials to reject extravagance, the usual conference hospitality was simplified into a buffet and the dining hall was saved for the wedding. Deputies and CPPCC members who passed by even got a chance to congratulate the new husband and wife.

Many members of the public are likely to have similar experiences over the coming weeks, as officials' economy drives this year slow demand in the service sector. The approaching Chinese New Year usually sees a lot of public funds spent on officials' eating and drinking, at a time of conspicuous consumption across China.

However, all that has changed following the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China. Its newly elected leadership has pledged to reduce spending on hospitality and trim bureaucratic visits and meetings. The Political Bureau of the Communist Party of China Central Committee in early December introduced eight rules to change officials' work style.

More than 20 provinces have released detailed regulations to crack down on the three most-criticized uses of public funds for private purposes -- cars, banquets and overseas visits.

For example, the Anhui provincial government in late December issued a notice to ban officials from using governmental vehicles during the New Year festival and spring festival.

The governments of Gansu, Hubei and Fujian limited overseas visits to no more than once a year and banned personal tourism with public money.

No official banquets are allowed in Zhejiang Province and no alcohol is to be served during officials' meals. Officials of provincial government should eat at canteens when visiting lower-level governments.

In Xinjiang Uygur Autonomous Region, meal times during work visits have been limited to 45 minutes.

While people like Zhang Ben and Wu Luanluan are getting more access to in-demand restaurants and hotels, the service industry is feeling the effect of government cut-backs.

"This time used to be a peak for governmental annual meetings. But this year is gloomy. Only a few companies have chosen us and dining bookings are mostly for family meals," says the marketing manager of a five-star hotel in Hefei, capital of Anhui, who declined to be named.

The regulations have also turned peak seasons into off-seasons for other businesses like gift firms and travel agencies which typically have a lot of clients spending public funds.

"Orders dropped 50 percent this year. We have not even had many people coming to make enquiries," Zhen Fei, head of Hefei Lanhe Gift Company, sighs of the build-up to Chinese New Year.

High-end gifts used to be loved by government departments; however, customers are now choosing simple items like cups or notebooks, according to Zhen.

"It is getting harder to do business," he says.

Travel agencies have lost many group orders from government departments, while companies and families have become their main clients.

"The regulations and public supervision have meant that government departments dare not cross the line," says Yang Xiaoling, deputy manager of Anhui Global International Travel Co. Ltd..

A "fresh new style" has been forming among officials, according to Yuan Longsheng of the local government in Yancheng City in Jiangsu Province.

Although spending of public funds has been largely reduced, Yuan believes it is possible that it could edge back up if the crackdown is not maintained.

"It has been a chronic illness. Implementation should be tough this time," he urges.

This illness had been treated with many methods in past years but the results were limited, according to Cheng Wenhao, professor of Tsinghua University's School of Public Policy and Management and director of its Anti-Corruption and Governance Research Center.

The new regulations from central and local governments have been targeted at the core of the problems, an approach which has refreshed the work style in China, Cheng says.

Cheng also points out that to fundamentally solve the problems, more policies should be established on financial management and transparency of government affairs.

Public supervision should be courageous to report corruption, and real punishment should be carried out to warn others, the academic adds.   Enditem
</TEXT>
</DOC>
