<DOC    id="ENG_NW_001278_20130828_F00011S1X">
<DATE_TIME>2013-08-28T04:27:29</DATE_TIME>
<HEADLINE>
UN aid supplies arrive in north Iraq for Syrian refugees
</HEADLINE>
<AUTHOR>裴蕾</AUTHOR>
<TEXT>
UN aid supplies arrive in north Iraq for Syrian refugees

UN aid supplies arrive in north Iraq for Syrian refugees

UNITED NATIONS, Aug. 27 (Xinhua) -- A chartered flight carrying urgent relief items for Syrian refugees has arrived in the Iraqi city of Erbil, a UN spokesperson said on Tuesday.

The aid supplies are for the World Food Program (WFP) and the UN Refugee Agency (UNHCR) to meet "the immediate humanitarian needs of Syrian refugees fleeing the violence in Syria and crossing into northern Iraq," associate UN spokesman Farhan Haq told the press at a daily briefing.

The flight, chartered by WFP, includes 340 family tents, 42 metric tonnes of high energy biscuits and 15 metric tonnes of special nutrition bars contributed by the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID). The supplies will be distributed by WFP and the Office of the UN High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR).

"More than 44,000 Syrian refugees have crossed into the Kurdish region of northern Iraq since 15 August," said Haq, adding that most of them are women and children sheltered in camps or collective facilities.

In a news release, UNHCR and WFP said most of the newly arrived Syrians have been transferred to Kawergosk camp close to Erbil, which is now home to an estimated 15,000 refugees.

According to UN humanitarian agencies, a second flight is due to arrive in Erbil on Tuesday from Adana, Turkey, with 93 metric tonnes of food, enough to feed 11,500 people for three weeks.

Almost 200,000 Syrian refugees have fled into Iraq since the onset of conflict in Syria in March 2011, with some 30 percent residing in camps and 70 percent living in Iraqi communities.

The Syrian civil war between government forces and armed opposition seeking to oust President Bashar al-Assad, has led to the deaths of more than 93,000 people and forced over 1.7 million people to flee the Middle East country.   Enditem
</TEXT>
</DOC>
