<DOC id="NYT_ENG_20131030.0283" type="story" from_file="/newswire/daily_process/nyt/english/source_data/20131030/20131030,e84917be6258ddaaa851ceb091988e2d.xml">
<HEADLINE>
PHILADELPHIA INQUIRER MAJORITY OWNERS SEEK TO BUY OUT OTHERS
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
<P>
This article is part of TIMES EXPRESS. It is a condensed version of a story that will appear in tomorrow’s New York Times.);
</P>
<P>
After nearly a month of upheaval at The Philadelphia Inquirer, including the firing of the paper’s top editor and lawsuits among its owners, the majority owners Wednesday offered to buy out the minority investors, in what they described as an effort to provide stability to the company.
</P>
<P>
George E. Norcross III and William P. Hankowsky, both majority owners in the Philadelphia Media Network, which also publishes the Philadelphia Daily News and Philly.com, said they wanted to put an end to the infighting. So they offered to buy out two minority investors, H.F. Lenfest and Lewis Katz, for $29 million, which they said represented nearly a 12 percent profit in the 18 months since they made the original investment.
</P>
<P>
“We did not want or initiate the litigation that has created a sideshow that will ultimately waste hundreds of thousands, if not millions, of dollars in legal fees that could be used to further strengthen and build the company,” Norcross and Hankowsky said.
</P>
<P>
Norcross, a Democratic power broker, and Lenfest, a parking lot magnate, were among a group of investors who bought the struggling newspaper in April 2012. The investor group then hired back William K. Marimow, who had served as the Inquirer’s top editor from 2006 to 2010.
</P>
<P>
While there appeared to be conflicts among investors from the start, these battles culminated in Marimow’s firing on Oct. 7. Three days later, Katz and Lenfest sued, claiming that Marimow should be reinstated because the firing took place without their consultation. Then Norcross countersued.
</P>
<P>
Jay Devine, a spokesman representing Katz, Lenfest and Marimow, declined to comment.
</P>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
