<DOC id="NYT_ENG_20131106.0066" type="story" from_file="/newswire/daily_process/nyt/english/source_data/20131106/20131106,364e19d1f0b63ed6f1295b7764261a22.xml">
<HEADLINE>
BILL DE BLASIO: HEADING TO CITY HALL, A LIBERAL USED TO EXCEEDING EXPECTATIONS
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
<P>
This article is part of TIMES EXPRESS. It is a condensed version of a story that will appear in tomorrow’s New York Times.);
</P>
<P>
NEW YORK - The sidewalk outside the subway station in Crown Heights, Brooklyn, was crowded on Tuesday morning. Bill de Blasio bent his 6-foot-5 frame again and again to shake hands.
</P>
<P>
The spot had been chosen with care. It was here, in 1991, that New York City’s deep racial divide had exploded into three days of violence when de Blasio had been a low-level aide to Mayor David N. Dinkins. De Blasio’s opponent this year, Joseph J. Lhota, had pointed to that dark episode as a reason not to vote for him, as a warning of the bad times that were likely to return if he were elected.
</P>
<P>
But there was no strife on Tuesday, no flying bottles. Just handshakes on the way to winning as de Blasio was welcomed as a hero and celebrity. “All I want to say is that I love you,” said a woman in jeans, a denim jacket and a paisley shawl.
</P>
<P>
It was a note-perfect play in a campaign of them, summing up both his sharp political instincts and the changing feel of the city he wanted to run.
</P>
<P>
On Tuesday, de Blasio was elected to become the first Democratic mayor of New York City in 20 years. Few had initially predicted his victory except, perhaps, the candidate himself. In high school, he was known by a nickname, Senator Provolone, and his classmates sometimes hummed “Hail to the Chief” when he entered the room.
</P>
<P>
But throughout his life, de Blasio had come to delight in upsetting expectations.
</P>
<P>
He overcame a troubled childhood and attended some of the country’s most prestigious universities. He married a black woman who once identified as a lesbian, Chirlane McCray, and created a proudly biracial home. He cut his teeth as a political operator but abandoned life as a strategist to make an audacious bid for public office himself.
</P>
<P>
Now, as de Blasio, 52, prepares to become chief executive of one of the world’s largest cities, he will have a far grander stage on which to test the decidedly liberal world view that has been the hallmark of his career.
</P>
<P>
On Tuesday, as de Blasio campaigned in Brooklyn, the centrality of his family to his personal and political life was clear. His daughter, Chiara, who is a college student in California, traveled home to surprise her father. She had told him she would not be able to return because of exams.
</P>
<P>
“This is the greatest gift I could have on Election Day,” de Blasio told reporters. “I’m already floating on air because my daughter’s here with us.”
</P>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
