<DOC id="NYT_ENG_20130925.0184" type="story" from_file="/newswire/daily_process/nyt/english/source_data/20130925/20130925,9e928177cf1abfc37aa5f8e85a4e8549.xml">
<HEADLINE>
BEFORE KENYA ATTACK, REHEARSALS AND PLANTING OF MACHINE GUNS
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
<P>
EDS: SUBS for complete writethru; CHANGES byline; NEW headline.) ; (This article is part of TIMES EXPRESS. It is a condensed version of a story that will appear in tomorrow’s New York Times.);
</P>
<P>
NAIROBI, Kenya - The plot was hatched weeks or months ago on Somali soil, by al-Shabab’s “external operations arm,” officials say. A team of English-speaking foreign fighters was carefully selected, along with a target: Nairobi’s gleaming Westgate mall.
</P>
<P>
The building’s blueprints were studied, down to the ventilation ducts. The attack was rehearsed and the team dispatched, slipping undetected through Kenya’s porous borders, often patrolled by underpaid - and deeply corrupt - border guards.
</P>
<P>
A day or two before the attack, powerful belt-fed machine guns were secretly stashed in a shop in the mall with the help of a colluding employee, officials say. At least one militant had packed a change of clothes so he could slip out with fleeing civilians after the killings were done.
</P>
<P>
That is the picture emerging from American security officials of the massacre at the Westgate mall, which killed scores of people over the weekend. After a four-day standoff, President Uhuru Kenyatta of Kenya claimed Tuesday to have finally “ashamed and defeated our attackers,” declaring that the last militants still holed up inside the mall had been killed, though the bodies of many civilians, perhaps dozens, have yet to be recovered.
</P>
<P>
Kenyatta contended that “intelligence reports had suggested that a British woman and two or three American citizens may have been involved,” but said that he could not confirm those reports. American officials said that they had not determined the identities of the attackers and were awaiting DNA tests and footage from the mall’s security cameras, but that they did know the massacre was meticulously planned to draw “maximum exposure.”
</P>
<P>
“They had people in there, they had stuff inside there,” said an American security official who asked not to be identified because he was not authorized to speak publicly. “This was all ready to go when the shooters walked in.”
</P>
<P>
Kenya is now entering an official three-day mourning period to mark one of the most unsettling episodes in its recent history. The authorities here, in a country widely perceived as an oasis of peace and prosperity in a troubled region, are struggling to answer how 10 to 15 Islamist extremists could lay siege to a shopping mall, killing more than 60 civilians with military-grade weaponry, then hold off Kenyan security forces for days.
</P>
<P>
Western security officials fear that several fighters slipped out of the mall during the mayhem of the attack, dropping their guns and disguising themselves as civilians, an account echoed by some witnesses.
</P>
<P>
And there could be more bodies. The Kenya Red Cross said Tuesday that more than 50 people were still missing.
</P>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
