<DOC id="NYT_ENG_20131221.0217" type="story" from_file="/newswire/daily_process/nyt/english/source_data/20131221/20131221,d2b4c68bcca783df02b2e6645bc2303a.xml">
<HEADLINE>
BLACKBERRY STAGGERS TO A DEEPER, $4.4 BILLION LOSS
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
<P>
EDS: SUBS for complete writethru; NEW headline.) ; (This article is part of TIMES EXPRESS. It is a condensed version of a story that will appear in tomorrow’s New York Times.);
</P>
<P>
OTTAWA, Ontario - BlackBerry, the hobbled smartphone maker, reported more dire financial news Friday, posting a $4.4 billion loss and a 56 percent drop in revenue in its latest quarter. The company also outlined a sharp retreat from its once-core handset business by entering a partnership with the Asian contract manufacturer Foxconn.
</P>
<P>
The substantial loss, which follows one of nearly $1 billion in the previous quarter, again reflected the failure of the BlackBerry 10 line of phones, which were portrayed as a lifesaver for the company when introduced at the beginning of the year. The latest loss included a $2.7 billion write-down mainly related to BlackBerry 10 phones, including the Q10 and the Z10.
</P>
<P>
Of the 4.3 million BlackBerrys bought by consumers and businesses during the quarter, 3.2 million were models that use the obsolete BlackBerry 7 operating system. The meager sales of the phone led revenue to plunge to $1.2 billion, compared with $2.7 billion in the same period a year ago.
</P>
<P>
Last month, BlackBerry failed to find a buyer for the company and replaced Thorsten Heins, the chief executive, with John S. Chen, the former chairman of the software company Sybase. Chen has since fired several high-level executives at the company.
</P>
<P>
But the first real strategic change under Chen came Friday, when he announced the company’s arrangement with Foxconn. BlackBerry, like other many other hardware companies including Apple, has long relied on Foxconn to manufacture phones. The new partnership appears to take the relationship to a new level.
</P>
<P>
The arrangement also seems to be a way for BlackBerry to effectively hand over some of its handset business without running afoul of Canadian foreign investment laws.
</P>
<P>
In a conference call with analysts, Chen said that BlackBerry would jointly develop and manufacture some phones with Foxconn. Because Foxconn will carry the inventory of those phones on its books, Chen said that BlackBerry would be shielded from large writedowns of unwanted handsets in the future.
</P>
<P>
In what seemed to be an even further distancing from the company’s past, Chen was remarkably open to the idea of joining the competition.
</P>
<P>
“I would love to find a way to make our BlackBerry experience on the Android and the iOS,” he said, referring to the two dominant mobile operating systems. “It’s not without difficulties, as you all know. But it’s something that we’re very interested in trying.”
</P>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
