<DOC id="NYT_ENG_20131113.0045" type="story" from_file="/newswire/daily_process/nyt/english/source_data/20131113/20131113,2016acd01c68578bc00a3088898cddcd.xml">
<HEADLINE>
THREE JOURNALISTS AT THE TIMES ARE DEPARTING
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
<P>
EDS: SUBS for writethru to reflect developments; NEW headline.);
</P>
<P>
Three journalists at The New York Times on Tuesday announced plans to leave the newspaper.
</P>
<P>
Hugo Lindgren, editor of The New York Times Magazine, told his staff in a brief meeting Tuesday afternoon that he would leave The Times at year’s end. Lindgren was hired by The Times in September 2010 after working as executive editor of Bloomberg Businessweek. No successor has been named, a spokeswoman for The Times said. Responding to a request for comment, Lindgren wrote in an email: “I loved editing The Times Magazine over the course of 150-plus issues. Looking forward to the next challenge.”
</P>
<P>
Also Tuesday, CNN announced that it had hired Brian Stelter, a media reporter at The Times, to host its weekly news show “Reliable Sources.” The network said that Stelter, 28, would also be a senior media correspondent, reporting on “trends, personalities and companies across the media spectrum.”
</P>
<P>
“I’m equally excited about reporting throughout the week on CNN’s many digital platforms and television networks,” Stelter, who joined The Times in 2007, said in a statement. “CNN is reimagining media coverage at what is the best time ever to be covering media, and I’m very happy to be a part of it.”
</P>
<P>
In addition, Matt Bai, a political correspondent for The New York Times Magazine, said he was joining Yahoo News as its national political columnist. Bai, 45, said in an email that he planned to start at Yahoo in December, probably writing a weekly column “with some additional columns added on big news days.”
</P>
<P>
“It’s just such a chaotic moment in journalism, and here was a chance to work for a digital entity that combines vast resources and just this vast readership,” he wrote. “I found that really compelling.”
</P>
<P>
The departures follow moves last month by several other well-known Times employees, all of whom were leaving to join digital companies. Richard L. Berke, a longtime political correspondent and senior editor, left for Politico. Howard Beck, an NBA beat reporter, joined Bleacher Report, and David Pogue, a longtime technology columnist, also announced he was joining Yahoo. Nate Silver, whose FiveThirtyEight blog was licensed by The Times in 2010, joined ESPN in the summer.
</P>
<P>
News of Lindgren’s departure was first reported by Capital New York.
</P>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
