<DOC id="NYT_ENG_20130523.0220" type="story" from_file="/newswire/daily_process/nyt/english/source_data/20130523/20130523,b9daeb02758f370084b1d901bc57368c.xml">
<HEADLINE>
ENVOY SAYS NORTH KOREA OPEN TO DIALOGUE
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
<P>
BEIJING - A North Korean envoy, Marshal Choe Ryong-hae, said the North would “accept the proposal” by China to “open up dialogue,” the China News Service reported Thursday.
</P>
<P>
The comments were reported after the Choe met Liu Yunshan, a member of the Communist Party Standing Committee and the politician who heads ideological affairs for the Communist Party.
</P>
<P>
Liu was quoted as saying that China wanted a resumption of talks that would result in the removal of nuclear weapons from the Korean Peninsula “as soon as possible.” Chinese officials frequently make such appeals.
</P>
<P>
Choe, who arrived in China, North Korea’s biggest benefactor, on Wednesday on a fence-mending mission, is a close aide to North Korea’s leader, Kim Jong Un, and as such, what he says is taken relatively seriously.
</P>
<P>
Few diplomats believe that the North is prepared to be involved in six-party talks that aim to strip North Korea of its nuclear weapons. Such talks among the United States, North Korea, South Korea, China, Japan and Russia collapsed in 2008 after North Korea walked out. The regime has continued to persist with its nuclear weapons program ever since, despite constant pleas by China to stop.
</P>
<P>
Choe, 72, was quoted by the China News Service as being “highly” appreciative of “China’s huge efforts to maintain peace and stability” on the Korean Peninsula.
</P>
<P>
There have been no reports so far of Choe meeting with senior Chinese officials involved in foreign policy and military affairs. The publicized meetings have been with senior officials of the Communist Party who are the usual interlocutors with North Korea. On Wednesday, Choe met with Wang Jiarui, head of the International Department of the Communist Party of China.
</P>
<P>
The North Korean news agency said Choe visited an industrial park in Beijing on Thursday. China’s basic advice to North Korea is reform of its economy should follow the path of Deng Xiaoping with special economic zones and some private enterprise.
</P>
<P>
Choe’s visit is being watched closely by North Korean experts in China. They say they detect little change in China’s underlying policy of supporting North Korea. But the Chinese leadership would like North Korea to modify its erratic behavior, stop nuclear tests and halt its missile program, they say. How to reach that goal with Kim had not been resolved, some of the experts said.
</P>
<P>
China should begin to treat North Korea as a normal country and should resist extremes of sheltering it or abandoning it, said Wang Gunsheng, an analyst at the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences.
</P>
<P>
Wang said the visit of Choe could be interpreted as a “kind of apology” by North Korea by China for its recent behavior, including conducting its third nuclear test in February.
</P>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
