<DOC id="NYT_ENG_20130810.0221" type="story" from_file="/newswire/daily_process/nyt/english/source_data/20130810/20130810,f658f0a0b61ea94183936575e64b1479.xml">
<HEADLINE>
GUN RIGHTS CELEBRATION AT STARBUCKS? NOT IN NEWTOWN
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
<P>
The nation’s gun owners declared Friday Starbucks Appreciation Day, but in Newtown, Conn., not everyone seemed very appreciative.
</P>
<P>
Instead, the local Starbucks closed five hours early, disappointing some gun owners who had planned to show up wearing holstered pistols to make a statement in favor of gun rights and Starbucks’ policies. The plan had already infuriated many residents still reeling from the murder of 26 children and educators at Sandy Hook Elementary School in December.
</P>
<P>
Earlier, however, about two dozen gun rights supporters, some wearing pistols, camouflage or Connecticut Citizens Defense League T-shirts, showed up to show their support.
</P>
<P>
The company said it had no participation in the event.
</P>
<P>
Matt Botalli, 30, who owns a landscaping company in Ridgefield, was among the gun owners who planned to show up with half a dozen armed friends at the Newtown Starbucks in a national effort by gun owners to show their appreciation for Starbucks’ policy, which allows customers to carry weapons into their stores in states where it is legal. Companies have the option of banning weapons if they choose.
</P>
<P>
“Come down, meet me and my friends,'' Botalli wrote on his Facebook page. ”I guarantee there will not be a safer public place in all of CT."
</P>
<P>
“This isn’t to make a spectacle or terrorize anyone,'' he said early Friday afternoon, adding that he regularly carried his Smith &amp; Wesson pistol to coffee shops. He added: ”This was just about going to the local Starbucks and having a cup of coffee together. And that’s still my plan. I’m not going there to stomp my feet or march around in a circle.''
</P>
<P>
Earlier, the Newtown Action Alliance issued a statement, discouraging gun rights groups from holding Starbucks Appreciation Day in Newtown.
</P>
<P>
“Our community is still healing, and we find it reprehensible that they are picking Newtown to rally,” the statement said. Po Murray, the vice chairwoman of the group, called the plan “tasteless and insensitive” and said that just as Starbucks does not allow smoking within 25 feet of its buildings, it should take a stand on gun violence by not allowing customers to carry weapons there.
</P>
<P>
Instead, the local Starbucks closed about 4:30 p.m., instead of its usual 9:30 p.m. shutting time. A handwritten sign on the door read: "Out of respect for Newtown and everything our community has been through, we have decided to close our store early today.''
</P>
<P>
Usually associated with latte and cappuccino rather than Smith &amp; Wesson, Starbucks has drawn praise from gun owners and criticism from anti-gun groups for its policy allowing people to openly carry guns in states, like Connecticut, that allow it.
</P>
<P>
The National Gun Victims Action Council said that unlike companies like California Pizza Kitchen, Peet’s Coffee and Tea, Ikea and Disney, Starbucks had declined to ban guns from its stores. Starbucks said it chose simply to follow the laws as they exist in all states.
</P>
<P>
The anti-gun group has identified Starbucks as its first economic target and has sponsored a 2-year-old boycott of the company by “gun victims, survivors, their friends, family members, faith groups and all who want sane gun laws.” It says that the boycott has cost the company $11.5 million per year, and that it plans to step up its pressure on Starbucks in the future. The group says the efforts to openly display handguns at restaurants and coffee shops is part of a national effort to "normalize the carrying of guns in public places.''
</P>
<P>
It said: “Starbucks’ pro-gun policy on open carry makes it an active supporter of the gun lobby’s agenda to put more guns in more places in American life - and it must stop.”
</P>
<P>
On the other hand, gun owners have singled out Starbucks for praise and support. A Facebook page said gun supporters should thank Starbucks “for standing up for our right to bear arms by going there on Friday.”
</P>
<P>
Starbucks has found itself in the middle of controversy before, mostly on the other side of the political spectrum, over its support for gay marriage.
</P>
<P>
“Our longstanding approach to the open carry debate has been to comply with local laws and statutes in the communities we serve,'' said Zack Hutson, a company spokesman. ”We continue to encourage customers and advocacy groups from all sides of the debate to share their input with their elected officials, who make the open carry laws that our company follows.''
</P>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
