<DOC id="NYT_ENG_20131010.0200" type="story" from_file="/newswire/daily_process/nyt/english/source_data/20131010/20131010,b67600bfd2de29d9b5d232d247cc9767.xml">
<HEADLINE>
OSHA CITES OWNER OF TEXAS FERTILIZER PLANT THAT EXPLODED
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
<P>
WASHINGTON – The Occupational Safety and Health Administration has cited the company that owns the fertilizer plant in West, Texas, for safety violations following a massive explosion at the facility in April, which left 15 dead and leveled the surrounding area.
</P>
<P>
OSHA fined Adair Grain, Inc., parent of the West Fertilizer Co., $118,300 for 24 serious violations. The explosion exposed workers to ammonium nitrate chemical burns and created inhalation hazards in the plant.
</P>
<P>
The OSHA report stated that the company failed to develop a communication plan in cases of emergency or create a safe working environment. It is also being fined for having inadequate ventilation systems and improper chemical storage techniques.
</P>
<P>
''The employer did not furnish employment and a place of employment which was free from recognized hazards that were causing or likely to cause death,'' the report stated.
</P>
<P>
Democratic California Sen. Barbara Boxer, chair of the Committee on Environment and Public Works, announced the fines and violations Thursday, asserting that similar explosions can be prevented with proper oversight.
</P>
<P>
''All of these things are pretty much standard operating procedure,'' Boxer said.
</P>
<P>
OSHA, a division of the Department of Labor, works with several other agencies, including the Chemical Safety Board, to ensure proper and safe working conditions, and has been investigating the West explosion for months.
</P>
<P>
Daniel Horowitz, managing director for the CSB, said the agency is working to understand what exactly caused the West Fertilizer Co. plant to explode and where there were regulatory gaps in identifying potential hazards.
</P>
<P>
''What our team is focusing on is why did this fire progress to an ammonium detonation and how should that storage be made safer,'' Horowitz said.
</P>
<P>
Dan Keeney, a spokesman for West Fertilizer Co., said the company’s attorneys are still reviewing the citations, but based on their initial review, OSHA’s allegations don’t appear to be specifically related to the April explosion.
</P>
<P>
But the plant could have had better safety management years before the explosion happened, said Congressman Bill Flores, R-Bryan, whose district includes West.
</P>
<P>
Flores said plant managers should have had a stronger safety program in place – one of the citations in the OSHA report – to prevent similar large-scale accidents, which are often built up over time and not caused by a single mistake.
</P>
<P>
CSB testimony from a committee hearing in June revealed the West plant had not been inspected by a federal agency since 1985.
</P>
<P>
''If the plant had been run in a safer manner, then we wouldn’t be having this discussion today,'' Flores said. ''It shows that we still have a lot of work to do in terms of mitigating the risks from these types of facilities.''
</P>
<P>
The government’s investigation into the plant’s explosion isn’t complete, and OSHA and other federal agencies are working together to determine its cause, Boxer said. But the current government shutdown has prevented federal efforts to improve safety conditions in chemical facilities.
</P>
<P>
All but three of the 40-person CSB staff are furloughed, including all 10 of the people investigating the West explosion, Horowitz said.
</P>
<P>
''Our problems are really acute right now,'' he said.
</P>
<P>
The CSB has been working with agencies of each state to locate ammonium nitrate facilities and identify similar potential hazards, but their investigation has been delayed because of the shutdown.
</P>
<P>
Horowitz said the agency also has been analyzing eyewitness videos of the explosion to ''dissect’' what happened seconds before the blast.
</P>
<P>
The last time Flores visited West was in early September, and he said although residents have built new houses in the area and reopened schools, the town still has a long way to go – as do the agencies investigating it as they face uncertain fiscal times.
</P>
<P>
''In our current fiscal environment, we have to do more with less,'' Flores said. ''The federal government has never been very efficient, but it’s going to have to learn how to be efficient. We just don’t have the resources to fund everything we’d like to fund.''
</P>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
