<DOC id="NYT_ENG_20130804.0008" type="story" from_file="/newswire/daily_process/nyt/english/source_data/20130804/20130804,1295a9e61103a9bb792eca1ed8fa05f1.xml">
<HEADLINE>
OBAMA ADMINISTRATION OVERTURNS BAN ON APPLE PRODUCTS
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
<P>
EDS: CORRECTS to “this week” sted of “next week” and adds more information in lede; UPDATES throughout.); (This article is part of TIMES EXPRESS. It is a condensed version of a story that will appear in tomorrow’s New York Times.);
</P>
<P>
The Obama administration has vetoed a product ban that would have forced Apple to stop selling some iPhones and iPads in the United States this week, a rare intervention by the White House and a victory for Apple in its heated patent war with Samsung Electronics.
</P>
<P>
The U.S. International Trade Commission in June ordered a ban of older-model Apple products that worked with AT&amp;T’s network, including the iPhone 4 and 3GS, after determining that Apple had violated a patent that Samsung owned related to transmission of data over cellular networks. The administration had until Monday to weigh in.
</P>
<P>
It was the first time that an administration had vetoed an International Trade Commission ban since 1987, according to Susan Kohn Ross, an international trade lawyer for Mitchell Silberberg &amp; Knupp.
</P>
<P>
Michael Froman, the U.S. trade representative and the president’s adviser on international trade issues, wrote in his decision that it was based in part on the “effect on competitive conditions in the U.S. economy and the effect on U.S. consumers.”
</P>
<P>
Apple argued that Samsung had committed to licensing its patents related to wireless technology standards, but was refusing to keep that promise. Samsung said Apple refused to pay licensing fees for its patents.
</P>
<P>
Samsung said Saturday that it was disappointed, adding, “The ITC’s decision correctly recognized that Samsung has been negotiating in good faith and that Apple remains unwilling to take a license.”
</P>
<P>
Kristin Huguet, an Apple spokeswoman, said, “We applaud the administration for standing up for innovation in this landmark case.” She added, “Samsung was wrong to abuse the patent system in this way.”
</P>
<P>
Froman said his decision did not mean that Samsung was “not entitled to a remedy. On the contrary, the patent owner may continue to pursue its rights through the courts.”
</P>
<P>
Samsung and Apple were once tight partners - the South Korean company makes some key parts needed to produce iPhones and iPads. But over time, as they made products that competed in different markets, their friendship turned into rivalry.
</P>
<P>
The companies, which together rake in all of the profits in the handset industry, have been using patents as weapons to fight each other in the United States and other countries. Last year, a California jury awarded Apple $1 billion in damages after deciding that Samsung had violated the American company’s mobile patents, though the amount was reduced to $599 million.
</P>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
