<DOC id="NYT_ENG_20130603.0030" type="story" from_file="/newswire/daily_process/nyt/english/source_data/20130603/20130603,27c68e493e76e13f888c8ed74fc1bdc1.xml">
<HEADLINE>
TWO ACCUSED OF SOLDIER'S MURDER APPEAR IN COURT
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
<P>
LONDON - Two men accused of hacking an off-duty British soldier to death on a South London street last month appeared in separate courts for hearings Monday as politicians planned to meet with security and police chiefs to discuss ways of confronting what the government has termed the “poisonous narrative” of militant radicalization.
</P>
<P>
The men, Michael Adebolajo, 28, and Michael Adebowale, 22, both of Nigerian descent, face murder charges in the May 22 death of the soldier, Lee Rigby, 25, a military drummer and machine-gunner who had served with British forces in Afghanistan and elsewhere. After the soldier’s killing, both suspects were shot and wounded by police.
</P>
<P>
Adebowale was formally charged with murder last week, and Adebolajo appeared in a magistrate’s court Monday to be formally arraigned. He was also charged with other offenses, including the attempted murder of two police officers and possession of a revolver, identified as a 9.4-mm KNIL model 91.
</P>
<P>
Weapons experts said the revolver is a large-bore, antique handgun first manufactured in the Netherlands in the late 19th century.
</P>
<P>
According to reporters in the Westminster Magistrates Court, Adebolajo was wearing a white T-shirt and blew a kiss to an unidentified man in the public gallery. Both men then pointed to the sky.
</P>
<P>
For his part, Adebowale appeared at the Old Bailey criminal court and was told he would return for a preliminary hearing June 28 when the cases against both men would be heard together. He did not seek bail, news reports said.
</P>
<P>
The proceedings came after a weekend in which crowds added floral tributes to the thousands of bouquets left by well-wishers in the Woolwich neighborhood where Rigby was killed in full view of passers-by as he returned to an army barracks wearing a T-shirt with the name of a military charity.
</P>
<P>
While some mourned, others protested, and violent clashes broke out near the Parliaments in London and Edinburgh between rightists demonstrating against Islamic militancy and others promoting tolerance. In other cities, extreme rightists confronted campaigners opposed to racism and fascism. Scores of people were arrested in London on public order offenses after the police broke up fights.
</P>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
