<DOC id="NYT_ENG_20130510.0155" type="story" from_file="/newswire/daily_process/nyt/english/source_data/20130510/20130510,947245b1da4375577c7ce91a72b3ac7e.xml">
<HEADLINE>
PAKISTAN ORDERS NEW YORK TIMES REPORTER TO LEAVE
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
<P>
Pakistan’s Interior Ministry has ordered the expulsion of The New York Times bureau chief in Islamabad on the eve of national elections, the newspaper said Friday. The Times has strongly protested the move and is seeking his reinstatement.
</P>
<P>
The ministry gave no explanation for the expulsion order, which was delivered via a two-sentence letter by police officers to the bureau chief, Declan Walsh, at 12:30 a.m. Thursday local time at his home.
</P>
<P>
“It is informed that your visa is hereby canceled in view of your undesirable activities,” the order stated. “You are therefore advised to leave the country within 72 hours.” The timing of the order means Walsh must exit Pakistan on the night of the elections.
</P>
<P>
Walsh, 39, is a veteran correspondent who has lived and worked in Pakistan for nine years, most of it for The Guardian newspaper of Britain. He was hired by the Times in January 2012 and has written extensively about the country’s violent political convulsions, Islamist insurgency and sometimes tense relations with the United States, which has been conducting drone attacks on militants in Pakistan’s border areas with Afghanistan.
</P>
<P>
In a letter of protest to Pakistan’s interior minister, Malik Muhammad Habib Khan, Jill Abramson, the newspaper’s executive editor, expressed concern about the order, describing Walsh as a “reporter of integrity who has at all times offered balanced, nuanced and factual reporting on Pakistan.” She asked the minister to reinstate Walsh’s visa.
</P>
<P>
The accusation of undesirable activities, she wrote, “is vague and unsupported, and Mr. Walsh has received no further explanation of any alleged wrongdoing.”
</P>
<P>
Walsh said the circumstances of the expulsion order’s delivery were highly unusual. He had been on a social visit Thursday evening, he said, when he received a phone call from an unrecognized number advising him to “come home now.” Walsh arrived to find a half-dozen police officers and a plainclothes officer waiting outside. The plainclothes officer handed him the letter and asked him to sign for it.
</P>
<P>
“I opened the letter in front of him because I knew it was something serious,” he said. “This was a complete bolt from the blue. I had no inclination that anything of this sort was coming.”
</P>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
