<DOC id="NYT_ENG_20130425.0150" type="story" from_file="/newswire/daily_process/nyt/english/source_data/20130425/20130425,99acef939bcc1bb75bae5a71dda674c0.xml">
<HEADLINE>
PROTESTERS TARGET NRA LOBBYISTS
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
<P>
WASHINGTON – Though the Senate showed America where it stands on gun legislation last week, citizens took to the streets and sidewalks of Washington D.C. on Thursday to voice their displeasure with the vote that killed a measure to expand background checks on guns.
</P>
<P>
''I’m personally offended,'' said Meagan Kelly, a Newtown, Conn resident. ''The President said we’ll do something about this and the Senate didn’t follow through.''
</P>
<P>
Occupy the NRA staged a protest to call out the National Rifle Association and lobbying firms with ties to the gun rights group for using big money to stonewall gun safety legislation. The group, which says it advocates for sensible gun-safety laws, rallied supporters in McPherson Square, a small park near the famous K Street.
</P>
<P>
Many gun safety advocates have built an argument around the December 2012 shootings that killed 26 students and teachers at Sandy Hook Elementary in Newtown, pushing for more stringent background checks, bans on assault weapons, and other gun-control measures.
</P>
<P>
Several speakers addressed the crowd, including Nardyne Jefferies, a Washington mother who became a gun-safety advocate after her only daughter was killed in a drive-by shooting.
</P>
<P>
Charles McGarry, a former Stamford, Conn., resident who stood among the crowd listening to Jefferies speak, said the NRA has a powerful grip on the political process and it’s up to citizens to make a difference.
</P>
<P>
The protesters, somewhat unorganized and flanked by a small band of police on motorcycles, delivered letters to lobbying firms including Prime Policy Group, Crossroads Strategies, Denton’s, and others asking them to sever their ties with the pro-gun group. None of the lobbying groups targeted by protesters returned phone calls made by Hearst Newspapers on Thursday.
</P>
<P>
The NRA and its affiliate groups are a huge political force, having spent $800,000 in lobbying efforts in this year’s first quarter, according to the Center for Public Integrity. The NRA has maintained a strong campaign to fend off control measures and advocate for arming schoolteachers following the Sandy Hook school shooting.
</P>
<P>
Aaron Black, the protest’s organizer, said the event is meant to shed light on the NRA’s part in hindering progress for improving gun legislation.
</P>
<P>
''Guns aren’t going to go away. We’re not trying to get rid of guns,'' Black said. ''We want to make sure people who have them use them safely.''
</P>
<P>
Many heads turned as they walked by the scene and one passerby even shouted ''long live the Second Amendment.''
</P>
<P>
The protesters stood outside the lobbying firms’ offices, but were not allowed inside.
</P>
<P>
 ’'Unfortunately, I’m not surprised,'' said Kelly, who is friends with the daughter of a teacher killed at Sandy Hook. ''They don’t want to take responsibility for their role in this.''
</P>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
