<DOC id="NYT_ENG_20130720.0209" type="story" from_file="/newswire/daily_process/nyt/english/source_data/20130720/20130720,f41d6e8f24fc6db4af6c96f627ec6c8e.xml">
<HEADLINE>
A SHUFFLE OF ALUMINUM, BUT TO BANKS, PURE GOLD
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
<P>
This article is part of TIMES EXPRESS. It is a condensed version of a story that will appear in tomorrow’s New York Times.);
</P>
<P>
MOUNT CLEMENS, Mich. - Hundreds of millions of times a day, thirsty Americans open a can of soda, beer or juice. And every time they do it, they pay a fraction of a penny more because of a shrewd maneuver by Goldman Sachs and other financial players that ultimately costs consumers billions of dollars.
</P>
<P>
The story of how this works begins in 27 industrial warehouses in the Detroit area where Goldman stores customers’ aluminum. Each day, a fleet of trucks shuffles 1,500-pound bars of the metal among the warehouses. This industrial dance has been choreographed by Goldman to exploit pricing regulations set up by an overseas commodities exchange, an investigation by The New York Times has found. The back-and-forth lengthens the storage time. And that adds many millions a year to the coffers of Goldman, which owns the warehouses and charges rent to store the metal. It also increases prices paid by manufacturers and consumers across the country.
</P>
<P>
Tyler Clay, a forklift driver who worked at the Goldman warehouses until early this year, called the process “a merry-go-round of metal.”
</P>
<P>
Only a tenth of a cent or so of an aluminum can’s purchase price can be traced back to the strategy. But multiply that amount by the 90 billion aluminum cans consumed in the United States each year - and add the tons of aluminum used in things like cars, electronics and house siding - and the efforts by Goldman and other financial players has cost American consumers more than $5 billion over the last three years, say former industry executives, analysts and consultants.
</P>
<P>
The inflated aluminum pricing is just one way that Wall Street is capitalizing on loosened federal regulations to sway a variety of commodities markets, according to financial records, regulatory documents and interviews with people involved in the activities. The maneuvering in markets for oil, wheat, cotton, coffee and more have brought billions in profits to investment banks while forcing consumers to pay more.
</P>
<P>
In the case of aluminum, Goldman bought Metro International Trade Services, one of the country’s biggest traders of the metal.
</P>
<P>
Goldman Sachs says it complies with all industry standards and there is no suggestion that these activities violate any laws or regulations. Metro International, which declined to comment for this article, in the past has attributed the delays to logistical problems, including a shortage of trucks and forklift drivers, and the administrative complications of tracking so much metal.
</P>
<P>
But interviews with several current and former Metro employees, as well as someone with direct knowledge of the company’s business plan, suggest the longer waiting times are part of the company’s strategy and help Goldman increase its profits from the warehouses.
</P>
<P>
“It’s a totally artificial cost,” said Jorge Vazquez, managing director at Harbor Aluminum Intelligence, a commodities consulting firm. “It’s a drag on the economy. Everyone pays for it.”
</P>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
