<DOC id="NYT_ENG_20130723.0139" type="story" from_file="/newswire/daily_process/nyt/english/source_data/20130723/20130723,8699db322e76f070479b895700e1b405.xml">
<HEADLINE>
SENATE PANEL EXAMINES POTENTIAL RISKS IN BANKS' INVOLVEMENT IN COMMODITIES
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
<P>
EDS: SUBS throughout to update and restructure.) ; (This article is part of TIMES EXPRESS. It is a condensed version of a story that will appear in tomorrow’s New York Times.);
</P>
<P>
WASHINGTON - Wall Street’s lucrative commodities businesses came to the fore here Tuesday as a Senate panel questioned whether banks should be allowed to control warehouses, pipelines and other infrastructure used to store and transport essential goods.
</P>
<P>
The hearing, convened by the Senate Financial Institutions and Consumer Protection subcommittee, came as Goldman Sachs, JPMorgan Chase and others face growing scrutiny over their role in the commodities markets and the extent to which their activities can inflate prices paid by manufacturers and consumers. The Federal Reserve is reviewing the potential risks posed by the operations, which have generated many billions of dollars in profits for the banks.
</P>
<P>
The hearing followed an article in The New York Times on Sunday that explored the operations of warehouses controlled in part by Goldman Sachs. The bank’s tactics, along with those of other financial players, have inflated the price of aluminum and ultimately cost consumers billions of dollars, an investigation by The Times found. The Commodity Futures Trading Commission is now gathering information on the warehouse operations.
</P>
<P>
Several witnesses at Tuesday’s hearings warned that letting the country’s largest financial institutions own commodities units that store and ship vast quantities of metals, oil and the other basic building blocks of the economy could pose grave risks to the financial system. The ability of those bank subsidiaries to gather nonpublic information on commodities stores and shipping also could give the banks an unfair advantage in the markets, the witnesses said.
</P>
<P>
Representatives from the financial industry did not testify Tuesday, but Goldman Sachs for the first time addressed its role in the aluminum market. In a statement posted on its website, Goldman said that its ownership of aluminum warehouses did not affect prices of the metal, in part because only 5 percent of the aluminum that is used in manufacturing passes through the warehouses owned by Goldman and others. Goldman controls 27 warehouses in the Detroit area that are used to store aluminum for customers.
</P>
<P>
Saule T. Omarova, a law professor at the University of North Carolina who has studied the issue, told the subcommittee that there was one other company that was an early leader in combining the practice of moving physical commodities with the financing of market activity - Enron.
</P>
<P>
The comparison was seized upon by Sen. Elizabeth Warren, D-Mass. “The notion that two of largest financial companies are adopting a business method pioneered by Enron,” she said, “suggests that this movie will not end well.”
</P>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
