<DOC id="NYT_ENG_20131011.0094" type="story" from_file="/newswire/daily_process/nyt/english/source_data/20131011/20131011,5cf93b3f3e3435850e325f5f6b999afb.xml">
<HEADLINE>
OUTSIDE NATIONAL PARKS, FEELING SQUEEZED BY THE SHUTDOWN
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
<P>
This article is part of TIMES EXPRESS. It is a condensed version of a story that will appear in tomorrow’s New York Times.);
</P>
<P>
SPRINGDALE, Utah - In the 10 days since Zion National Park closed its gates, the community on its doorstep has become a shutdown ghost town. Hotel rooms are dark, and housecleaners are working half-shifts. Herds of campers and sightseers have streamed away along the only highway out of town, and canceled reservations from New Zealand, California and Germany are piling up every day.
</P>
<P>
“The phone’s still ringing, unfortunately,” said Dean Cook, manager of the Zion Park Inn, which lost about $19,000 in business during the first week of the federal government shutdown. “We thought of not answering it for a while.”
</P>
<P>
The shutdown has pinched millions of Americans, from furloughed federal workers to poor mothers seeking food aid, but its economic toll is particularly concentrated in gateway communities to national parks, from Gatlinburg, Tenn., to Estes Park, Colo., to here in southwest Utah, where local businesses live or die on tourist traffic.
</P>
<P>
On Thursday, people here welcomed the news that federal officials would allow states to reopen some national parks if they used their own money to run them - an expensive proposition for any state government. Governors in Utah, South Dakota, Colorado and Arizona have been urging the Interior Department to reopen the parks, or allow states to do so if they paid for some day-to-day operations.
</P>
<P>
In Utah, officials were scrambling to find the money to put the park rangers and employees back to work - Zion alone costs $50,000 a day to operate - and determine which parks might open first and whether the state would be repaid once the shutdown ends. “We’re just figuring this out,” said Ally Isom, a spokeswoman for Utah’s governor, Gary R. Herbert.
</P>
<P>
It has gotten so bad that four counties in Utah have declared a state of emergency. The closure of Zion has cost about $3.5 million in visitor spending, according to a report by the Coalition of National Park Service Retirees, using data from the research firm Headwaters Economics. The report estimates that the shutdown is costing parks communities across the country about $76 million per day.
</P>
<P>
“This is as dangerous to us as an earthquake,” said Rebecca McKown, whose family owns The Spotted Dog restaurant.
</P>
<P>
As the closure drags on, anger has turned into action. Last week, about a dozen protesters climbed over the metal gates and walked through the park. Another protest march is planned for Saturday. Similar protests, dubbed Occupy Yellowstone and Occupy Yosemite, have sprung up outside other parks.
</P>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
