<DOC id="NYT_ENG_20131108.0148" type="story" from_file="/newswire/daily_process/nyt/english/source_data/20131108/20131108,87bc69f39b28e8c6a7578dff22b67bc7.xml">
<HEADLINE>
METAL EXCHANGE CHANGES RULES TO TRIM WAIT TIMES
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
<P>
ART ADV: Photo is being sent to NYT photo clients. Nonsubscribers can purchase one-time rights by calling: 1-888-603-1036 or 1-888-346-9867.);
</P>
<P>
Hoping to reduce the warehouse delays that have added billions of dollars to the prices that consumers pay for beverage cans and other aluminum products, the London Metals Exchange has released new regulations meant to reduce the waiting times at storage facilities owned by commodities traders and banks like Goldman Sachs.
</P>
<P>
Beer breweries and other businesses that buy aluminum have for years complained that Metro International Trade Services, a string of Detroit-area warehouses owned by Goldman Sachs, had orchestrated bottlenecks at its facilities that forced them to wait as long as 16 months for their metal to be delivered.
</P>
<P>
The delays have generated millions in profits for the warehouse, which charges rent by the day. But they also add to the storage expense for aluminum buyers, costs that are passed on to consumers. Because of a quirk in the way metal prices are set on the spot market, the delays raise the price of nearly all the aluminum sold in the United States, even if the metal is never stored in a warehouse.
</P>
<P>
The new guidelines, released Wednesday after a three-month review of the aluminum storage business, will require warehouses with waiting times of 50 days or longer to load out more metal than they take in each day. The exchange, which is owned by investors and regulates 700 storage facilities around the globe, said it would also be more aggressive in investigating instances where warehouses appeared to be instigating the delays.
</P>
<P>
“The LME will now have a greater power to investigate and to act to prevent warehouse companies unreasonably incentivizing the formation of queues,” Garry Jones, the exchange’s chief executive, said in a video announcing the changes.
</P>
<P>
Beverage makers and aluminum brokers offered measured praise for the new regulations.
</P>
<P>
Some aluminum brokers and users had urged the exchange to forbid warehouses from charging rent during any delivery delays. But the report said that that suggestion, while attractive, might lead warehouse owners to raise other fees, so the exchange would consider it as a “next step” option if its current reforms failed to shorten the lines.
</P>
<P>
Nick Madden, the head of procurement at Novelis, said he was optimistic that the changes would help address the issue. But the Beer Institute, which lobbied Congress and federal regulators, said more needed to be done.
</P>
<P>
The rule changes “are a move in the right direction, but we believe further reforms could be immediately implemented to return the LME to a proper, free-market function of global aluminum price discovery,” a spokeswoman for institute said in a statement.
</P>
<P>
The Federal Reserve is reviewing the exemptions that allow Goldman and other banks to own commodities storage facilities.
</P>
<P>
Michael DuVally, a spokesman for Goldman, said Thursday that the company had no comment on the new regulation.
</P>
<P>
But Goldman officials have repeatedly denied accusations that they intentionally caused the delays. Company officials have cited a variety of causes for the bottlenecks over the years, including a shortage of trucks and forklift drivers and the logistical challenges of locating and moving 1,500-pound bars of aluminum stacked 15 feet high in cavernous storage facilities.
</P>
<P>
After a congressional hearing in July, at which several senators called on Goldman and other investment banks to divest themselves of their commodities holdings, Gary Cohn, the Goldman president, said that Metro would offer immediate delivery to any metal owners who requested it. But the report released Wednesday by the metal exchange - based on meetings with more than 70 participants in the aluminum industry - found that stronger measures were needed to ease the backlog at Metro and a handful of other warehouses with long waiting times.
</P>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
