<DOC id="NYT_ENG_20131210.0244" type="story" from_file="/newswire/daily_process/nyt/english/source_data/20131210/20131210,e2084c0bc9bd76157312ab1453e1d42b.xml">
<HEADLINE>
U.N. TO DELIVER AID TO SYRIA VIA IRAQ
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
<P>
GENEVA - U.N. relief agencies are preparing to make their first deliveries of aid from Iraq to Syria this week but it remains unclear whether this will prove a regular channel of assistance, the U.N. refugee agency said Tuesday.
</P>
<P>
An airlift of 12 flights using Russian-built Ilyushin cargo aircraft is to start Thursday and last until Sunday delivering food and other assistance from Iraq to Kurdish areas of Syria’s northeastern Hassakeh province, according to Amin Awad, the director of the Middle East and North Africa bureau at the Office of the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees.
</P>
<P>
Relief agencies believe there are 50,000 to 60,000 people in need of assistance in Hassakeh, where conflict has obstructed access by humanitarian agencies.
</P>
<P>
“It’s certainly a welcome development for us, the humanitarian conditions there are getting worse,” said Adrian Edwards, a spokesman for the refugee agency, citing U.N. estimates that 6.5 million people inside Syria have been driven from their homes by fighting.
</P>
<P>
In addition to the security challenges in delivering assistance to areas of conflict, international aid agencies have complained of bureaucratic obstacles and delays from the government in Damascus in obtaining approval for relief convoys destined for populations trapped by fighting, and the agencies have pushed for more cross-border access from neighboring countries.
</P>
<P>
The high commissioner for refugees, António Guterres, is to meet Anne Richard, the U.S. assistant secretary of state for population, refugees, and migration, and officials from aid agencies in Geneva on Wednesday at the start of a two-day meeting. The gathering is aimed at bolstering international support for close to 29 million people around the world reportedly displaced by conflict and more than 30 million displaced by other disasters.
</P>
<P>
Guterres is expected to tell participants the number of people displaced by conflicts has risen in 2013, particularly in Syria, the Central African Republic and the Democratic Republic of Congo. He is also expected to warn that climate change is likely to add significantly to the scale and complexity of population displacements.
</P>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
