<DOC id="NYT_ENG_20130613.0034" type="story" from_file="/newswire/daily_process/nyt/english/source_data/20130613/20130613,24e4e7209f677d37a297bf21dacd183c.xml">
<HEADLINE>
Houston news
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
<P>
Despite President Barack Obama’s pledge of support for the people of West, federal disaster officials have declined to pay for millions of dollars in damages caused by a deadly fertilizer plant explosion in the small Texas town.
</P>
<P>
''We have determined that a major disaster declaration is not necessary,'' Federal Emergency Management Agency administrator Craig Fugate wrote in a letter to Gov. Rick Perry.
</P>
<P>
Perry called for the president to be ''true to his word’' and help deliver assistance to the devastated community. Fourteen people were killed, 200 were injured and dozens of homes were severely damaged in the April 17 blast at the West Fertilizer Co.
</P>
<P>
West Mayor Tommy Muska said rebuilding will continue despite local frustration over the FEMA decision. ''We’re not going to panic,'' he said. ''It’s more a kick in the teeth than a bump in the road.''
</P>
<P>
The agency has provided about $6.5 million in disaster aid to homeowners and small businesses in West, according to a recent statement from FEMA.
</P>
<P>
The denial covers public assistance, commonly used to rebuild community assets like roads, water lines and public buildings. Based on estimates from city officials, West sustained tens of millions of dollars in damage to local infrastructure, including roads and sewer lines. School district officials have estimated the cost of rebuilding an intermediate school at  $40 million.
</P>
<P>
It is not uncommon for FEMA to deny requests. The agency last summer rejected Minnesota’s request for additional aid for flood-damaged homes and businesses, and in 2011 it rejected requests in Alabama after houses were destroyed by a tornado.
</P>
<P>
Texas has 30 days to appeal the denial and is assessing options, said Josh Havens, a spokesman for Perry.
</P>
<P>
It’s not unusual for FEMA to turn down that level of assistance for emergencies not stemming from natural disasters. In 2010, for example, officials denied a request for millions in aid after a gas pipeline explosion that consumed a Northern California neighborhood.
</P>
<P>
''We know that the community has met the thresholds established by FEMA to qualify for public assistance and we have provided the information required to show as much,'' Havens said.
</P>
<P>
The denial, issued by FEMA’s Washington office, followed an April 25 appearance by the president in Waco. The president promised the nation would not forget the tragedy.
</P>
<P>
''We may not all live here in Texas, but we’re neighbors, too,'' Obama told a capacity crowd at Baylor University’s Ferrell Center. ''We’re Americans, too. And we stand with you and we will not forget, and we’ll be there even after the cameras leave and after the attention turns elsewhere.''
</P>
<P>
Perry said he was disappointed with the decision.
</P>
<P>
''We anticipate the president will hold true to his word and help us work with FEMA to ensure much-needed assistance reaches the community of West,'' Perry said in a statement.
</P>
<P>
Muska, echoing that disappointment, noted he was angry because the country ''can spend billions of dollars in other countries, but won’t help a little Texas town.''
</P>
<P>
''We’re not stingy or want gold-plated carpet,'' he said. ''We just want to replace some pipes.''
</P>
<P>
FEMA officials in Washington did not respond to requests for comment.
</P>
<P>
The explosion, caused by a stockpile of ammonium nitrate, remains under investigation by state and federal agencies. Last month, officials ruled out natural causes, smoking and water used by firefighters as possible causes.
</P>
<P>
Two, seemingly-simultaneous explosions gouged a 93-foot-wide crater at the plant and damaged 100 nearby buildings, mostly homes.
</P>
<P>
Meanwhile, West residents most affected by the explosion, notably those closest to the plant, are still displaced, interim city secretary Jennifer Schaffer said. Some continue living with friends or in a local hotel. Residents of homes closest to the plant are advised to boil water as officials rebuild and test water lines.
</P>
<P>
Rebuilding began days after the explosion, as people were slowly allowed back to assess the damage to homes. In a statement, Sen. John Cornyn, R-Texas, said he was confident state and local officials would support rebuilding.
</P>
<P>
''This wonderful town deserves nothing less,'' Cornyn said. XXX - End of Story&lt;3D&gt;
</P>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
