<DOC id="NYT_ENG_20130828.0109" type="story" from_file="/newswire/daily_process/nyt/english/source_data/20130828/20130828,6dbf53b0e84d9d5bf126720ddb969fe6.xml">
<HEADLINE>
End of trial brings relief to Killeen
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
<P>
By Scott Huddleston Staff Writer FORT HOOD--Local residents and community leaders celebrated the death sentence given Wednesday to Nidal Hasan and the end of a long, arduous quest for justice. Barbara Gee, a longtime Killeen resident whose husband died nine months ago, said she had mixed feelings about the sentence. Gee was on Fort Hood when the shooting occurred in 2009. ''I’m glad (Hasan) got what he deserved. But in a way I wish he could be kept alive and have to suffer,'' Gee said. ''Everybody here wishes that son of a gun never existed.'' Gee and her husband, a veteran, were at the commissary on the sprawling post when it was placed on lockdown the day of the shootings. ''We were hearing that there were multiple gunmen, and they told us to get away from the windows,'' Gee recalled. ''They said that if we had anything frozen, we should put it back because they didn’t know when we could leave.'' John Crutchfield, president and CEO of the Greater Killeen Chamber of Commerce, said he was told during a tour of the post Wednesday that the building where 13 people were killed will be razed, and a memorial put on the site. Fort Hood officials could not confirm that. The former Soldier Readiness Processing center, or Building 42003, has remained a fenced-off crime scene. Local news updates, security barriers on the post and reminders to the community to be on heightened alert for security threats during the trial also have kept the tragedy at the forefront. ''I think obviously everyone is relived that it’s over with,'' Crutchfield said. ''As we see the physical changes with the building and security barriers coming down, we’ll also see emotional changes start to occur.'' Killeen, which adopted ''Where Freedom Grows’' several years ago as its motto, reflecting the city’s ties to one of the world’s largest military installations, will keep ''making lemons into lemonade,'' Crutchfield said. Killeen has relied on the Army as its economic mainstay since Camp Hood was established during World War II. The chapter in local history that began with the worst shooting ever on a U.S. military base is rivaled only by a 1991 mass shooting in Killeen. In that case, George Hennard killed 23 people at a Luby’s restaurant, then turned the gun on himself, in the third-deadliest shooting in U.S. history. Although Hasan’s death sentence will go to an automatic appeal, he will soon be on a one-way flight out of Texas. Hasan, who was treated at Fort Sam Houston in San Antonio for five months after the shooting, has since been kept at the Bell County Jail in nearby Belton. He may be flown as early as Thursday to Fort Leavenworth, Kan. Jerry Haisler, a longtime Killeen-area resident and former president of the local chamber, said Fort Hood-Killeen can start a new chapter. ''It is a good day,'' Haisler said. ''This certainly brings some closure for the families that have been affected.'' ''It’s a very tight-knit community,'' he said. ''This has affected everyone because we’re all family here. Finally, people can move on to the other things in life.'' Part of that process will be completion of a memorial pavilion honoring victims of the shooting that is planned in Killeen. Troy Kelley, a Vietnam veteran and sculptor who is working the project, said a life sentence for Hasan would not have provided a platform the victims’ families need to heal. ''It’s a healing process that probably will never end,'' said Kelley, who is working with a committee that has raised $130,000 for the project but still must collect $250,000. The group has yet to work out details of how the markers of the memorial will explain what happened at Building 42003 on Nov. 5, 2009. But Kelley said he does not want any specific references to Nidal Hasan in the memorial. ''I don’t even want to mention that SOB’s name,'' he said. shuddleston@express-news.net End of trial brings relief to KilleenKilleen residents celebrated the death sentence and end to the Fort Hood trial
</P>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
