<doc id="ENG_DF_001503_20140127_G00A0GHYU">
<headline>
Update to BC Teachers' Strike
</headline>
<post author="chan_konabe" datetime="2014-01-27T22:19:00" id="p1">
For those of you who like updates to stories on old threads, this one made the news today.

The original thread is here:

<a href="http://britishexpats.com/forum/maple-leaf-98/bc-teachers-strike-750253/">BC Teachers' Strike</a>

Today, the BC Supreme Court released its decision on the events surrounding Bill 22 and that teachers' strike from two years ago. Justice Griffin ruled in the teachers' favour. Namely, she

- ruled the government intentionally provoked teachers into a strike to attempt to gain public support for a legislated contact containing strips.
- said the government did not bargain in good faith.
- awarded $2 million in damages to the teachers.
- ruled that stripped language on class size and composition must be restored.

You can find more information on the Vancouver Sun web site.

<a href="http://www.vancouversun.com/business/Court+orders+restore+class+sizes+million+damages+teachers/9436151/story.html">Court orders B.C. to restore class sizes and pay $2 million in damages to teachers</a>
</post>
<post author="Oink" datetime="2014-01-27T22:32:00" id="p2">
<quote orig_author="chan_konabe">
For those of you who like updates to stories on old threads, this one made the news today.

The original thread is here:

<a href="http://britishexpats.com/forum/maple-leaf-98/bc-teachers-strike-750253/">BC Teachers' Strike</a>

Today, the BC Supreme Court released its decision on the events surrounding Bill 22 and that teachers' strike from two years ago. Justice Griffin ruled in the teachers' favour. Namely, she

- ruled the government intentionally provoked teachers into a strike to attempt to gain public support for a legislated contact containing strips.
- said the government did not bargain in good faith.
- awarded $2 million in damages to the teachers.
- ruled that stripped language on class size and composition must be restored.

You can find more information on the Vancouver Sun web site.

<a href="http://www.vancouversun.com/business/Court+orders+restore+class+sizes+million+damages+teachers/9436151/story.html">Court orders B.C. to restore class sizes and pay $2 million in damages to teachers</a>
</quote>
The courts are good at awarding other people's money. <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/thumbdown.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Former Lancastrian" datetime="2014-01-27T22:46:00" id="p3">
Also shows that Governments be they Provincial or Federal don't bargain in good faith with their employees.
</post>
<post author="Oink" datetime="2014-01-27T23:02:00" id="p4">
<quote orig_author="Former Lancastrian">
Also shows that Governments be they Provincial or Federal don't bargain in good faith with their employees.
</quote>
What does good faith mean? They are trying to get the best deal for the taxpayers and students while the union is trying to get the best for itself and its members. Both engage in the manipulation of public opinion to further their own interests.
</post>
<post author="Aviator" datetime="2014-01-27T23:11:00" id="p5">
<quote orig_author="Oink">
What does good faith mean? They are trying to get the best deal for the taxpayers and students while the union is trying to get the best for itself and its members. Both engage in the manipulation of public opinion to further their own interests.
</quote>
I find myself agreeing with you.

Public employees do get a pretty sweet deal compared to private sector.
</post>
<post author="Former Lancastrian" datetime="2014-01-27T23:13:00" id="p6">
Good faith means going into negotiations without telling the other party that this is what we are prepared to impose on you and if you don't agree we will legislate you back to work. Sure both use tactics to the benefit of whom they represent but Im pretty sure if the Govt came in and said Hey BC teachers we are reducing your wages by 25% take it or leave it Im pretty sure the taxpayers and students might agree with this. Would you as a teacher?
There is always room for compromise and even the Unions understand this.
</post>
<post author="Oink" datetime="2014-01-27T23:32:00" id="p7">
Then all options in good faith should be on the table. We’ll give you the percentage raise you want, but you agree to work full time and and take four weeks holiday, that way we can recoup the money lost by charging for the classes you’ll have to teach in the extra two months. And how about giving back those Pro D. days and doing any further education on your own time and with your own money?
</post>
<post author="Jsmth321" datetime="2014-01-28T12:12:00" id="p8">
I wouldn't say the teachers union bargains in good faith either, they can be pretty militant towards anyone who dares disagree with them.

I'd have more sympathy towards public sector employees and union issues if the wages were inline with similar jobs in the private sector, but more times then not, they are paid a significant amount more with far better benefits.

My ex-wife worked for the federal government, made mid 40,000 for unskilled admin work, and only got the job because she knew someone inside, you'd be lucky to get 12/hr in the private sector doing what she did.

I don't find based on whats reported by media, government, and unions that either negotiate in good faith, the unions are just as bad.

As for an employer coming in and imposing wages and such, welcome to the private sector, never worked in a job yet where employees had any say in their wages and benefits, the company says we pay this, you either take it or leave it, no room for negotiation.
</post>
</doc>
