<doc id="ENG_DF_001471_20120427_G00A0FL0L">
<headline>
Article: Recording Record Profits, Apple Must Manufacture in USA
</headline>
<post author="mdntcallr" datetime="2012-04-27T16:56:00" id="p1">
Here is a link to my article at Peace, Love &amp; Apple Pie on Why Apple needs to bring back some manufacturing to the United States.

Hope you all like it. I try to have some good Tech coverage.

Recording Record Profits, Apple Must Manufacture in USA
<a href="http://www.peaceloveapplepie.com/apple-must-manufacture-in-usa/">http://www.peaceloveapplepie.com/apple-must-manufacture-in-usa/</a>
</post>
<post author="*LTD*" datetime="2012-04-27T17:56:00" id="p2">
<quote orig_author="mdntcallr">
Why Apple needs to bring back some manufacturing to the United States.
</quote>

So... why?

Has the average American worker suddenly become more globally competitive overnight?

What is Apple's incentive? THIS is the ONLY question that matters.
</post>
<post author="snberk103" datetime="2012-04-27T18:14:00" id="p3">
A few points about article. It is well written and logically structured. I only skimmed it, but I only caught one typo (look for 'tought')

However. While you mention the quote from the NY Times about how it wasn't the cost of labour that gives China it's edge in attracting the assembly jobs, but the flexibility in creating supply chains and the flexibility of the factories - you don't really address the issue. Your article talks about how China bent over backwards to create a factory for Gorilla glass. In contrast, compare that to a story on the MacRumours front page where Apple's campus in Austin wants to expand, but the various levels of government can't agree on what level of incentives to provide.

Your article also ignores the statements that in China can recruit several hundred low-level engineers in a matter of days, if not hours. Basically, engineers with a technical college diploma. While in the US it would take them weeks if not months to recruit those numbers in a community where they could also afford the land. So.... while Apple may be able to recruit those engineers in LA or NY.... could they afford the real estate to locate a factory there? And in places where they can afford to locate a factory, are there enough engineers who already live there or who would move - at their own expense?

Many parts of an Apple device are in fact manufactured in the US.... primarily chips. It's the assembly that is happening in China. Nonetheless, a lot of spin-off supplier benefits are in the US.

And finally.... just because they can... why should they? One of the reasons the US was able to become so rich was by opening up other countries to American trade. Often those countries were reluctant to give up their own domestic manufacturing in exchange for American imports, and the US would bully or even use force to open them up to "free trade". Free Trade is Free Trade - and the USA can't just decide to change the rules because it is now being out-compteted. Learn to compete... don't close the gates.
</post>
<post author="kdarling" datetime="2012-04-27T20:31:00" id="p4">
I would point out that Samsung says one of the main reasons they built their chip factories in Austin Texas, is because of the quantity of talent available from the local University of Texas Engineering School.

However, I don't believe the need for "hundreds of engineers" at Foxconn.

I think it was more like the need at the time to satisfy Steve Jobs' desire for instant re-manufacturing whenever he wanted a last minute change.
</post>
<post author="entatlrg" datetime="2012-04-27T20:51:00" id="p5">
Unions killed that idea 50+ years ago. The average North American worker is longer interested in working as hard as factory workers do in China.
</post>
<post author="noisycats" datetime="2012-04-27T20:56:00" id="p6">
<quote orig_author="kdarling">
I would point out that Samsung says one of the main reasons they built their chip factories in Austin Texas, is because of the quantity of talent available from the local University of Texas Engineering School.

However, I don't believe the need for "hundreds of engineers" at Foxconn.

I think it was more like the need at the time to satisfy Steve Jobs' desire for instant re-manufacturing whenever he wanted a last minute change.
</quote>

I think the 'hundreds of engineers' needed is directly related to the tens of thousand of assembly line workers that Foxconn has employed. The more I read, the more I am convinced those of us in the "western world" cannot conceive the scale of production needed to produce these devices.

250k employees in one factory?!! That is a small city by our standards--where, hypothetically speaking, every man, woman, and child is employed in one facility.

I honestly think we don't understand nor comprehend.
</post>
</doc>
