<doc id="ENG_DF_001503_20140317_G00A0GIYH">
<headline>
Bitcoins has anyone used them ?
</headline>
<post author="ottotheboar" datetime="2014-03-17T23:00:00" id="p1">
Has anyone on here used bitcoins ? I do not see much use for them unless you made purchases on the old Silk Road or now use Silk Road 2.
</post>
<post author="sir_eccles" datetime="2014-03-17T23:15:00" id="p2">
It's one of those things that smells so strongly of Ponzi pyramid scheme I wish I had got some in the early days when they were cheap as chips. The mining now is almost impossible on a solo basis.

I don't pretend to understand how they work for purchases but it seems they are more of a speculative commodity right now. Fewer and fewer exchanges can seem to swap them out for cash which seems to be a bit alarming. The exchanges themselves seem to be run by the strangest bunch too. Would you trust your cash to someone who trades collectable cards? There is absolutely no oversight or insurance.
</post>
<post author="penguinbar" datetime="2014-03-18T00:54:00" id="p3">
My friends nephew was one of the developers. he was a computer nerd in high school. Now he's a 26 years old multi millionaire.
</post>
<post author="Michael" datetime="2014-03-18T01:41:00" id="p4">
There are so many incompetent and/or shady characters running Bitcoin exchanges that it makes wall street bankers look like geniuses and angles.

MtGox (once the world largest Bitcoin exchange) recently filed for bankruptcy after telling clients for months that they couldn't get their money because the bank only allowed a certain amount of ACH transfers daily and then later told clients they couldn't get their Bitcoins for some other reason. Finally they admitted that about 600,000 client Bitcoins and 100,000 MtGox Bitcoins were lost through theft (about $500 million or 7% of the outstanding Bitcoins).

Other exchanges have also filed for bankruptcy due to stolen/lost Bitcoins and many well know Bitcoin players have been prosecuted for money laundering and other schemes.
</post>
<post author="ChocolateBabz" datetime="2014-03-18T01:50:00" id="p5">
I don't understand what they are <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/sad.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="penguinbar" datetime="2014-03-18T01:52:00" id="p6">
Her nephew left them over a year ago and has his own company now. He's far from shady.
</post>
<post author="Michael" datetime="2014-03-18T02:15:00" id="p7">
<quote orig_author="ChocolateBabz">
I don't understand what they are <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/sad.gif"/>
</quote>
Bitcoins are virtual money that has no intrinsic value but is currently trading for about $630 each.

<a href="http://bitcoincharts.com/markets/currency/USD.html">Current USD Bitcoin Exchanges</a>

Initially someone created a software concept that would produce Bitcoins quickly but as time passed, it became more difficult to create them. After about 8 million Bitcoins were produced, even groups of people with computers couldn't produce Bitcoins without using more electricity than the current trading value of a Bitcoin and then companies produced special hardware that was designed for the sole purpose of producing Bitcoins. When 20 million Bitcoins are eventually produced, no more Bitcoins can be produced.

Bitcoins are held in a blockchain and are validated by groups of miners (people that are producing Bitcoins). Therefore it needs Bitcoin miner software running around the world to validate trades.

Although some stores take Bitcoins and instantly use an exchange to trade it into the local currency (customer usually doesn't know the exchange rate until it is exchanged), most of the trading is for speculation.

Bitstamp is currently the largest USD exchange running out of the UK and LocalBitcoins is similar to an eBay concept of peer to peer trades. If you look at LocalBitcoins during the last 30 days, you will notice that Bitcoins traded as low as $5.76 and as high as $2,000. Most other exchanges have traded Bitcoins between $400-$700 during the past 30 days. Like eBay, you have to be very careful who you are dealing with on LocalBitcoins since they could take your money and not give you Bitcoins or visa/versa.

Silk Road is referred to the illicit trading of Bitcoins usually for drug money laundering purposes.
</post>
<post author="Pulaski" datetime="2014-03-18T02:38:00" id="p8">
<quote orig_author="ChocolateBabz">
I don't understand what they are <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/sad.gif"/>
</quote>

Michael's explanation is correct, but in short and simple terms, Bitcoins are pretend money. No central bank issued them, no country is "standing behind" Bitcoin. It is essentially a very complex confidence trick.

So long as everyone who uses and holds Bitcoins acts as if they continue to believe that Bitcoins have value then everything will continue, but as soon as there is a whiff that "the game is over", they will sink to negligible value very very quickly.

There isn't even a physical banknote or coin, so there isn't even collector value, the currency exists only in the on-line world.

<quote orig_author="penguinbar">
Her nephew left them over a year ago and has his own company now. He's far from shady.
</quote>
Says you! Have you done much due diligence into your friend's nephew? <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/rolleyes.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="rpjs" datetime="2014-03-18T02:40:00" id="p9">
The only difference between bitcoins and tulip bulbs is that when all the fuss dies down, with a tulip bulb you can still grow a pretty flower.
</post>
</doc>
