<doc id="ENG_DF_001503_20140617_G00A0GKM3">
<headline>
BC Teachers strike
</headline>
<post author="Alan2005" datetime="2014-06-17T20:18:00" id="p1">
This is great. Those stroppy teachers with their inflated sense of how much they are worth striking meant that I could drive through the school zones at a proper speed today; none of this 30kph bollocks. I hope it lasts forever.
</post>
<post author="Almost Canadian" datetime="2014-06-17T20:26:00" id="p2">
Are they striking for a sufficiently long period that they will extend their summer vacation?
</post>
<post author="Alan2005" datetime="2014-06-17T20:31:00" id="p3">
<quote orig_author="Almost Canadian">
Are they striking for a sufficiently long period that they will extend their summer vacation?
</quote>
They seem to do it this time every year. One of my neighbours told me that the union spent all the cash and there isn't any strike pay. Dunno if that's true though.

Personally I think it is a small price to pay to save me a minute or so every other day as the local filth quite often have radar near the schools I drive past.
</post>
<post author="Almost Canadian" datetime="2014-06-17T20:37:00" id="p4">
<quote orig_author="Alan2005">
They seem to do it this time every year. One of my neighbours told me that the union spent all the cash and there isn't any strike pay. Dunno if that's true though.

Personally I think it is a small price to pay to save me a minute or so every other day as the local filth quite often have radar near the schools I drive past.
</quote>
OK

The schools that my kids go to always seem to arrange "trips" at this time of year. Anything to avoid having to teach. <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/tongue.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Jsmth321" datetime="2014-06-17T20:48:00" id="p5">
Both sides play dirty games, I can't say I support either side. I don't have kids, so I am not affected directly, but it just seems to be non-stop fights with this union.

Seems the government saves X amount every day they don't work, and some say that is why the government is in no hurry to settle, but I don't know how accurate these reports are.

Maybe teachers should work for individual districts directly, with each district negotiating the contract, and not one contract for all as it appears it is in BC.

Then at-least the entire province would not be on strike at once.
</post>
<post author="rivingtonpike" datetime="2014-06-17T21:01:00" id="p6">
We have a few teachers who are friends who are totally hacked off with the whole thing. What started off as a "moral" crusade (with a bit of a payrise on the side (??!??)) seems to have become hijacked by the Unions. Apparently the teachers didn't realise there wasn't a strike fund kitty left. They thought they'd still get some money. They're also acutely aware their popularity amongst parents now scrambling for childcare - or shelling out $80 a day for 2 in daycare - has diminished dramatically. As a parent with a couple of kids in the system, when someone else's fight directly affects my pocket, my sympathies begin to stretch rather thin (not that I support Union fuelled disputes in general anyway).

Another friend told me at the weekend that the starting pay for a "normal" teacher was in the mid $40k's - rising to $85 (very ish) K for the top grade of a "normal" teacher. But in the Province as a whole the average salary of a teacher is around $78k, so most teachers have been in post so long they almost all get top whack already.

Just saying - and I don't know the veracity of this information.....
</post>
<post author="Almost Canadian" datetime="2014-06-17T21:02:00" id="p7">
<quote orig_author="Jsmth321">
Both sides play dirty games, I can't say I support either side. I don't have kids, so I am not affected directly, but it just seems to be non-stop fights with this union.

Seems the government saves X amount every day they don't work, and some say that is why the government is in no hurry to settle, but I don't know how accurate these reports are.

Maybe teachers should work for individual districts directly, with each district negotiating the contract, and not one contract for all as it appears it is in BC.

Then at-least the entire province would not be on strike at once.
</quote>
Or, return the appropriate amount to taxpayers via a reduction in income/property taxes, and then let the taxpayers negotiate directly with the teachers. Yeah, that'd work <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/rofl.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Alan2005" datetime="2014-06-17T21:16:00" id="p8">
I reckon they are so whiny cos most teachers are married to other teachers so they end up suffering from groupthink like the nazis in Germany.
</post>
<post author="Oink" datetime="2014-06-17T21:23:00" id="p9">
What bunch of greedy self-absorbed bastards. Really putting children first. <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/thumbdown.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="rivingtonpike" datetime="2014-06-17T21:25:00" id="p10">
<quote orig_author="Almost Canadian">
Or, return the appropriate amount to taxpayers via a reduction in income/property taxes, and then let the taxpayers negotiate directly with the teachers. Yeah, that'd work <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/rofl.gif"/>
</quote>
Apparently this strike will save the BC Government more than $160 million in salaries not paid! I even heard as much as $190 million + with other savings made over the 2 weeks.
</post>
</doc>
