<doc id="ENG_DF_001487_20160419_G00A0G8H3">
<headline>
Bring Tebow back to Denver!
</headline>
<post datetime="2016-04-19T11:08:46" id="p1">
<a href="#comment">Skip to comments.</a>
Posted on 04/19/2016 11:08:46 AM PDT by <a href="/~realsaxophonist/">real saxophonist</a>
The Denver Broncos have lost their two main quarterbacks from their epic 2016 Super Bowl Championship winning season. We need a proven winner to continue to move this team in the right direction. Coach Gary Kubiak's offense would thrive with Tebow under center. He and the legendary John Elway can make this happen. We dont need a subpar throwaway from some other team, we need an original Bronco who has the fire, desire, and love of the game to play as a Bronco again! As a bonus the Bronco fans would be ecstatic! He just wins, we all know this! #TebowTime

use the links below to view more comments.,
use the links below to view more comments., Disclaimer: Opinions posted on Free Republic are those of the individual posters and do not necessarily represent the opinion of Free Republic or its management. All materials posted herein are protected by copyright law and the exemption for fair use of copyrighted works.
</post>
<post author="real saxophonist" datetime="2016-04-19T11:08:46" id="p2">
Just saw this on the Denver news. I don't care about the Broncos, but this might provide an entertaining respite from all the Trump/Cruz stuff. Post or flame away!
</post>
<post author="RedWulf" datetime="2016-04-19T11:08:46" id="p3">
I'm still really pissed about what the media did to Tebow. Every time I read an article it was some leftist hack trashing Tebow for being Christian.
</post>
<post author="PAR35" datetime="2016-04-19T11:08:46" id="p4">
I don’t think the NFL would let a team sign Tebow. They are more interested in players with the character of Manziel or the special attraction of Sam.
</post>
<post author="BenLurkin" datetime="2016-04-19T11:08:46" id="p5">
Send Johnny Manziel along with him.
</post>
<post author="xzins" datetime="2016-04-19T11:08:46" id="p6">
Elway hates Tebow. It won’t happen.
</post>
<post author="DoodleDawg" datetime="2016-04-19T11:08:46" id="p7">
Ah if he only had the talent to play at the pro level. But the author didn't specify that so maybe he doesn't think it's necessary?
</post>
<post author="2nd Amendment" datetime="2016-04-19T11:08:46" id="p8">
Tebow puts Elway under conviction. Besides he might run for a Florida House seat.
</post>
<post author="yuleeyahoo" datetime="2016-04-19T11:08:46" id="p9">
Sorry, but Tebow is considering a run for the retiring Ander Crenshaw’s House seat.
Today the House, tomorrow the Governorship!
</post>
<post author="xzins" datetime="2016-04-19T11:08:46" id="p10">
Shades of Heath Shuler
</post>
<post author="Lakeshark" datetime="2016-04-19T11:08:46" id="p11">
Not trying to offend anyone here, but Tebow maybe should have tried another position. He was a gifted athlete, but NOT an NFL calber QB.
He could run over people, but couldn't throw consistently to even be a second string QB.
When he was cut by New England, I knew what I suspected was simply true.
Love the guy, but I don't think he was black balled because he was a Christian.
</post>
<post author="The Louiswu" datetime="2016-04-19T11:08:46" id="p12">
That ship has sailed. Let it be.
</post>
<post author="xzins" datetime="2016-04-19T11:08:46" id="p13">
Something happened between him and Elway, and it wasn’t just Payton Manning.
Turns out Manning was a good decision on Elway’s part, but he sent Tebow out with a bad referral to other teams.
I still cannot account for that.
</post>
<post author="RedWulf" datetime="2016-04-19T11:08:46" id="p14">
&gt;Ah if he only had the talent to play at the pro level. But the author didn’t specify that so maybe he doesn’t think it’s necessary?
He played well enough to get a win in the playoffs. The better than vast majority of Pro QBs. Tebow was a decent ball control QB that could win games with a strong defense and he certainly played better than Manning did last year. Tebow’s primary problem is he’s just not smart enough to be a pro level QB and lead a team effectively. He’d make an excellent tight end.
</post>
<post author="Resolute Conservative" datetime="2016-04-19T11:08:46" id="p15">
Elway is a turd.
</post>
<post author="DoodleDawg" datetime="2016-04-19T11:08:46" id="p16">
As long as he just has to run for the seat. If he has to throw for the seat then he's in trouble.
</post>
<post author="needmorePaine" datetime="2016-04-19T11:08:46" id="p17">
But this describes Tebow as a quarterback.
</post>
<post author="xzins" datetime="2016-04-19T11:08:46" id="p18">
:&gt;)
</post>
<post author="IllumiNaughtyByNature" datetime="2016-04-19T11:08:46" id="p19">
Denver will end up with Colin kaepernick
</post>
<post author="thorvaldr" datetime="2016-04-19T11:08:46" id="p20">
I wouldn’t cost the Broncos anything to tell Tebow “come out to Spring training and show us you are better than Sanchez”. I might even get them some publicity. But realistically, even after his self funded passing coaching, he’s probably not better than Sanchez.
</post>
<post author="Larry Lucido" datetime="2016-04-19T11:08:46" id="p21">
LOL!
</post>
<post author="BenLurkin" datetime="2016-04-19T11:08:46" id="p22">
<img src="http://tse1.mm.bing.net/th?&amp;id=OIP.M855653d1372acac95251a588f1eae7e7o1&amp;w=243&amp;h=300&amp;c=0&amp;pid=1.9&amp;rs=0&amp;p=0&amp;r=0"/> <img src="http://tse1.mm.bing.net/th?&amp;id=OIP.M1e5d9ff508da4c14c72bf8ca1e605c48H1&amp;w=229&amp;h=300&amp;c=0&amp;pid=1.9&amp;rs=0&amp;p=0&amp;r=0"/>
</post>
<post author="yuleeyahoo" datetime="2016-04-19T11:08:46" id="p23">
</post>
<post author="sparklite2" datetime="2016-04-19T11:08:46" id="p24">
... because Christians are known for the inability to read defenses and aren’t very accurate passers.
</post>
<post author="RedWulf" datetime="2016-04-19T11:08:46" id="p25">
&gt;Denver will end up with Colin kaepernick
Another QB too dumb to play in the NFL. Poor Broncos fans.
</post>
<post author="DoodleDawg" datetime="2016-04-19T11:08:46" id="p26">
Last time I checked neither Sam or Manziel was on a team roster. Just like Tebow.
</post>
<post author="Pelham" datetime="2016-04-19T11:08:46" id="p27">
..before the Trump war, there was the Tebow war....
</post>
<post author="DoodleDawg" datetime="2016-04-19T11:08:46" id="p28">
While I'm sure that San Francisco is kicking themselves for keeping Kapernick and letting Alex Smith get away it may be too late for the trade. Denver has Sanchez now. They're looking for a backup for him.
</post>
<post author="RedWulf" datetime="2016-04-19T11:08:46" id="p29">
&gt;As long as he just has to run for the seat. If he has to throw for the seat then he’s in trouble.
Ha!
</post>
<post author="Snickering Hound" datetime="2016-04-19T11:08:46" id="p30">
</post>
</doc>
