<doc id="ENG_DF_001471_20121017_G00A0FLWN">
<headline>
Who thinks Mr Cook is doing a good job.
</headline>
<post author="Mikes2pads" datetime="2012-10-17T13:21:00" id="p1">
You just can't compare the buzz that Steve Jobs created when running HIS company to the mediocre performance and route Apple has taken since Cook stood in.
I just wonder how much Jobs had to do with his appointment.
If its a lot I would certainly be surprised.
I just don't like him so maybe I'm not seeing it clearly.
Issues arose while Steve Jobs ran HIS company but IMO things are not the same.
Who needs a mini iPad? Get the Os's correct before putting them out.
He showed zero respect by not mentioning SJ one time in the keynote for new iPad which has a foolish name, is thicker and does not work.
People, keep your second gen ipads, they are the last thing Steve Jobs crafted and a solid device indeed.
I have little good to say about T. Cook so ill stop here.
Flame me but I know I'm correct in thinking there are two much better choices to run this company. Much better.
</post>
<post author="Gunny011" datetime="2012-10-17T13:26:00" id="p2">
I think he is doing a fine job, I refuse to compare him to Steve, entirely different personalties.

Just look at how emotional he was at the end of WWDC this year when he thanked everyone for contributing to changing people's lives...there was proper emotions flowing through him there. This shows he cares, and that's enough for me when evaluating him.
</post>
<post author="Night Spring" datetime="2012-10-17T13:31:00" id="p3">
Well, Tim Cook sure isn't Steve Jobs, but much as we all wish Jobs were still with us, since he isn't, then who do you think should run Apple, if not Tim Cook? Ive doesn't have the temperament to run a complex cooperation like Apple, Scott Forstall is still unseasoned, Bob Mansfield? Peter Oppenheimer? Philip Schiller? Who would *you* suggest?
</post>
<post author="TC03" datetime="2012-10-17T13:39:00" id="p4">
<quote orig_author="Night Spring">
Well, Tim Cook sure isn't Steve Jobs, but much as we all wish Jobs were still with us, since he isn't, then who do you think should run Apple, if not Tim Cook? Ive doesn't have the temperament to run a complex cooperation like Apple, Scott Forstall is still unseasoned, Bob Mansfield? Peter Oppenheimer? Philip Schiller? Who would *you* suggest?
</quote>

Without any inside knowledge, this is an impossible question to answer.
</post>
<post author="ActionableMango" datetime="2012-10-17T13:43:00" id="p5">
Apple stock is doing fine, so the market seems to disagree with you.

Steve is reported to have had input on years worth of Apple's future product line. It is unreasonable to think he wasn't involved in the new iPad.

The iPad name had to drop the number because of the new iPad Mini line. Sequential numbering doesn't work well for two simultaneous models. iPods, iMacs, MacBook Airs, MacBook Pros, Mac Pros, Mac Minis, and Apple TVs all do fine without a number tacked onto their names.
</post>
<post author="Night Spring" datetime="2012-10-17T13:55:00" id="p6">
<quote orig_author="TC03">
Without any inside knowledge, this is an impossible question to answer.
</quote>

That is kind of my point, but since OP seems to think he knows better, I wanted to see what he has to say.
</post>
<post author="poloponies" datetime="2012-10-17T14:00:00" id="p7">
<quote orig_author="Mikes2pads">
You just can't compare the buzz that Steve Jobs created when running HIS company to the mediocre performance and route Apple has taken since Cook stood in.
I just wonder how much Jobs had to do with his appointment.
If its a lot I would certainly be surprised.
I just don't like him so maybe I'm not seeing it clearly.
Issues arose while Steve Jobs ran HIS company but IMO things are not the same.
Who needs a mini iPad? Get the Os's correct before putting them out.
He showed zero respect by not mentioning SJ one time in the keynote for new iPad which has a foolish name, is thicker and does not work.
People, keep your second gen ipads, they are the last thing Steve Jobs crafted and a solid device indeed.
I have little good to say about T. Cook so ill stop here.
Flame me but I know I'm correct in thinking there are two much better choices to run this company. Much better.
</quote>

Lots of random thoughts here. Jobs appointed Cook as Interim CEO during his extended medical leaves, so Cook was on bench before Jobs formally stepped down. The rest of your post is pretty much subjective.
</post>
<post author="ReValveiT" datetime="2012-10-17T14:02:00" id="p8">
New iPad "does not work"?

Funny how this post made it here then. I must have one of the rare 'does work' new iPads, no?...
</post>
<post author="token787" datetime="2012-10-17T14:04:00" id="p9">
Mmmm, never thought about the iPad 2 like that. Good info on that one, maybe I will buy the 2. <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=";)"/>
</post>
<post author="charlieegan3" datetime="2012-10-17T14:04:00" id="p10">
I think Cook is doing a great job, absolutely no complaints here.
</post>
</doc>
