<doc id="ENG_DF_001471_20141216_G00A02X0G">
<headline>
Apple Store Birmingham - Friday Warning
</headline>
<post author="TheBama" datetime="2014-12-16T20:50:00" id="p1">
Just a heads up to those doing Holiday shopping. A local Black Lives Matter group is planning to shut down the road leading to The Summit where the Apple Store is this Friday at 3. If they pull it off it's going to be a huge mess on the busiest road in the state and people will likely be stuck at the mall.

Would suggest avoiding the area altogether Friday.
</post>
<post author="Wiggle" datetime="2014-12-17T16:06:00" id="p2">
Thus causing everyone to not care about whatever cause they are protesting about. Pissing people off is terrible strategy.
</post>
<post author="Kilamite" datetime="2014-12-18T03:19:00" id="p3">
<quote orig_author="Wiggle">
Thus causing everyone to not care about whatever cause they are protesting about. Pissing people off is terrible strategy.
</quote>

If they didn't, then no one would pay attention to their protest.
</post>
<post author="Wiggle" datetime="2014-12-18T07:47:00" id="p4">
<quote orig_author="Kilamite">
If they didn't, then no one would pay attention to their protest.
</quote>

This is definitely ONE way to get people to pay attention, it's NOT the way to get people to care about it.
</post>
<post author="Huntn" datetime="2014-12-19T07:46:00" id="p5">
<quote orig_author="Wiggle">
Thus causing everyone to not care about whatever cause they are protesting about. Pissing people off is terrible strategy.
</quote>

Protests are viable and are the only recourse aside from violence when the system fails you. Labor unions do this quite successfully, but usually are more orderly (strike) although some people still get pissed about the inconvenience.
</post>
<post author="Mr. McMac" datetime="2014-12-19T07:52:00" id="p6">
I'm sick and tired of hearing about these protests. I wish they'd all get a job and stop this nonsense.
</post>
<post author="mercuryjones" datetime="2014-12-19T07:55:00" id="p7">
<quote orig_author="Huntn">
Protests are viable and are the only recourse aside from violence when the system fails you. Labor unions do this quite successfully, but usually are more orderly (strike) although some people still get pissed about the inconvenience.
</quote>

Yes, protests are visible and one of the main ways to get that information out, but there has to be a better way than blocking traffic on a Friday? At that point, all they are going to accomplish is to piss people off and then the message gets lost. Just like when the people looted and burned buildings and cars after the verdict. It does no good at all for the cause.
</post>
<post author="Aspasia" datetime="2014-12-19T07:56:00" id="p8">
<quote orig_author="Wiggle">
This is definitely ONE way to get people to pay attention, it's NOT the way to get people to care about it.
</quote>

Yes. When I see of gangs shutting down traffic (causing people to be late picking up their kids, or missing their trains/flights) and generally causing mayhem, what sympathy I may have had for their cause evaporates.
</post>
<post author="rdowns" datetime="2014-12-19T08:41:00" id="p9">
Yes, because being inconvenienced in traffic is way more important than shining a light on racism in this country.
</post>
<post author="mercuryjones" datetime="2014-12-19T10:31:00" id="p10">
<quote orig_author="rdowns">
Yes, because being inconvenienced in traffic is way more important than shining a light on racism in this country.
</quote>

If this is in regards to Ferguson, then it's not about "shining a light on racism".
</post>
<post author="Aspasia" datetime="2014-12-19T17:44:00" id="p11">
<quote orig_author="rdowns">
Yes, because being inconvenienced in traffic is way more important than shining a light on racism in this country.
</quote>

The mobs in Ferguson and in other cities where they looted, destroyed, and in some cases, became violent, may have garnered respect in your eyes, but not in mine.

Blocking streets, bridges, tunnels, etc. goes beyond just causing "inconvenience." Ask any ambulance driver or first responder trying to get through.
</post>
</doc>
