<doc id="ENG_DF_001471_20130729_G00A01RYW">
<headline>
Banks and the control of Aluminium
</headline>
<post author="luffytubby" datetime="2013-07-29T02:04:00" id="p1">
Link; <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/07/21/business/a-shuffle-of-aluminum-but-to-banks-pure-gold.html?pagewanted=all&amp;_r=0">http://www.nytimes.com/2013/07/21/b...t-to-banks-pure-gold.html?pagewanted=all&amp;_r=0</a>

Basically many banks have begun buying all the factories that produce and distribute Aluminium. A desired Metal, from which Iphones and Macbooks are made of.
What the Banks do is that they have increased the weight time for companies to get a shipment of Aluminium from 3-4 months, to 16 months.
They drive these trucks of Aluminium through "check ups" between warehouses almost endlessly.
Why? Aluminium is a great product and near irreplaceable. For what purpose? Much like the diamond industry, they can manipulate supply and demand, and rise the prices. If it's suddenly harder to get a hold of Aluminium everyone has to pay more (Apple, Coca-Cola etc) to all the people in the banks who own these Aluminium factories.

What do you think? Could there be a link? Since Apple can't use another metal alloy with the same benefits as Aluminium, doesn't it make sense to make a cheaper more mass produced Plastic version, while keeping the Aluminium products in the higher pro-consumer bracket. They can make lot less of them, so they need a lot less aluminium compared to if every entry Iphone or Ipad was made from Aluminium. With a 200 Dollars less device, maybe only one/8th or one/10th of a device would be made from Aluminium, allowing Apple to get away from these banks chokeholds of a desired ground material.
</post>
<post author="waa1futs" datetime="2013-07-29T02:15:00" id="p2">
Hopefully this forces Apple to bring back the glass / stainless steel design of the 4 and 4s for future iPhones <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=":D"/>

Aluminum is quite crappy when it comes to scuffs since its so soft <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=":("/>
</post>
<post author="atlatnesiti" datetime="2013-07-29T02:37:00" id="p3">
First of all, in comparison to automotive, building or food and drink industries around the world, Apple use of aluminium is minimal - tiny drop in the ocean.
Secondly, let's not forget about Apple acquisition and recent patent for Liquid Metal manufacturing.
There are always alternatives... <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=";)"/>
</post>
<post author="ogremoustro" datetime="2013-07-29T02:50:00" id="p4">
Hmm i thought the wait before was 3-4 weeks.
</post>
<post author="Lucille Carter" datetime="2013-07-29T03:08:00" id="p5">
I think the cost of Aluminum and it availablity has little to do with Apple's products. <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=":rolleyes:"/>

If we use millions of aluminum cans each day, many that are tossed away, we need not worry.
</post>
<post author="paulbennett95" datetime="2013-07-29T04:16:00" id="p6">
Aluminum is one of the most common metals in the Earths crust and we've gotten good at extracting it from ores, so I don't think there's some conspiracy to cut the supply...

Or blame the Zionist banking corporations for the cheap iPhone! Down with the Rothschilds! <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=":rolleyes:"/>
</post>
<post author="ucfgrad93" datetime="2013-07-29T04:19:00" id="p7">
<quote orig_author="paulbennett95">
Aluminum is one of the most common metals in the Earths crust and we've gotten good at extracting it from ores, so I don't think there's some conspiracy to cut the supply.
</quote>

Agreed. This is much ado about nothing.
</post>
<post author="LethalWolfe" datetime="2013-07-30T09:05:00" id="p8">
<quote orig_author="paulbennett95">
Aluminum is one of the most common metals in the Earths crust and we've gotten good at extracting it from ores, so I don't think there's some conspiracy to cut the supply...
</quote>

What does one have to do with the other? If the supply to buyers is being constrained then the prices can be raised by the sellers regardless of how much raw material is available. Classic examples being diamonds or oil. For example, OPEC can manipulate fuel prices up or down by how much oil they ship regardless of how much is still in the ground.

Unless end buyers of aluminum get into the mining and processing business it doesn't how much ore is in the ground. It only matters how much usable material is available in the marketplace.

I would be surprised though if this had anything to do with Apple presumably using plastic for the rumored economy-class iPhone.
</post>
<post author="elistan" datetime="2013-08-12T22:12:00" id="p9">
Back in the news:

U.S. Subpoenas Goldman in Inquiry of Aluminum Warehouses
By DAVID KOCIENIEWSKI

<a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/08/13/business/us-subpoenas-goldman-in-inquiry-of-aluminum-warehouses.html?partner=rss&amp;emc=rss">http://www.nytimes.com/2013/08/13/b...-aluminum-warehouses.html?partner=rss&amp;emc=rss</a>

To give an idea of the scale:

<quote>
Industry analysts and beverage makers estimate that long queues cost manufacturers and consumers more than $5 billion.
</quote>

Kinda like Office Space - a few cents from each transaction is hopefully hidden from the end user, but aggregated they total billions. $5 billion across 300 million Americans is "only" $16.66 each, but it's still more than we would have allegedly paid otherwise. Imagine if this was then the case for EVERY commodity.
</post>
</doc>
