<doc id="ENG_DF_001471_20160314_G00A0G6F8">
<headline>
Best way to prevent Soros funded thugs from breaking up Trump rallies
</headline>
<post author="XrayTed" datetime="2016-03-14T14:26:00" id="p1">
Seems very likely things will escalate into havoc and violence - Indeed, that seems to be the goal of the well known leftist nation wrecking foreign shill Soros.
Hire inherently violent, unemployed and aimless minorities already whipped into an anti establishment frenzy by Obama to agitate and intimidate, then when the **** hits the fan, blame it on the rhetoric of Trump and claim the hired thugs were just peaceful, grass roots protesters who were innocently protesting and attacked by angry mobs of neo Nazi whites.

So it would behoove those of us interested in the rule of law and 1st amendment rights to find ways to prevent these anarchic 3rd world rented left wing urban terrorists from doing their dirty work in this once great nation of ours, and a couple ideas come to mind.

Charge anyone entering $20 and require legal, state issued ID.
That would ordinarily filter out about 99.9% of them, but with the Soros funding, they could easily get around the $$ barrier. State ID barrier not so easy, that should filter out at least half to 75% of them. Add a requirement that those with felonies will not be allowed in, then we are back up to the 90% region in many locations, add drug screening and consistent 100% nation wide,,, But that would take alot of pre planning to accomplish, something not always feasible in campaign rallies.

Then, they can "peacefully protest" outside until their cold little lizard hearts are content, and the $$ raised by the rally would be donated to charity.

Any more ideas ?
</post>
<post author="rdowns" datetime="2016-03-14T14:46:00" id="p2">
Can't trust Trump with the money. He says he raised $6 million for veterans yet only ~$2,000,000 of it has been donated. I don't think the funds earned from your stellar idea would ever make it out of his pockets.

EDIT: Corrected 200,000 to 2,000,000.
</post>
<post author="Praxis91" datetime="2016-03-14T14:49:00" id="p3">
Trump should just rename his rallies job fairs.
</post>
<post author="steve knight" datetime="2016-03-14T14:49:00" id="p4">
<quote orig_author="XrayTed">
Charge anyone entering $20 and require legal, state issued ID.
That would ordinarily filter out about 99.9% of them, but with the Soros funding, they could easily get around the $$ barrier. State ID barrier not so easy, that should filter out at least half to 75% of them. ?
</quote>

that may take out most of his supporters.
</post>
<post author="FieldingMellish" datetime="2016-03-14T14:53:00" id="p5">
Intimidating protestors paid to arrive in droves contrasted with Obama about to empty jails of convicted felons.... Coincidence?
</post>
<post author="vrDrew" datetime="2016-03-14T15:08:00" id="p6">
Donald Trump charging $20 to go to one of his rallies?

Well it certainly would remove all doubt: Trump supporters have to be the most gullible saps on the planet. And it would add an extra tinge of seediness to Trumps glowing reputation as a con-man and rip-off artist. Think Trump University writ small.

But it would do nothing to prevent people from protesting outside the facilities. Where most of last weeks protestors were located. The thought of a having to face huge crowds of people holding up banners decrying racism; xenophobia; and hatred probably will keep at least a few of the Trump suckers home in their trailers.

I do love the George Soros paranoia in this thread. There is creepy <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Protocols_of_the_Elders_of_Zion">Protocols of The Elders of Zion</a> element to the whole thing. (Question: Has anyone actually claimed they got paid to protest at Trump's Chicago fest?)

The thing that stinks to high heaven is the revolting racism. The assumption that african-americans and latinos couldn't afford $20. The assumption that they don't have "state-issued" local ID: At the Chicago event many of the protestors were local University students. Many of the Trump supporters were from Wisconsin and Indiana.
</post>
</doc>
