<doc id="ENG_DF_001503_20130521_G00A0AV22">
<headline>
Ship SOfas?
</headline>
<post author="Flames123" datetime="2013-05-21T11:23:00" id="p1">
Hi all - i know the Australian Quarantine is rather strict in what we can and cannot bring to the country. That said, I am planning on shipping most items of Personal effects to Oz (to help offset initial relocating costs)
Among my electrical and electronic stuff, i have rather good furniture (finished properly - not rough and untreated) such as King SIze Bed / 6 door wardrobe/ Sofa set/ Hutch etc. - can ship them?

WOuld there be any reason I should not be bringing them even if they are good, fine and treated properly?

That said, Can i bring Leather Furniture/ Sofas?

Any help will be much appreciated

Thanks in advance.
</post>
<post author="Bikergirl" datetime="2013-05-21T11:27:00" id="p2">
We brought with us leather sofa, Pine wood bookcases and unit and bed frames as well as outdoor wooden furniture with no problems at all.
</post>
<post author="Tiawamutu" datetime="2013-05-21T11:36:00" id="p3">
We brought our 2 sofas, IKEA furniture, Sofa bed etc.

We even brought our used dyson hoover (thoroughly cleaned of course)

We also brought an LCD TV which worked fine with our english DVD HD recorder, until the TV broke after 6 months and then DVD didn't work and we only had sound with no vision <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/sad.gif"/>

Don't think TV's travel too well, as they're not that careful with the boxes, and we found our TV in it's box on it's side <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/sad.gif"/>
We also had to pay duty on it (around $350) as it was less than a year old.

Didn't have any quarantine issues.
</post>
<post author="rasen78" datetime="2013-05-21T12:01:00" id="p4">
Most household items/furniture will be fine. Anything that has untreated wood may not, depends on what it is. Our daughter's untreated wood doll's house and contents went through fine. Rattan, wicker, anything with pine cones etc will not be allowed (not sure if painted is ok though <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/confused.gif"/> ), so check your Christmas decorations etc. Any outdoor stuff will need to be thoroughly cleaned - spray/scrub with Jeyes fluid.
</post>
<post author="Kapri" datetime="2013-05-23T20:44:00" id="p5">
<quote orig_author="Tiawamutu">
We brought our 2 sofas, IKEA furniture, Sofa bed etc.

We even brought our used dyson hoover (thoroughly cleaned of course)

We also brought an LCD TV which worked fine with our english DVD HD recorder, until the TV broke after 6 months and then DVD didn't work and we only had sound with no vision <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/sad.gif"/>

Don't think TV's travel too well, as they're not that careful with the boxes, and we found our TV in it's box on it's side <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/sad.gif"/>
We also had to pay duty on it (around $350) as it was less than a year old.

Didn't have any quarantine issues.
</quote>
Hello stranger <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/biggrin.gif"/>

How did they know it was less than a year old? Did you have to declare it?
Our telly is 18 months old so no probs but our washing machine is only 3 months old.
</post>
<post author="Jilliebee" datetime="2013-05-23T21:04:00" id="p6">
You should declare anything under 12 months old x
</post>
<post author="Blossom" datetime="2013-06-15T13:58:00" id="p7">
Well I had a 40ft container of household items of furniture and most of it under 12 months old or new (bedding light fittings curtains etc). I then bought a rangemaster cooker and had that sent direct to shippers and none of this was declared as new and all went through without any problems. Customs inspected the container and never blinked an eye - even though several large items (cooker - garden settings etc) were all brand new and in original packing.

Two leather sofas under 12 months old and a dining suite also included. the only items they actually looked at were christmas decorations and the kept two back because one santa had twine around him - oh and one bell had fake berries on it (go figure that one)!
</post>
<post author="Alfresco" datetime="2013-06-15T20:03:00" id="p8">
<quote orig_author="Kapri">
Hello stranger <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/biggrin.gif"/>

How did they know it was less than a year old? Did you have to declare it?
Our telly is 18 months old so no probs but our washing machine is only 3 months old.
</quote>

<quote orig_author="Jilliebee">
You should declare anything under 12 months old x
</quote>
Yes, indeed. We brought a brand new tumble dryer over and paid duty on it. It was small amount but worth it.
</post>
</doc>
