<doc id="ENG_DF_001471_20151217_G00A0G3AL">
<headline>
Obama prepares for executive order on guns?
</headline>
<post author="lostngone" datetime="2015-12-17T14:40:00" id="p1">
"Obama meets Bloomberg as he prepares order on guns"
<a href="http://www.cnn.com/2015/12/16/politics/obama-mike-bloomberg-gun-control/index.html">http://www.cnn.com/2015/12/16/politics/obama-mike-bloomberg-gun-control/index.html</a>
"As his administration prepares an executive order tightening access to guns"

Time for body armor, a bunker and some popcorn! This is going to be one hell of a show! It would be funny if it wasn't so serious.
</post>
<post author="Renzatic" datetime="2015-12-17T14:51:00" id="p2">
I doubt it'll amount to much of anything other than yet another feel good "hey, at least we're doing SOMETHING about all this crazy violence" gesture.

The moment it pops out of his mouth, those with concerns will pitch a fit, it'll be dragged before SCOTUS, and probably deemed in violation of the 2nd. Democrats look like they made an effort. Republicans look like they're fighting the good fight. Nothing gets done other than generating more talking points. POLITICS!
</post>
<post author="steve knight" datetime="2015-12-17T14:59:00" id="p3">
<quote orig_author="lostngone">
"Obama meets Bloomberg as he prepares order on guns"
<a href="http://www.cnn.com/2015/12/16/politics/obama-mike-bloomberg-gun-control/index.html">http://www.cnn.com/2015/12/16/politics/obama-mike-bloomberg-gun-control/index.html</a>
"As his administration prepares an executive order tightening access to guns"

Time for body armor, a bunker and some popcorn! This is going to be one hell of a show! It would be funny if it wasn't so serious.
</quote>

wonder how many white men will be turned in hording ammo and guns?
</post>
<post author="jkcerda" datetime="2015-12-17T15:06:00" id="p4">
<quote orig_author="Renzatic">
I doubt it'll amount to much of anything other than yet another feel good "hey, at least we're doing SOMETHING about all this crazy violence" gesture.

The moment it pops out of his mouth, those with concerns will pitch a fit, it'll be dragged before SCOTUS, and probably deemed in violation of the 2nd. Democrats look like they made an effort. Republicans look like they're fighting the good fight. Nothing gets done other than generating more talking points. POLITICS!
</quote>

SCOTUS is not interested in dealing with challenges.
</post>
<post author="Renzatic" datetime="2015-12-17T15:18:00" id="p5">
<quote orig_author="jkcerda">
SCOTUS is not interested in dealing with challenges.
</quote>

Yeah, because we all know how they've played it safe over the last 20 odd years, concerning everything from gun control to gay marriage.
</post>
<post author="webbuzz" datetime="2015-12-17T15:22:00" id="p6">
He likes common sense gun control.
</post>
<post author="jkcerda" datetime="2015-12-17T15:22:00" id="p7">
<quote orig_author="Renzatic">
Yeah, because we all know how they've played it safe over the last 20 odd years, concerning everything from gun control to gay marriage.
</quote>

they don't get that involved in guns, at least not that I have seen
</post>
<post author="LizKat" datetime="2015-12-17T15:35:00" id="p8">
<quote orig_author="steve knight">
wonder how many white men will be turned in hording ammo and guns?
</quote>

What would law enforcement do anyway, past keeping an eye on them. No one wants another Waco type of situation. It's only if someone with a lot of weaponry and ammo actually starts something that the authorities are likely to step in because, no other option.

So LE gets all this military stuff from the government, and that makes the hoarders nervous and angry so they buy more stuff? The percentage of households with guns is more or less stable so it's the same people amping up their inventory. What a mess, and it's not even a mess yet.
</post>
<post author="Renzatic" datetime="2015-12-17T16:05:00" id="p9">
<quote orig_author="jkcerda">
they don't get that involved in guns, at least not that I have seen
</quote>

The weird thing about SCOTUS decisions involving gun control is that it weirdly aligns with conservative ideals regarding the division between the states and government, while biting them in the ass over it at the same time.

Basically, they've gone on record stating that the federal government can't impede the 2nd amendment, which means any executive action Obama takes will probably be struck down if it's too vague or widespread.

But on a state and local level? Well hell, that's up to them. SCOTUS usually doesn't get involved.
</post>
<post author="einmusiker" datetime="2015-12-17T16:23:00" id="p10">
I hope so! About time someone in government has the gonads to actually do some work
</post>
<post author="lowendlinux" datetime="2015-12-17T23:35:00" id="p11">
The idea is fine the means are the issue. I understand he can't get anything done but if he does this then nothing will get done for a long while.
</post>
<post author="Eraserhead" datetime="2015-12-17T23:43:00" id="p12">
<quote orig_author="lowendlinux">
The idea is fine the means are the issue. I understand he can't get anything done but if he does this then nothing will get done for a long while.
</quote>

Nothing will be done until if/when the Republican Party collapses.
</post>
<post author="lowendlinux" datetime="2015-12-17T23:50:00" id="p13">
<quote orig_author="Eraserhead">
Nothing will be done until if/when the Republican Party collapses.
</quote>

But it won't
</post>
</doc>
