<doc id="ENG_DF_001471_20111104_G00A0FKEO">
<headline>
The Dark Side of Apple, Do You Contribute?
</headline>
<post author="sumone" datetime="2011-11-04T13:35:00" id="p1">
Just read this article online

<a href="http://finance.yahoo.com/blogs/daily-ticker/darker-side-apple-human-cost-iproducts-164412176.html">http://finance.yahoo.com/blogs/daily-ticker/darker-side-apple-human-cost-iproducts-164412176.html</a>

To sum it up many workers at Foxconn experience horrible work conditions as a result of trying to complete demand for various different tech devices by companies like HP, Nokia and Apple. In order to reduce the stress that's put on workers, monologist Mike Daisey, suggested that consumers NOT update devices as frequently. Thoughts?
</post>
<post author="miles01110" datetime="2011-11-04T13:39:00" id="p2">
<quote>
To sum it up many workers in third-world countries experience horrible work conditions as a result of trying to complete demand for various different products for first-world businesses.
</quote>

Fixed that for you. Apple isn't alone.
</post>
<post author="sumone" datetime="2011-11-04T13:48:00" id="p3">
<quote orig_author="miles01110">
Fixed that for you. Apple isn't alone.
</quote>

I never said Apple was alone I even stated some of the other companies mentioned that employed Foxconn.
</post>
<post author="dukebound85" datetime="2011-11-04T13:53:00" id="p4">
Yup and I don't lose sleep over it
</post>
<post author="wrinkster22" datetime="2011-11-04T13:53:00" id="p5">
I know apple factories are not pleasant but no other company treats their employees well either, I think as consumers we need to make the choice of buying things made in North America at a higher price vs. things made in China at a lower price. With the costs of many things going up I do not think we as consumers can afford higher costs. I, purposely try to buy things made in Canada or USA. We are all to blame at this mess- consumers wanting cheap goods, Wal Mart and other big box stores importing things, and the chinese governments openness to these horrible factories.
Also manufacturing of goods in china dwindles the jobs in America.
Also stuff made here lasts longer and is better quality.
Another video about foxconn: go to youtube and search foxconn- the first one foxconn lies.
</post>
<post author="Apple OC" datetime="2011-11-04T13:59:00" id="p6">
not much the consumer can do when the products they want are produced under these terms... all computers are made this way
</post>
<post author="sumone" datetime="2011-11-04T14:10:00" id="p7">
<quote orig_author="wrinkster22">
I think as consumers we need to make the choice of buying things made in North America at a higher price vs. things made in China at a lower price. With the costs of many things going up I do not think we as consumers can afford higher costs.
</quote>

Hypothetically speaking, say that we as consumers refused to buy products that were made under these conditions. As you predicted the result would be that the prices would go up but say consumers refused to pay the higher prices. Something would have to give, so what would be the result? Would the companies just go out of business? Or would the companies be willing to take a hit like instead of bringing in over 50% profits on each iPhone sold Apple would settle for less?

----------

<quote orig_author="Apple OC">
not much the consumer can do when the products they want are produced under these terms... all computers are made this way
</quote>

Well according to the article you could help out by not buying a product as soon as a new one comes out. Well i'm not entirely certain the impression that I got was that the conditions are especially harsh because the company is trying to meet increasing demand. If people didn't swarm to buy the newest product every time they are released the demand for products wouldn't be as high and the workers would not be worked as hard.
</post>
<post author="velocityg4" datetime="2011-11-04T14:10:00" id="p8">
Isn't replacing "When the next on comes out." and "is no longer current" the same thing?

I replace mine when it is no longer performs the tasks I want it to or need it to perform. If it has failed I replace it if the cost to benefit ration of a new model outweighs the cost to benefit ratio of repairing it.

Though I generally buy used products at a heavy discount over new. Excepting those where age or wear and tear make a huge difference in useful life vs cost. Or were used has little cost benefit over new.

Anything heavy duty and mechanical I definitely buy used. That way I can buy something that is top of the line and built in the USA or other first world nation. Rather than some cheap POS built in China. I'll take my Kirby vacuum and Kitchen Aid Pro Series mixer over something cheap built in China. They'll withstand more use and abuse plus have a much longer overall lifespan.

Sure some well made stuff can come from China. When the company contracting insists on the factory to meet stringent quality standards. But they are usually more interested in price over quality.
</post>
</doc>
