<doc id="ENG_DF_001503_20140216_G00A0GID3">
<headline>
Berlusca
</headline>
<post author="Maybe1day" datetime="2014-02-16T07:01:00" id="p1">
I must have missed something. I thought Berlusca was supposed to be under house arrest or something. Now i see him meeting Napolitano?
It's all a fiendish plot, Berlusca will win the next election thanks to Renzi splitting the PD. He will quash all his court cases and convictions. Renzi will become the PM for Forza Italia and Berlusca will be the next Italian President by the end of 2015. What bets with William Hill?
M
</post>
<post author="heritagestanley" datetime="2014-02-16T14:37:00" id="p2">
What an amazing business. We seem to have an unholy combination of two old blokes who should have left the stage a long time ago plus one young bloke whose only experience is in local government and who's never even been elected to the national Parliament
</post>
<post author="Patty" datetime="2014-02-16T15:00:00" id="p3">
As usual Italian politics makes Eastenders look almost serious <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/wink.gif"/>
I'm trying to see the funny side but living here its very hard - I feel like crying !!
It really is the most farcical situation ever and the whole thing should never have been allowed to happen. Napolitano is abusing his powers and should retire from the scene. Only problem is that I too, fear that Berli has his eye on the presidency. Then we will all have to pack our bags I think <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/tongue.gif"/>
(Inciucio is the word I think- hear it alot but not sure of the actual english translation ?)
</post>
<post author="Garbatellamike" datetime="2014-02-16T17:26:00" id="p4">
<quote orig_author="Patty">
As usual Italian politics makes Eastenders look almost serious <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/wink.gif"/>
I'm trying to see the funny side but living here its very hard - I feel like crying !!
It really is the most farcical situation ever and the whole thing should never have been allowed to happen. Napolitano is abusing his powers and should retire from the scene. Only problem is that I too, fear that Berli has his eye on the presidency. Then we will all have to pack our bags I think <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/tongue.gif"/>
(Inciucio is the word I think- hear it alot but not sure of the actual english translation ?)
</quote>
inciucio is mess or mess ups - I think.

Berli only wants the Presidency if it comes with more executive power like the US methinks. Napolitano was struggling with old age in his last term and now.....well!
</post>
<post author="Maybe1day" datetime="2014-02-18T07:12:00" id="p5">
I still don't understand why he isn't under house arrest or doing social work?
M
</post>
<post author="sunnysider" datetime="2014-02-18T07:23:00" id="p6">
Am am total agreement with Patty.

It's awful.

Beyond belief.

But it's real and it's Italy.

Where there is no law.

A few years ago when there was a real prospect of Berlusconi realising his ambition to be president I said to an Italian of my acquaintance that the prospect was horrific.

"Well good, it will get him out of our hair" (teachers) I was told.

Yes a throwaway comment maybe but I'm afraid that this jaundiced Italy watcher sees the place as just a load of factional interests. Goes for rather a lot on the "left" as well I fear.
</post>
<post author="sunnysider" datetime="2014-02-18T07:30:00" id="p7">
<quote orig_author="Garbatellamike">
inciucio is mess or mess ups - I think.
</quote>
This implies the "bungle" "incompetence" view of the reasons behind bad stuff.

I rather thought "inciucio" was at the "conspiracy" end of the range of interpretations and meant "stitch up".

(I remember a couple of ears ago seeing a very funny online debate where someone was claiming that "stitch-up" in English meant to repair something, to make it good. I'm pretty sure the person claiming this was Italian which made it even more bizarre since the debate was about "inciucio" which unless I'm pretty much mistaken is used with a snarl/sneer in Italy. In the end an English person said "I give up, English is now a world language, it no longer belongs to the British and hasn't for a long time, if that's what you say "stitch up" means then maybe it does" <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/smile.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Maybe1day" datetime="2014-02-18T07:34:00" id="p8">
<quote orig_author="sunnysider">
This implies the "bungle" "incompetence" view of the reasons behind bad stuff.

I rather thought "inciucio" was at the "conspiracy" end of the range of interpretations and meant "stitch up".

(I remember a couple of ears ago seeing a very funny online debate where someone was claiming that "stitch-up" in English meant to repair something, to make it good. I'm pretty sure the person claiming this was Italian which made it even more bizarre since the debate was about "inciucio" which unless I'm pretty much mistaken is used with a snarl/sneer in Italy. In the end an English person said "I give up, English is now a world language, it no longer belongs to the British and hasn't for a long time, if that's what you say "stitch up" means then maybe it does" <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/smile.gif"/>
</quote>
I'll go for stitch-up !
Back to the original question, why haven't the magistrates had him put away in one way or another?
M
</post>
</doc>
