<doc id="ENG_DF_001503_20140502_G00A0AIIF">
<headline>
Ontario Election 2014
</headline>
<post author="magnumpi" datetime="2014-05-02T14:39:00" id="p1">
<a href="http://metronews.ca/news/toronto/1020952/horwath-says-ndp-wont-support-budget-ontario-headed-for-early-election/">http://metronews.ca/news/toronto/102...arly-election/</a>

Bring it on, I can use my vote this time.

Ontario voters are heading to the polls next month.

A June election is a certainty after NDP Leader Andrea Horwath said her party could not support the budget tabled by Premier Kathleen Wynne’s minority Liberals.
</post>
<post author="Former Lancastrian" datetime="2014-05-02T15:00:00" id="p2">
Can Ontario even afford an election <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/lol.gif"/>
Reading some of the comments from Ontarians Im glad Im not living in that Province anymore.
The liberals are hated after McGuinty, the Cons are hated after Harris and some still even blame Bob Rae when he was with the NDP.
So as an Ontarian who do you vote for?
Regardless of who wins be it majority or minority that Province is in DEBT so how do you spend less? I can see a lot of Ontario Public Service workers thinking
Oh shit Im about to be told to bend over and they won't use any lube or kiss me.
</post>
<post author="magnumpi" datetime="2014-05-02T15:02:00" id="p3">
Rob Ford for premier Lol
</post>
<post author="Zoe Bell" datetime="2014-05-02T15:50:00" id="p4">
I will be voting for the first person that runs their campaign by telling me why I SHOULD vote for them, rather than simply slagging the opposition off.

I don't hold out much hope.
</post>
<post author="Former Lancastrian" datetime="2014-05-02T16:10:00" id="p5">
<quote orig_author="Zoe Bell">
I will be voting for the first person that runs their campaign by telling me why I SHOULD vote for them, rather than simply slagging the opposition off.

I don't hold out much hope.
</quote>
But haven't politicians tried this before? Vote for me because I will do this and do that etc etc and then get elected and break all these promises. Even when they can vote on something they promised you if the Party thinks its a bad idea then they whip the vote along party lines a la gun registry reform a few years ago.
Currently IMHO voters are showing apathy during various elections as they simply believe politicians of all stripes cannot be trusted which of course is not true.
You can run with the best intentions and if you don't give what the voters want in their opinion then you have failed.
How many think when the gun registry was introduced that it was a good idea. How many elected officials voted in favour of it when clearly their constituents wanted them to vote against it.
</post>
<post author="Bleepedy Bloops" datetime="2014-05-03T17:13:00" id="p6">
I'm voting Green for the first time in my life. I just look at the candidates, and every year it seems like their talking points and tactics are getting more stoopider and juvenile. The level of political discourse is depressingly low and uninspiring.

This province used to have great leadership many many years ago, Bill Davis comes to mind....I figure since this election is going to be a complete washout for any party looking for a mandate....might as well vote with my gut.
</post>
</doc>
