<doc id="ENG_DF_001471_20120923_G00A01ATM">
<headline>
Riot at Taiyun Factory
</headline>
<post author="pwhitehead" datetime="2012-09-23T21:32:00" id="p1">
Why cant this employees just get good pay and equal share? They bust their asses to bring us great products. At least their not jumping off buildings this time.

<quote>
Foxconn, a contract manufacturer to Apple, closed a northern China factory for the day following an early Monday riot that, according to the company, began as a fight between workers. Details remain scarce.

The company said several people were injured and sent to the hospital after the incident, and that some were also detained by police. The factory in question employees about 79,000 workers.

Other reports, however, described a riot possibly involving as many as 2,000 people and, by one account, potentially sparked when a guard struck a worker. Photos posted by a user on the Chinese Internet service Baidu depicted lines of helmet-clad riot police surrounding what appeared to be workers and rooms littered with detritus and glass from broken windows.

Earlier this month, a Shanghai Evening Post journalist claimed to have gone undercover at the Taiyun plant. He described his orientation, plant security and his job, which was supposedly to manufacture the back plate of the iPhone 5.

Back in March, the head of human resources at the Taiyun factory reportedly told a South Korean newspaper that Foxconn had "just got[ten] the order" for the iPhone 5. That was just a few weeks after a reported strike involving hundreds of workers over a pay dispute at the Taiyun plant.

We'll update this story as we know more.

Updated 8:46 p.m. PT: with more details.
<a href="http://news.cnet.com/8301-1001_3-57518617-92/apple-supplier-foxconn-confirms-worker-riot-at-taiyun-factory/">http://news.cnet.com/8301-1001_3-57...xconn-confirms-worker-riot-at-taiyun-factory/</a>
</quote>
</post>
<post author="Cinematographer" datetime="2012-09-24T00:46:00" id="p2">
I have to ask myself: Does more excitement on the customer's side (for the new products) result in more pressure on the worker's side?

Edit: there's a video about it.

<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;v=8FqKkQJIf9s">http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;v=8FqKkQJIf9s</a>
</post>
<post author="Consultant" datetime="2012-09-24T06:52:00" id="p3">
At least it's not the Taiwan parliament (they fight too). Surely it's about them getting "good pay and equal share".

<a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/newsvideo/7878861/Mass-brawl-in-Taiwans-parliament.html">http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/newsvideo/7878861/Mass-brawl-in-Taiwans-parliament.html</a>
</post>
<post author="snberk103" datetime="2012-09-26T08:26:00" id="p4">
In the article quoted, there is no mention that the riot was caused by workers wanting more pay. For all we know it may have been rival gangs, or the settling of old disputes between ethnic minorities, or about some bullies pushing in line at the cafeteria.
</post>
<post author="TedM" datetime="2012-09-26T09:44:00" id="p5">
hopefully we don't have a similar issue as last time. If people start to protest apple cause of this. :/ Sad day.
</post>
</doc>
