<doc id="ENG_DF_001471_20160330_G00A0G78U">
<headline>
Hidden Video Catches Hillary on Emails - She Knew It All Along
</headline>
<post author="thewap" datetime="2016-03-30T09:50:00" id="p1">
This clip from ABC News reporting on its 20/20 investigation brings new light to the Hillary Clinton email scandal. She is caught speaking about emails and not wanting to use govt emails due to wanting to keep from having them come up in investigations later. She is exposed. No wonder she wanted to hide her server. No wonder she deleted all her emails. The video also shows how Clinton's claim that she barely knew Peter Paul was false, and how she under reported contributions by him by millions.
</post>
<post author="haxrnick" datetime="2016-03-30T10:34:00" id="p2">
And the left's response:

<img src="proxy.php?image=http%3A%2F%2Fs2.quickmeme.com%2Fimg%2F4f%2F4f4b7b8cce3a920b9263179cb28d7c822cdfaa49e6bcaa2fe215a34a2fc727c8.jpg&amp;hash=545222d2baf99ea28db59f6bd739942e" alt="[ IMG]"/>
</post>
<post author="steve knight" datetime="2016-03-30T10:35:00" id="p3">
and the right is foaming at the mouth.
</post>
<post author="VulchR" datetime="2016-03-30T10:41:00" id="p4">
Fine. Let us elect Bernie then.
</post>
<post author="Renzatic" datetime="2016-03-30T10:42:00" id="p5">
So I see we're all trusting the MSM today.
</post>
<post author="VulchR" datetime="2016-03-30T10:47:00" id="p6">
Actually having watched the video, I am not sure she's admitting much. Management at my institution often will not use e-mail because it leaves a paper trial. You just know when you're getting a phone call that it's going to be a crap day. However, using alternatives to e-mail is not a crime. I am sure most of the people in Congress and running for President have done exactly the same thing.
</post>
<post author="Robisan" datetime="2016-03-30T11:00:00" id="p7">
<quote>
"She knew it all along"?
</quote>

What is "it"? The video is from before the 2008 election, before she ever knew she was going to be Secretary of State. Honestly, do you ever tire of spewing argle-bargle?
</post>
<post author="A.Goldberg" datetime="2016-03-30T11:20:00" id="p8">
Yes, as much as I distrust Hillary, I'm not sure this proves anything. It's pretty much common knowledge not to write an email of something you don't want there to be a record of.

It also suggests nothing of government email specifically. In the broad context of investigations, her personal email can be used in investigations - just as it is now. Even without a warrant to investigate her server, if someone recieved an incriminating email from her and submitted as evidence, then you still have evidence of a paper trail.
</post>
<post author="Jess13" datetime="2016-03-30T23:37:00" id="p9">
Although it was long before she became Secretary of State, it shows that back then she was concerned with hiding incriminating information from potential future investigations. Good find.
</post>
<post author="thekev" datetime="2016-03-30T23:43:00" id="p10">
Does this load for anyone else? I tried 3 different browsers, and this page doesn't load anything. Links from google also seem to be dead.
</post>
<post author="Jess13" datetime="2016-03-30T23:52:00" id="p11">
<quote orig_author="thekev">
Does this load for anyone else? I tried 3 different browsers, and this page doesn't load anything. Links from google also seem to be dead.
</quote>

Yes, it’s just one YouTube:

ABCNews: Hidden Video Catches Hillary on Emails - She Knew It All Along
</post>
<post author="mudslag" datetime="2016-03-31T00:08:00" id="p12">
Welcome to 2007, when this story was done.
</post>
<post author="Eraserhead" datetime="2016-03-31T00:17:00" id="p13">
<quote orig_author="Jess13">
Although it was long before she became Secretary of State, it shows that back then she was concerned with hiding incriminating information from potential future investigations. Good find.
</quote>

Oh for Christ sakes this "point" has been obvious to me since I left university. And it applies equally well to letters as to email.
</post>
<post author="Renzatic" datetime="2016-03-31T00:30:00" id="p14">
<quote orig_author="Eraserhead">
Oh for Christ sakes this "point" has been obvious to me since I left university. And it applies equally well to letters as to email.
</quote>

What does this video even prove? That even before she was secretary of state, she wanted to be sloppy handling classified documents?
</post>
<post author="thekev" datetime="2016-03-31T00:33:00" id="p15">
<quote orig_author="Jess13">
Yes, it’s just one YouTube:

ABCNews: Hidden Video Catches Hillary on Emails - She Knew It All Along
</quote>

Thanks. Safari is being weird for some reason (went back to because chrome takes too much ram and firefox has been acting weird). Searching that headline in youtube worked in chrome. It isn't that shocking though. I expected something a bit more revealing rather than a somewhat generic comment.
</post>
<post author="Jess13" datetime="2016-03-31T00:42:00" id="p16">
<quote orig_author="thekev">
Thanks. Safari is being weird for some reason (went back to because chrome takes too much ram and firefox has been acting weird). Searching that headline in youtube worked in chrome. It isn't that shocking though. I expected something a bit more revealing rather than a somewhat generic comment.
</quote>

Yeah, no blockbuster revelation. But still, doesn’t put Hillary in a good light, considering she is now pretending she wasn’t trying to hide anything by using private email/server as SoS. This just negates her lies that she hadn’t used private email/server to hide anything incriminating. Pattern.
</post>
</doc>
