<doc id="ENG_DF_001471_20121217_G00A02LVB">
<headline>
White Dudes Keep Mass Murdering People
</headline>
<post author="SomeDudeAsking" datetime="2012-12-17T22:09:00" id="p1">
Have You Noticed That White Dudes Keep Mass Murdering People?

<quote>
When anyone who isn't a white and relatively well-off man strides into a public place and guns down innocent civilians, we attack his race and/or religious beliefs before we bury his victims in the ground. But when yet another privileged white guy storms into a school or movie theater and kills dozens of people, we assume there's something wrong with his brain instead of wondering whether his murderous rage has anything to do with good ol' American macho entitlement. Are we ready to talk about it yet? Let's.

This is hardly the first time we've questioned what makes white middle-class dudes more prone to shooting up public spaces; last summer, after the Aurora movie theater massacre, Hugo Schwyzer wrote that "the fact that these white male mass murderers felt so confident choosing public spaces to commit their crimes reflects a powerful truth about the culture in which they were raised."

......

When Seung-Hui Cho killed 32 people at Virginia Tech, pundits instantly declared that his Korean upbringing had something to do with it. When Maj. Nidal Hasan went on a shooting rampage at Fort Hood shootings, we heard more about his Muslim faith than anything else. Yet, when David Sirota suggested on the Sunday morning edition of "Up" with Chris Hayes that the same conservative politicians and commentators who support racial profiling when black people or Muslims are the ones being profiled would rather sacrifice a few of their semi-automatic weapons than think critically about white men, the right-wing media freaked the **** out.
</quote>

I find it sadly hilarious that when this latest white dude shot all those people, the American headlines didn't mention terrorist at all. If this dude was Muslim/black/asian, you would have heard that we need to bomb yet another country because of our racial prejudice and the need to get rid of all non-White "terrorists".
<a href="http://jezebel.com/5969023/have-you-noticed-that-white-dudes-keep-mass-murdering-people">http://jezebel.com/5969023/have-you-noticed-that-white-dudes-keep-mass-murdering-people</a>
</post>
<post author="Caliber26" datetime="2012-12-18T00:05:00" id="p2">
I think some of these guys are Manchurian Candidates being used by our good ole government to help push its gun control agenda. It's more effective when they create the problem, which in turn prompts us to demand the "solution". Reverse psychology on a large scale. -- Or as the saying goes: Order out of Chaos

Anyone who thinks this is far-fetched thinking, seriously needs to open up a history book.
</post>
<post author="JohnnyComeLatly" datetime="2012-12-18T01:48:00" id="p3">
Gotta agree. The dust hasn't even settled and Obama is already talking gun control.

Keep in mind a few things in play: Go to Africa and you'll find non-white dudes killing thousands. Secondly, you have to recognize there is a different reference point between society's view of those who are "dominant," and those who aren't. Long under attack, the "White guy," is considered still the race/sex that has every thing easy. You can't really say it was his "culture." However, it plays better if it's the underdog who's trying to fight the power and this was their, "last stand."

I'm in Asia and the last headline I saw was, "He was a Hard Core Call of Duty player," and I just thought, "What a crock of ****." I have thousands of hours into Call of Duty, Black Ops, Rainbox 6, Saints Row, GTA, etc, and I would never have the urges this guy acted upon.
</post>
<post author="Shrink" datetime="2012-12-18T03:39:00" id="p4">
<quote orig_author="Caliber26">
I think some of these guys are Manchurian Candidates being used by our good ole government to help push its gun control agenda. It's more effective when they create the problem, which in turn prompts us to demand the "solution". Reverse psychology on a large scale. -- Or as the saying goes: Order out of Chaos

Anyone who thinks this is far-fetched thinking, seriously needs to open up a history book.
</quote>

Right...
Attached Files:
<a href="attachments/tin-foil-hat-png.384345/">Tin Foil Hat.png</a> File size: 146.1 KB Views: 190
</post>
<post author="rdowns" datetime="2012-12-18T03:49:00" id="p5">
<quote orig_author="Caliber26">
I think some of these guys are Manchurian Candidates being used by our good ole government to help push its gun control agenda. It's more effective when they create the problem, which in turn prompts us to demand the "solution". Reverse psychology on a large scale. -- Or as the saying goes: Order out of Chaos

Anyone who thinks this is far-fetched thinking, seriously needs to open up a history book.
</quote>

Seriously? Even Mark Sanchez doesn't miss this badly.
</post>
</doc>
