<doc id="ENG_DF_001503_20140429_G00A0GJRI">
<headline>
Cost of Living Budget for the Algarve
</headline>
<post author="allylulu" datetime="2014-04-29T08:24:00" id="p1">
My first post, looking forward to some interaction...

My wife and i have just bought a property on the central algarve as a holiday home and planned retirement home. We have spent the last 14 years in Dubai and decided its time to start the retirement planning and the algarve won hands down.

We have already been over earlier this month for 2 weeks and ordered the furniture etc and generally found everything (except petrol!) cheaper than Dubai, so my 2 questions for the forum are:

1. How much should we budget to spend per month for when we retire to the algarve? For a reasonably decent existence and lifestyle?

2. We can ship our cars to Portugal relatively cheaply, but i hear its extremely expensive to import them into portugal? any ideas

Many thanks
</post>
<post author="gedscottish" datetime="2014-04-29T08:37:00" id="p2">
See this thread:
<a href="http://britishexpats.com/forum/portugal-89/could-i-live-1000-euros-month-796058/?highlight=cost+of+living">Could I live on 1000 euros a month</a>

Cars coming from Dubai could be complicated, you "may" be able to import them and avoid the "imposto automovel" tax(can be done with cars that came within EU and Switzerland)
Certicate of conformity could also be a problem. I would forget it to be honest and buy here.
</post>
<post author="allylulu" datetime="2014-04-29T08:48:00" id="p3">
<quote orig_author="gedscottish">
See this thread:
<a href="http://britishexpats.com/forum/portugal-89/could-i-live-1000-euros-month-796058/?highlight=cost+of+living">Could I live on 1000 euros a month</a>

Cars coming from Dubai could be complicated, you "may" be able to import them and avoid the "imposto automovel" tax(can be done with cars that came within EU and Switzerland)
Certicate of conformity could also be a problem. I would forget it to be honest and buy here.
</quote>
Thats what i thought, thanks very much for the quick reply
</post>
<post author="newintavira" datetime="2014-04-29T10:37:00" id="p4">
I wrote a big article about this, I hope the admins won't mind me posting it as I think it will help you. I just scanned through it and it's all still valid, but I would say our gas and water costs have crept up in the last year (water is now hitting €50 / month and it's not like we're using more).

<a href="http://www.movingtoportugal.org/2012/05/portugal-cost-of-living-update/">http://www.movingtoportugal.org/2012...living-update/</a>

PS. I agree with Ged about the cars - just buy here and avoid the heartache!
</post>
<post author="allylulu" datetime="2014-04-29T15:58:00" id="p5">
<quote orig_author="gedscottish">
See this thread:
<a href="http://britishexpats.com/forum/portugal-89/could-i-live-1000-euros-month-796058/?highlight=cost+of+living">Could I live on 1000 euros a month</a>

Cars coming from Dubai could be complicated, you "may" be able to import them and avoid the "imposto automovel" tax(can be done with cars that came within EU and Switzerland)
Certicate of conformity could also be a problem. I would forget it to be honest and buy here.
</quote>

Thats brilliant thanks, and i have just ordered your book from Amazon :-)

<quote orig_author="newintavira">
I wrote a big article about this, I hope the admins won't mind me posting it as I think it will help you. I just scanned through it and it's all still valid, but I would say our gas and water costs have crept up in the last year (water is now hitting €50 / month and it's not like we're using more).

<a href="http://www.movingtoportugal.org/2012/05/portugal-cost-of-living-update/">http://www.movingtoportugal.org/2012...living-update/</a>

PS. I agree with Ged about the cars - just buy here and avoid the heartache!
</quote>
That's very useful much appreciated
</post>
<post author="heading2PT" datetime="2014-05-01T07:29:00" id="p6">
Hi allylulu,

Just thought I drop a note here because you two appear to be in a similar situation as my wife and I. We have lived in DXB for the past ten years and have decided 'enough is enough' and plan to retire to Portugal – target May 2015, although we are heading to the Silver Coast.

As for cost of living you may find this site useful.

<a href="http://www.numbeo.com/cost-of-living/">http://www.numbeo.com/cost-of-living/</a>

Not sure if you have explored the tax benefits of applying for the Non Habitual Resident scheme, maybe worth getting in contact with a good tax advisor over there. We used PWC.

Initially we were apprehensive about taking our car across, but after finding out that the same model we have here will cost a staggering 15K Euros more in Portugal, we did some further research and made some inquiries. The result is there are companies and people who will handle all of the paperwork for your, for a price, (but not 15K Euros). Non-European cars will not have a Certificate of Conformity, but you can get the car certified by companies like: T.D.S. - Engenharia e Gestão Automóvel, Lda. There are many examples of people importing cars from Canada and US, which do not have CoC.

Anyhow, I thought it would be worth sharing experiences with you. Good luck.
</post>
</doc>
