<doc id="ENG_DF_001471_20160107_G00A02XWT">
<headline>
Law-Abiding Gun Owners Pose ‘Risk’
</headline>
<post author="rdowns" datetime="2016-01-07T08:16:00" id="p1">
Before you get your panties all tied up in your holsters, this is a statement from a pro-gun, conservative Republican member of Congress with a 93% NRA rating.

<quote>
Man, they’re makin’ them Republican congressmen liberaler and liberaler in Alabama, son!

President Obama ‘s <a href="http://www.mediaite.com/tv/president-obama-announces-gun-control-executive-actions/">just-announced executive actions</a> on gun regulation have had the predictable effect of boosting the sale of popular gun talking points, one of which got a little banged up Wednesday night by All In with Chris Hayes host Chris Hayes. At the conclusion of an interview with Rep. Mo Brooks (R-AL), Hayes decided to put the tandem “gun-free zones” and “good guy with a gun” talking points to the test by asking Brooks if he would support allowing law-abiding gun owners to carry firearms in the U.S. Capitol complex.

Brooks first tried to parry with a “property rights” argument, but then admitted that he would not support it because:
</quote>

Video and more at link below

<a href="http://www.mediaite.com/tv/republican-congressman-tells-chris-hayes-law-abiding-gun-owners-pose-risk/">http://www.mediaite.com/tv/republic...chris-hayes-law-abiding-gun-owners-pose-risk/</a>
</post>
<post author="AlliFlowers" datetime="2016-01-07T08:31:00" id="p2">
The fact that they talked to Mo Brooks suggests they have no sense to start with.
</post>
<post author="nbs2" datetime="2016-01-07T09:32:00" id="p3">
This is one of the few things I give Texas a lot of credit for. I hate living here and (but for the friends I've made, who are also transplants) would to leave. But, business is business - which is another thing they do well, but not the point here.

Back to the matter at hand, going to the Capitol the first time and seeing the CC line, and that they don't hold themselves as for me and not for thee, I was impressed. I would have expected a Brooks-like attitude from more politicians, but I guess those are the folks that are wily enough to get to DC.
</post>
<post author="Huntn" datetime="2016-01-07T09:42:00" id="p4">
<a href="http://www.mediaite.com/tv/republican-congressman-tells-chris-hayes-law-abiding-gun-owners-pose-risk/">Law-Abiding Gun Owners Pose ‘Risk’</a> They are law-abiding until the point when they let their emotions get the better of them and lose perspective. It's not that unusual. Even the GOP balks at letting armed citizens into the Capitol.
</post>
</doc>
