<doc id="ENG_DF_001471_20160105_G00A0G3W2">
<headline>
North Korea Claims Successful Hydrogen Bomb Test
</headline>
<post author="Traverse" datetime="2016-01-05T20:38:00" id="p1">
According to The Guardian, unnatural earthquakes where detected near a known nuclear testing site in North Korea and North Korean leaders claim that it was a successful detonation of a miniaturized nuclear bomb.

<quote>
North Korea claims it has successfully detonated a miniaturised hydrogen bomb. The test took place on Wednesday at 10am local time (1.30am GMT/Wednesday 12.30pm AEDT/Tuesday 6.30pm ET) at a known nuclear test site at Punggye-ri. An announcement on state television claimed the test “worked perfectly” and was “self-defence against the US having numerous and humongous nuclear weapons”. If true, this would be North Korea’s fourth nuclear test, and its first using a hydrogen bomb, significantly more powerful than an atomic bomb. There has been no independent verification of North Korea’s claims. An artificial earthquake of magnitude 5.1 was detected close to Punggye-ri. Japan has condemned news of the test, labelling it a threat to Japan’s security.
</quote>

There's no evidence of this being genuine outside of North Korea's claims. I'm skeptical, but it's best to proceed with caution. Was curious about the thoughts here.

Update: A organization of the UN that monitors for nuclear activity stated that it detected an "unusual" even as well.

<quote>
The UN organisation monitoring the world for signs of nuclear testing confirms it has detected “an unusual event in the Korean peninsula”.

The head of the Comprehensive Test Ban Treaty Organisation, Lassina Zerbo, said:

Our international monitoring system detected an unusual seismic event in the Korean peninsula at latitude 41.27 longitude 129.10.

The location on the map places the epicenter at North Korea’s Pyunggye-ri testing site in its north-eastern mountains, where all of its nuclear tests have been conducted.
</quote>

Link: <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2016/jan/06/north-korea-major-announcement-artificial-earthquake-nuclear-test-site-live">http://www.theguardian.com/world/li...-artificial-earthquake-nuclear-test-site-live</a>
</post>
<post author="sim667" datetime="2016-01-06T01:59:00" id="p2">
Its alright though, because Americans can own guns, and nothing bad can happen when you have guns.
</post>
<post author="rdowns" datetime="2016-01-06T02:22:00" id="p3">
Yeah, North Korea has a hydrogen bomb. I also get as hard as I did when I was 20.
</post>
<post author="fitshaced" datetime="2016-01-06T03:16:00" id="p4">
On a side note, I guess fish can't really get embarrassed when they fart as its obvious when they do and they would just do it in front of each other like its normal behaviour. We need tolerance like that up here on concrete.
</post>
<post author="vrDrew" datetime="2016-01-06T03:47:00" id="p5">
<quote orig_author="Traverse">
There's no evidence of this being genuine outside of North Korea's claims. I'm skeptical, but it's best to proceed with caution. Was curious about the thoughts here
</quote>

I imagine our nation's intelligence and photoreconnaissance agencies will be in for some long hours in the days ahead trying to establish what, exactly, went on in North Korea.

The "good" things about nuclear testing is that with modern technology, its possible for our analysts and scientists to gain a pretty clear idea of exactly what sort of weapon was tested, even though they cannot gain access to the site itself. Airborne sensors will take air samples looking for particular isotopes, and specifically the mix of such isotopes, to look for clues as to the process. Other scientists will look at the seismological data to determine how the explosion (if any) took place; and to gain a better idea of the potential explosive yield of any such device.

My guess is that North Korea detonated some form a a fission weapon that was successfully "boosted" with the addition of Tritium. Such "boosted" weapons, while terrifying and powerful; are a long way from the almost unlimited power and complexity of a full fusion weapon. It seems unlikely that North Korea would be able to engineer a full fusion weapon without first conducting a far more comprehensive test program than they have previously.
</post>
<post author="Traverse" datetime="2016-01-06T06:31:00" id="p6">
<quote orig_author="vrDrew">
My guess is that North Korea detonated some form a a fission weapon that was successfully "boosted" with the addition of Tritium. Such "boosted" weapons, while terrifying and powerful; are a long way from the almost unlimited power and complexity of a full fusion weapon. It seems unlikely that North Korea would be able to engineer a full fusion weapon without first conducting a far more comprehensive test program than they have previously.
</quote>

Though nothing is confirmed, most seem to believe it was a nuclear weapon, but not a hydrogen bomb.
</post>
<post author="sim667" datetime="2016-01-06T06:46:00" id="p7">
I've also seen suggestions that there was a natural earthquake and DPRK are pretending to have let off a bomb.
</post>
<post author="aaronvan" datetime="2016-01-06T06:47:00" id="p8">
H-Bomb, my eye.

Boosted fission device at best. With no delivery vehicle.

Color me unimpressed.
</post>
</doc>
