<doc id="ENG_DF_001471_20081229_G00A0FHRN">
<headline>
Apples brand will carry it through any future leadership ch...
</headline>
<post author="MacBytes" datetime="2008-12-29T07:51:00" id="p1">
Category: Opinion/Interviews
Link: <a href="http://www.macbytes.com/link.php?sid=20081229105106">Apples brand will carry it through any future leadership changes</a>
Description: : Some people are concerned that when CEO Steve Jobs leaves Apple, the company is doomed. Certainly, theres no CEO more associated with a company than Jobs with Apple, but unless the other members of the management team go totally nuts, the Apple brand will remain strong.

Posted on <a href="http://www.macbytes.com">MacBytes.com</a>
Approved by Mudbug
</post>
<post author="rubberduck007" datetime="2008-12-29T09:19:00" id="p2">
Interesting....
</post>
<post author="Fuchal" datetime="2008-12-29T09:26:00" id="p3">
We'll see about that. It didn't work out so well last time...
</post>
<post author="mklos" datetime="2008-12-29T09:53:00" id="p4">
<quote orig_author="Fuchal">
We'll see about that. It didn't work out so well last time...
</quote>

But last time Apple didn't have the expertise in place like it does now. Steve has a Apple going in a great direction and as long as they stay on track they'll be successful for years to come. All it has to do is keep doing what its doing, which innovating some of the best products on the market and stay ahead of the game. I guess it sounds easy to say, but thats what they're currently doing. We don't necessarily need Steve Jobs to do that. There are plenty of very talented people at Apple to keep this going. Again, this wasn't necessarily the case from the mid-80's to the mid 90's where they executed great on all of the wrong things. They just had bad leadership.
</post>
<post author="IJ Reilly" datetime="2008-12-29T10:20:00" id="p5">
Apple did have poor leadership during the '80s and '90s, but one of those poor leaders was Steve Jobs. Even Jobs recognized his limitations, which is why he hired John Scully. The fact that he was able to return to Apple after 12 years as such a completely transformed corporate leader is one of the greatest stories in business. But it's incorrect to believe that Apple went downhill because he left in 1985. If Jobs had remained in charge of Apple at that time, he might well have run the company into the ground.
</post>
<post author="kastenbrust" datetime="2008-12-29T10:22:00" id="p6">
Brands are based around leaders, I could reel off thousands of companies who have had a very strong brand, had a leadership change, and then gone through the floor and sometimes even closed. If this wasn't true, then the share price of Apple wouldn't have plummeted on the news of Steve's ill health. I really hope the team that successes the current board doesn't mess things up because Apple's in a good place at the moment, with $20Billion in the bank, im sure only a few oil companies and maybe Microsoft have those kind of free resources.
</post>
<post author="IJ Reilly" datetime="2008-12-29T10:27:00" id="p7">
Apple now has more free cash than Microsoft ($25 billion), but mainly because Microsoft is now paying a dividend to stockholders.

I don't think brands are based around leaders, they are based around companies and products. Even in its darkest days, the Apple brand was one of the most recognized in the world.
</post>
<post author="mklos" datetime="2008-12-29T15:02:00" id="p8">
<quote orig_author="kastenbrust">
Brands are based around leaders, I could reel off thousands of companies who have had a very strong brand, had a leadership change, and then gone through the floor and sometimes even closed. If this wasn't true, then the share price of Apple wouldn't have plummeted on the news of Steve's ill health. I really hope the team that successes the current board doesn't mess things up because Apple's in a good place at the moment, with $20Billion in the bank, im sure only a few oil companies and maybe Microsoft have those kind of free resources.
</quote>

I don't hardly think that brands are based around leaders. Thats totally untrue. Sure, Steve Jobs is known to a lot of tech people, but the general everyday consumer? No so much. Try going into an Apple Store and asking a first time non-technical person who Steve Jobs is. You will most likely get a lot of "I don't know" answers. People don't buy Apple products just because of Steve Jobs. If he left, people will still buy Apple products if they're good products like they are now. I could personally care less who is in charge of Apple. As long as they're making kickass products, I'm buying them.

Brands like Coca-Cola, Nike, Disney are all extremely popular brands around the world with a very loyal following just like Apple has. But those people don't follow Disney for example because of their leader. They follow because of the products (or services) that company produces/serves.
</post>
</doc>
