<doc id="ENG_DF_001503_20140604_G00A0AIFJ">
<headline>
BE invading my dreams.
</headline>
<post author="SchnookoLoly" datetime="2014-06-04T12:23:00" id="p1">
Thought I'd share a dream I had Monday night...

Husband and I were staying with friends in France (?). Husband got up in the morning before me, as usual, then came into the bedroom holding his phone to his ear and says "Have I done anything in the past year that would cause me to have a police record?"

"Uh... no...?"

Then he walked out of the room telling off whoever was on the phone. So I started to get up, and the woman who owned the house we were staying in comes in with all these forms, which I recognised as a bunch of IMM forms for immigration. She then says "So we don't have Husband's police check."

"Uh, yes you do, it came back 'no trace', we applied back in 2012, and everything was fine. You've already issued him PR."

"No, it doesn't work that way. We need a new police certificate."

"What? No, you already gave him PR. He has his card and everything. He's picked up everything and is living and working in Canada."

"That doesn't matter, he needs a police check, or he'll have his PR revoked."

This exchange went back and forth for awhile with me arguing immigration rules with her, and then:

Her: "Let's start over, I don't even know your name. My name is Erica."

Me: "Wait, you don't even know who I am and you're telling me that you're going to revoke my husband's immigration status?"

"Only if that woman doesn't win the election. If she loses then all immigrants will have to leave the country."

"... Election? You mean if Kathleen Wynne doesn't win then Husband has to leave?"

"Yes."

And then I woke up.

[For those not in Ontario, there's a provincial election next week, quite hotly contested at the moment. Not sure who will win it. Wynne is the current leader who is fighting to remain in power.]

So yeah, that was my twisted and very strange dream about immigration.
</post>
<post author="ann m" datetime="2014-06-04T12:38:00" id="p2">
It was only a matter of time.

First, Moderator.

Next, lunacy. <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/biggrin.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="MrFloyd" datetime="2014-06-04T12:46:00" id="p3">
Haha! Brilliant!

Love that you managed to stay logical even in dream land <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/lol.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="christmasoompa" datetime="2014-06-04T12:52:00" id="p4">
<quote orig_author="ann m">
First, Moderator.

Next, lunacy. <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/biggrin.gif"/>
</quote>
Other way around. You only get asked to be a Moderator or Concierge if you are in the full throes of lunacy. Otherwise Sue knows there's no way you'd say yes. <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/biggrin.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="SchnookoLoly" datetime="2014-06-04T12:55:00" id="p5">
<quote orig_author="MrFloyd">
Haha! Brilliant!

Love that you managed to stay logical even in dream land <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/lol.gif"/>
</quote>

Haha pretty much! When I told my husband about this dream, he just went "...You spend way too much time on BE." And walked away. Hahahaha.

<quote orig_author="ann m">
It was only a matter of time.

First, Moderator.

Next, lunacy. <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/biggrin.gif"/>
</quote>

<quote orig_author="christmasoompa">
Other way around. You only get asked to be a Moderator or Concierge if you are in the full throes of lunacy. Otherwise Sue knows there's no way you'd say yes. <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/biggrin.gif"/>
</quote>
So as a super mod, that makes you.... ready to be committed? :P Something about 'fool me once'...?? <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/rofl.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="christmasoompa" datetime="2014-06-04T12:59:00" id="p6">
<quote orig_author="SchnookoLoly">
So as a super mod, that makes you.... ready to be committed? :P Something about 'fool me once'...?? <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/rofl.gif"/>
</quote>
I've no idea, but just as soon as these lovely men in white coats let me out of my padded cell, I'm sure I'll figure it out.
</post>
<post author="BristolUK" datetime="2014-06-04T15:30:00" id="p7">
@SchnookoLoly

Ha.

I thought that was going to be a "bureaucracy" dream until you got to the election part and I was going to ask if you had been a civil servant.

It reminded me of a recurring dream I used to have where someone in the education dept discovered I left school too early and even though I was an adult and been employed for many years - the last time I had this dream I was about 40 - I had to return to school to complete the last few months. Having been a 30 year civil servant I put it down to bureaucratic nonsense.

So I thought you were going on similar lines because of something missed. Except in CIC's case it may well be the sort of thing they'd do, if my past experience with them is anything to go by. <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/redface.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Pollyana" datetime="2014-06-04T16:28:00" id="p8">
<quote orig_author="christmasoompa">
I've no idea, but just as soon as these lovely men in white coats let me out of my padded cell, I'm sure I'll figure it out.
</quote>
I once dreamt I had banned Sue, when I woke up I was out of bed with the speed of light to check it had been only a dream <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/scaredhair.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="SchnookoLoly" datetime="2014-06-04T17:26:00" id="p9">
:O oh dear! Run! RUN!
</post>
</doc>
