<doc id="ENG_DF_001471_20130521_G00A0FN99">
<headline>
Moore Oklahoma Tornado 20May2013
</headline>
<post author="Huntn" datetime="2013-05-21T08:06:00" id="p1">
I imagine most of you have seen the images. Tornadoes seem to be the most dangerous weather events I know of and scare me the most. Hurricanes do more overall damage to a larger area, but nothing can match the intensity and focused damage of a twister. In 1999 the highest winds every recorded was associated with an F5 twister, 318 mph, in the same vicinity near Oklahoma City.

I wonder what happens to the population count after an event like this. I'm not talking of the deceased, but the number of people who say they've had enough and move away?
</post>
<post author="justperry" datetime="2013-05-21T08:10:00" id="p2">
Your video shows this:
Attached Files:
<a href="attachments/screen-shot-2013-05-21-at-22-07-37-png.413265/">Screen Shot 2013-05-21 at 22.07.37.png</a> File size: 3.1 KB Views: 313
</post>
<post author="GoCubsGo" datetime="2013-05-21T08:15:00" id="p3">
I'm not sure if there is a state you can move to where you won't experience something. It is terrible for sure and I think I fear tornados more than earthquakes. I spent 90% of my life in So. Cal. so perhaps that is just my ignorance of the unknown. The devastation in Moore is horrible. I did read at least a little news where they had the death toll at 91 and figured out they double counted some so the number when down to 24. ( <a href="http://www.usatoday.com/story/weather/2013/05/21/oklahoma-tornadoes/2344923/">source</a> )

For me, I would say that was enough and get the F out. Moving may not be that easy for some depending upon their job/family situation. I do wish the best for those affected as well as anyone ever affected by any natural disaster.
</post>
<post author="justperry" datetime="2013-05-21T08:23:00" id="p4">
I don't understand one thing here, this is already the 3th time this happens in the same area yet these houses are still built out of wood.
Not only there but in the whole Tornado ally, where I am from houses are built out of brick (solid) and double walls with insolation in between, so much stronger.

Sadly, as long as these houses are not built stronger we will see this happening again and again.
</post>
<post author="bradl" datetime="2013-05-21T08:28:00" id="p5">
<quote orig_author="jessica.">
I'm not sure if there is a state you can move to where you won't experience something. It is terrible for sure and I think I fear tornados more than earthquakes. I spent 90% of my life in So. Cal. so perhaps that is just my ignorance of the unknown. The devastation in Moore is horrible. I did read at least a little news where they had the death toll at 91 and figured out they double counted some so the number when down to 24. ( <a href="http://www.usatoday.com/story/weather/2013/05/21/oklahoma-tornadoes/2344923/">source</a> )
</quote>

The hard part for me: 7 of that 24 were children. <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=":("/>

As far as equating it to experiences you may know, picture a Ludlow earthquake on Saturday, followed by Northridge on Sunday, followed by Loma Prieta on Monday (The one that took out the Bay Bridge). All of those back to back to back within 72 hours. That's what happened here.

<quote>
For me, I would say that was enough and get the F out. Moving may not be that easy for some depending upon their job/family situation. I do wish the best for those affected as well as anyone ever affected by any natural disaster.
</quote>

this is a tough one for me, as all of my family were born/raised in Oklahoma. I wasn't, but lived in Tornado Alley all my life. For this to surprise and shock storm chasers says enough.

I'll post more thoughts after I get to work or the airport, depending on which may be needed (may be taking a flight to OKC to help with cleanup).

BL.
</post>
</doc>
