<doc id="ENG_DF_001503_20140113_G00A0GHPC">
<headline>
Ship car and furniture or start again !
</headline>
<post author="Murray family" datetime="2014-01-13T15:20:00" id="p1">
Hello,

Does anyone know if it is cheaper to ship your furniture and car over to Australia, or sell it all here in the uk and start again !! I've enquired about 20ft shipping containers and think there may be more costs to taking the car than originally throught. Any help would be much appreciated.

Kind regards,

Lisa <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/confused.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Buzzy--Bee" datetime="2014-01-13T17:30:00" id="p2">
<quote orig_author="Murray family">
Hello,

Does anyone know if it is cheaper to ship your furniture and car over to Australia, or sell it all here in the uk and start again !! I've enquired about 20ft shipping containers and think there may be more costs to taking the car than originally throught. Any help would be much appreciated.

Kind regards,

Lisa <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/confused.gif"/>
</quote>
Take everything except the car. Unless it's an unusual one such as a vintage Jag or something.

BB
</post>
<post author="Bermudashorts" datetime="2014-01-13T18:56:00" id="p3">
<quote orig_author="Buzzy--Bee">
Take everything except the car. Unless it's an unusual one such as a vintage Jag or something.

BB
</quote>
+1

You are not going to be able to furnish a house for the price of a container, not even close.
</post>
<post author="Alfresco" datetime="2014-01-13T19:14:00" id="p4">
+2

Ship it all over except the car. <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/smile.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="RedDragon2008" datetime="2014-01-14T08:50:00" id="p5">
<quote orig_author="Alfresco">
+2

Ship it all over except the car. <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/smile.gif"/>
</quote>
+3 Local furniture is pine not Oak <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/biggrin.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="tartankoala" datetime="2014-01-14T08:55:00" id="p6">
+4. You will be surprised at how much it will cost you to buy all your stuff again in Australia. We now wish we'd shipped more.

Not too sure about the car though.
</post>
<post author="Murray family" datetime="2014-01-14T09:14:00" id="p7">
Hi everyone,

Thank you for your comments. I have been looking on the internet at furniture and saw that you can get house packages from Super Amart. From what I have seen, if we go with the top range of furniture from there, we could furnish most of the house for the price of a container. But from your comments am I missing something <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/unsure.gif"/>

Lisa x.
</post>
<post author="Bermudashorts" datetime="2014-01-14T09:39:00" id="p8">
<quote orig_author="Murray family">
Hi everyone,

Thank you for your comments. I have been looking on the internet at furniture and saw that you can get house packages from Super Amart. From what I have seen, if we go with the top range of furniture from there, we could furnish most of the house for the price of a container. But from your comments am I missing something <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/unsure.gif"/>

Lisa x.
</quote>
Well you would get the most basic furniture, probably not all what you need, questionable quality (maybe I don't know), but in any case the bare bones of any household? No homely touches, soft furnishings? You generally cannot cramp all your personal effects into a suitcase, so you either leave behind or have to pay for some shipping anyway.

The voices of experience generally say to ship the lot, but if you think something else will work for you, then no reason you cannot buck the trend,
</post>
<post author="Murray family" datetime="2014-01-14T09:51:00" id="p9">
The internet tells me to buy new. The voices of experience tell me to ship the lot. The internet was winning last night. The voices are winning today aaarrgggg ha ha. Got a couple of weeks to decide, will let you know.

Thanks x.
</post>
<post author="Red_V_Roger" datetime="2014-01-14T09:53:00" id="p10">
There's also the fact that when you are settling in to a new country and finding somethings unexpectedly hard, its nice to have your own stuff from 'home' with you.
</post>
<post author="Alfresco" datetime="2014-01-14T10:05:00" id="p11">
<quote orig_author="Murray family">
The internet tells me to buy new. The voices of experience tell me to ship the lot. The internet was winning last night. The voices are winning today aaarrgggg ha ha. Got a couple of weeks to decide, will let you know.

Thanks x.
</quote>

Well, the reality is that it will take a fair amount of time for the container to arrive and in that time you will buy stuff unless in a holiday place with everything. We squatted for about two months with bare minimum until it arrived. It felt like Christmas.

<quote orig_author="Red_V_Roger">
There's also the fact that when you are settling in to a new country and finding somethings unexpectedly hard, its nice to have your own stuff from 'home' with you.
</quote>
Agreed. <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/sunglasses.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Buzzy--Bee" datetime="2014-01-14T10:54:00" id="p12">
<quote orig_author="Murray family">
Hi everyone,

Thank you for your comments. I have been looking on the internet at furniture and saw that you can get house packages from Super Amart.
</quote>
The quality of furniture from Super Amart means you will be buying new all over again a year or two after you arrive.

BB
</post>
</doc>
