<doc id="ENG_DF_001503_20130921_G00A0GGAW">
<headline>
Westlands Nairobi, terrorist shooting
</headline>
<post author="al dente" datetime="2013-09-21T14:48:00" id="p1">
On my phone so don't know how to link but 20 dead so far. Shooters walked in and told the Muslims to leave and tried to kill the rest. In a family shopping centre. I know there are a few Kenyanphiles here. My dad has a place in Muthaiga.
</post>
<post author="mentalist" datetime="2013-09-22T04:58:00" id="p2">
We spent yesterday evening glued to the overseas news on TV and internet. The Westgate Mall is a place we know very well. Terrible news. I suspect there will be local retribution on the streets of Nairobi.
<a href="http://www.anglohili.com/blog/?p=6658">http://www.anglohili.com/blog/?p=6658</a>
</post>
<post author="Blue Cat" datetime="2013-09-22T06:21:00" id="p3">
I have a Kenyan friend who lives in Nairobi, thankfully he and his family weren't out shopping. What is wrong with these people?
</post>
<post author="Boomhauer" datetime="2013-09-22T06:22:00" id="p4">
<quote orig_author="Blue Cat">
I have a Kenyan friend who lives in Nairobi, thankfully he and his family weren't out shopping. What is wrong with these people?
</quote>
Religion of Peace...
</post>
<post author="Blue Cat" datetime="2013-09-22T06:24:00" id="p5">
<quote orig_author="Boomhauer">
Religion of Peace...
</quote>
as we have discussed before not all muslims are terrorists and not all terrorists are muslims
</post>
<post author="Boomhauer" datetime="2013-09-22T06:34:00" id="p6">
<quote orig_author="Blue Cat">
as we have discussed before not all muslims are terrorists and not all terrorists are muslims
</quote>
I don't proscribe Muslims per see, it's the religion that I strongly dislike due to its ethnosupremacist and conquering mindset.
</post>
<post author="Scamp" datetime="2013-09-22T07:00:00" id="p7">
Terrible news story to see.

Lots of stories of people being stuck, hidden in the mall, must be terrifying.

Fingers crossed no more people die and those responsible are punished.
</post>
<post author="Blue Cat" datetime="2013-09-22T07:21:00" id="p8">
<quote orig_author="Boomhauer">
I don't proscribe Muslims per see, it's the religion that I strongly dislike due to its ethnosupremacist and conquering mindset.
</quote>
great word <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/wink.gif"/> but it's not all muslims that have that attitude.
</post>
<post author="Beaverstate" datetime="2013-09-22T07:35:00" id="p9">
<quote orig_author="Scamp">
Terrible news story to see.

Lots of stories of people being stuck, hidden in the mall, must be terrifying.

Fingers crossed no more people die and those responsible are punished.
</quote>
Agreed. Problem is that the punished become martyrs, at least potentially.
</post>
<post author="Scamp" datetime="2013-09-22T07:40:00" id="p10">
<quote orig_author="Beaverstate">
Agreed. Problem is that the punished become martyrs, at least potentially.
</quote>
Indeed. Unfortunately this is the world we live in.
</post>
<post author="al dente" datetime="2013-09-22T08:00:00" id="p11">
Have there been any condemnation statements from Muslim leaders on the World stage? I don't mean by Kingston's local Iman who will be petrified that his mosque will be torched, but by muslim governments? I hope so.
</post>
<post author="Randy Bender" datetime="2013-09-22T09:07:00" id="p12">
Wherever there are Muslims, there's trouble. They spend most of their time killing each other, so they're not going to have much respect for other religions. Sure there are good muslims but they have a herd mentality programmed to never criticise their own and those in the Arab world especially are brainwashed from birth. It's not even a religion, it's a death cult.

Whenever I travel the local kids are usually very cute and inquisitive about strangers;when I go back to the Middle East they chuck stones and shout "f#*# you".
</post>
<post author="mikewot" datetime="2013-09-22T09:11:00" id="p13">
<quote orig_author="Randy Bender">
They spend most of their time killing each other,
</quote>
Wow! Really? I must have missed this piece of factual reporting on the 1.6 billion or about 23.4% of the world population which are Muslim.
</post>
<post author="Meow" datetime="2013-09-22T09:12:00" id="p14">
<quote orig_author="al dente">
Have there been any condemnation statements from Muslim leaders on the World stage? I don't mean by Kingston's local Iman who will be petrified that his mosque will be torched, but by muslim governments? I hope so.
</quote>
It seems that there is never enough of that. Insufficient condemnation may well be seen by the perpetrators as endorsement, so the powerful Muslim nations (yes, KSA, I'm looking at you) ought to be vociferous in the damning and distancing from such awful acts.
</post>
<post author="Scamp" datetime="2013-09-22T09:20:00" id="p15">
<quote orig_author="Randy Bender">
Wherever there are Muslims, there's trouble. They spend most of their time killing each other, so they're not going to have much respect for other religions. Sure there are good muslims but they have a herd mentality programmed to never criticise their own and those in the Arab world especially are brainwashed from birth. It's not even a religion, it's a death cult.

Whenever I travel the local kids are usually very cute and inquisitive about strangers;when I go back to the Middle East they chuck stones and shout "f#*# you".
</quote>
Wow.

You're as ****ing stupid as these 'terrorists'.
</post>
<post author="nottmbantam" datetime="2013-09-22T09:35:00" id="p16">
FFS. The world has seen 37 people shot dead. Yet, some people are more focused on 'I told you so'. Get a f&amp;@king grip.

Sympathies and thoughts go out to the families. My own family used to live in Westlands, thankfully they are all safe.
</post>
<post author="Cypselos" datetime="2013-09-22T09:49:00" id="p17">
<quote orig_author="Randy Bender">
Whenever I travel the local kids are usually very cute and inquisitive about strangers;when I go back to the Middle East they chuck stones and shout "f#*# you".
</quote>
Have you thought that maybe it's something personal?
</post>
</doc>
