<doc id="ENG_DF_001503_20140605_G00A0GKEU">
<headline>
Gunman on the loose - Moncton
</headline>
<post author="BristolUK" datetime="2014-06-05T03:05:00" id="p1">
It's all over the telly and the world's press.
</post>
<post author="Jsmth321" datetime="2014-06-05T03:08:00" id="p2">
Stay safe and doors and windows locked.

3 RCMP dead, 2 wounded.

<a href="http://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/new-brunswick/3-rcmp-officers-dead-2-wounded-in-moncton-shooting-1.2665359">http://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/new-br...ting-1.2665359</a>
</post>
<post author="Danny B" datetime="2014-06-05T03:18:00" id="p3">
<a href="https://twitter.com/RCMPNB/status/474359840807321600">https://twitter.com/RCMPNB/status/474359840807321600</a>
</post>
<post author="Alan2005" datetime="2014-06-05T03:40:00" id="p4">
<quote orig_author="BristolUK">
It's all over the telly and the world's press.
</quote>
Yeah. I did wonder if you'd gone wacko <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/eek.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="JamesM" datetime="2014-06-05T03:49:00" id="p5">
Serious stuff. Just watching the hospital interview now.

Hopefully they catch/ wack the shooter soon.
</post>
<post author="ann m" datetime="2014-06-05T04:57:00" id="p6">
He'll be willing to take out many more before they finally shoot him, or he blows his own brains out <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/sad.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Siouxie" datetime="2014-06-05T06:18:00" id="p7">
<a href="http://www.cbc.ca/player/News/TV%20Shows/The%20National/Canada/ID/2462234900/">http://www.cbc.ca/player/News/TV%20S...ID/2462234900/</a>

Dreadful.
</post>
<post author="caretaker" datetime="2014-06-05T10:45:00" id="p8">
<quote orig_author="ann m">
He'll be willing to take out many more before they finally shoot him, or he blows his own brains out <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/sad.gif"/>
</quote>
Depending on what his plan is (how far ahead he's thought it out) he may have slipped the cordon and got away, already commited suicide, or could be holed up in a prepared defensive position ready to do battle. At least now the sun's up the law should have airborne drones with cameras as well as IR imaging searching the forest. A witness said he has 2 assault rifles, a crossbow and a knife. I'm guessing when he is located police will assume he could have explosives as well and approach accordingly. His use of facebook revealing his identity indicates he isn't planning on getting away with it so I'm not holding my breath that he'll surrender.
</post>
<post author="MikeUK" datetime="2014-06-05T11:33:00" id="p9">
<quote orig_author="caretaker">
Depending on what his plan is (how far ahead he's thought it out) he may have slipped the cordon and got away,.
</quote>
my memory of the region is its covered with Pine forest, you could travel for miles and miles and not be seen..
</post>
<post author="magnumpi" datetime="2014-06-05T12:50:00" id="p10">
Still not found him. Moncton on lockdown I hear
</post>
<post author="withabix" datetime="2014-06-05T13:27:00" id="p11">
Remind me again, why do guns need to be so freely available ?
</post>
<post author="magnumpi" datetime="2014-06-05T13:32:00" id="p12">
Actually, it was said on the news that "if guns were? Freely available" he be dead now, shot by a bystander/witness to the cop killings
</post>
<post author="BristolUK" datetime="2014-06-05T14:12:00" id="p13">
<quote orig_author="magnumpi">
Still not found him. Moncton on lockdown I hear
</quote>
The area sealed off is only a few minutes away from where I am but the 'action' is some way off.

Schools closed, bus service suspended, Gov offices closed, mail delivery suspended for the day, hospital only taking visitors of critically ill relatives. Even stores have closed when they stay open despite official warnings to stay home for dangerous weather. Garbage trucks haven't been out.

But my newspaper got delivered!!
</post>
<post author="magnumpi" datetime="2014-06-05T14:19:00" id="p14">
The paper boy won't even see the news, he be wandering round with his iPod fones on
</post>
<post author="Alan2005" datetime="2014-06-05T14:27:00" id="p15">
Its's like the plot of Rambo. Do you think he's left any traps?
</post>
<post author="BristolUK" datetime="2014-06-05T14:47:00" id="p16">
<quote orig_author="Alan2005">
Its's like the plot of Rambo. Do you think he's left any traps?
</quote>
He must be very good. Usually, when a convenience store is robbed the villain is tracked down within a couple of hours.
Last month someone tried to rob a bank customer trying to make a deposit. A bystander relieved them of the money they had taken and they made a getaway by car.

They were caught within an hour.

All these resources and all the attention and he's still out there.
</post>
<post author="Nuckynoo" datetime="2014-06-05T15:50:00" id="p17">
Have the police caught the gun man yet ?
</post>
<post author="Siouxie" datetime="2014-06-05T15:56:00" id="p18">
<quote orig_author="Nuckynoo">
Have the police caught the gun man yet ?
</quote>
Not yet, though he's been spotted 3 times this morning by members of the public.
</post>
<post author="MarylandNed" datetime="2014-06-05T15:57:00" id="p19">
<quote orig_author="magnumpi">
Actually, it was said on the news that "if guns were? Freely available" he be dead now, shot by a bystander/witness to the cop killings
</quote>
That's the argument the NRA uses in the US. It's a load of crap. If guns weren't freely available, those cops wouldn't have been shot in the first place.
</post>
<post author="rivingtonpike" datetime="2014-06-05T16:03:00" id="p20">
Stay safe people.
</post>
<post author="magnumpi" datetime="2014-06-05T16:09:00" id="p21">
<quote orig_author="MarylandNed">
That's the argument the NRA uses in the US. It's a load of crap. If guns weren't freely available, those cops wouldn't have been shot in the first place.
</quote>
It's not my argument I was just saying.

And guns are here and so easily available, illegal licenced or whatever, nothing will stop a mentally ill loon from shooting people

We could however, stop making bullets?
</post>
</doc>
