<doc id="ENG_DF_001471_20050614_G00A0FCSK">
<headline>
Steve Jobs' Commencement Speech
</headline>
<post author="MacRumors" datetime="2005-06-14T17:19:00" id="p1">
<a href="http://news-service.stanford.edu/news/2005/june15/jobs-061505.html">Stanford has posted</a> the text of Steve Jobs' recent commencement speech from Stanford's 2005 graduation speech.

Jobs relates stories about his life, including his work at Apple as well as his public departure:

<quote>
I didn't see it then, but it turned out that getting fired from Apple was the best thing that could have ever happened to me. The heaviness of being successful was replaced by the lightness of being a beginner again, less sure about everything. It freed me to enter one of the most creative periods in my life.
</quote>

Jobs, of course, later returned to Apple when Apple purchased NeXT (also founded by Steve Jobs).
</post>
<post author="~Shard~" datetime="2005-06-14T17:21:00" id="p2">
Wow, I didn't realize Job was doing this - would have been a great speech to hear and experience. We didn't have anything like this for our graduation. <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=";)"/>
</post>
<post author="Mac_Freak" datetime="2005-06-14T17:28:00" id="p3">
Ok I will be good this time. It is nice to see Jobs beign so involved with higher eductaion. He sure made getting fired sound as not a bad thing.
</post>
<post author="DMann" datetime="2005-06-14T17:29:00" id="p4">
Think Different

Compared to GWs speech about being a 'C' student
and becoming President -- this somewhat outdoes
that Lame Yale address, and proves a drop out can
become a true leader who truly empowers
individuals and changes lives......
</post>
<post author="tech4all" datetime="2005-06-14T17:32:00" id="p5">
That part about the pancreas cancer and the doctor telling him he only had 3-6 months to live, then finding out it was actually a curable cancer was really something to read.
</post>
<post author="runninmac" datetime="2005-06-14T17:32:00" id="p6">
Wow Steve is amazing, I really wish I could have been there for it but then again i dont go to Stanford.
</post>
<post author="wwooden" datetime="2005-06-14T17:32:00" id="p7">
Just finished reading it. Next year is my senior year at college, man it would be sweet to have him come and talk at my school (I highly doubt it though, I go to the University of Vermont, I don't we quite have the same budget).
</post>
<post author="QFace" datetime="2005-06-14T17:42:00" id="p8">
Steve's partner went to UC, Berkeley...
As a cal student, this is blasphemy!
Steve, this is unforgivable!
</post>
<post author="SteveC" datetime="2005-06-14T17:49:00" id="p9">
Video clip:
<a href="http://news-service.stanford.edu/news/2005/june15/videos/51.html">http://news-service.stanford.edu/news/2005/june15/videos/51.html</a>
</post>
<post author="aquajet" datetime="2005-06-14T17:50:00" id="p10">
And Steve's return to Apple was the best thing that ever happened to the company.
</post>
<post author="Chaszmyr" datetime="2005-06-14T17:55:00" id="p11">
Very strange to stand up before a graduating class and say one of the best decisions he ever made was dropping out of college lol
</post>
<post author="Blue Moon" datetime="2005-06-14T18:02:00" id="p12">
<quote orig_author="SteveC">
Video clip:
<a href="http://news-service.stanford.edu/news/2005/june15/videos/51.html">http://news-service.stanford.edu/news/2005/june15/videos/51.html</a>
</quote>

Thank you for that. Watching it was all the more inspirational.
</post>
<post author="mgargan1" datetime="2005-06-14T18:03:00" id="p13">
I like this quote...

Remembering that you are going to die is the best way I know to avoid the trap of thinking you have something to lose.
</post>
<post author="dongmin" datetime="2005-06-14T18:04:00" id="p14">
<quote orig_author="QFace">
Steve's partner went to UC, Berkeley...
As a cal student, this is blasphemy!
Steve, this is unforgivable!
</quote>

don't be such a Weeny <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=";)"/>

you can always start using windows...
</post>
<post author="mcarnes" datetime="2005-06-14T18:08:00" id="p15">
Damn good speech Steve. Keep fighting the good fight.
</post>
<post author="mgargan1" datetime="2005-06-14T18:13:00" id="p16">
makes me wanna go to work...
</post>
<post author="wwooden" datetime="2005-06-14T18:36:00" id="p17">
After watching the video, it's strange to see Steve reading because at the Keynotes he is so smooth and passionate, this felt very rigid.
</post>
<post author="puckhead193" datetime="2005-06-14T18:44:00" id="p18">
I still don't get how he could be fired from a company he started.... <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=":confused:"/>
</post>
<post author="Rod Rod" datetime="2005-06-14T18:46:00" id="p19">
<quote orig_author="puckhead193">
I still don't get how he could be fired from a company he started.... <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=":confused:"/>
</quote>

That's happened to a lot of people, actually. It's not as strange as it initially seems.
</post>
<post author="njmac" datetime="2005-06-14T18:55:00" id="p20">
<quote orig_author="wwooden">
After watching the video, it's strange to see Steve reading because at the Keynotes he is so smooth and passionate, this felt very rigid.
</quote>

After seeing the clip, that was my first thought too. I assumed before I saw the speech that Steve had memorized it.

The speech was very inspirational though. He really delivered for Stanford.
</post>
<post author="sushi" datetime="2005-06-14T18:55:00" id="p21">
<quote orig_author="Macrumors">
<a href="http://news-service.stanford.edu/news/2005/june15/jobs-061505.html">Stanford has posted</a> the text of Steve Jobs' recent commencement speech from Stanford's 2005 graduation speech.

Jobs relates stories about his life, including his work at Apple as well as his public departure:

Jobs, of course, later returned to Apple when Apple purchased NeXT (also founded by Steve Jobs).
</quote>

Enjoyed reading his speech.

Steve makes some very good life points.

Connecting the dots... When he came back to Apple, he was hired for $1 per year. That was it. Until the BOD gave him the airplane and then other items. He was following his passion the gravy followed.

Sushi
</post>
<post author="TheAnswer" datetime="2005-06-14T19:06:00" id="p22">
Ummm....

....shouldn't this be the iTMS free download of the week or something?
</post>
<post author="cashmoney" datetime="2005-06-14T19:06:00" id="p23">
nice! it really touched my heart. <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=":eek:"/> Everything is meaningless compared to death.
</post>
<post author="ravenvii" datetime="2005-06-14T19:17:00" id="p24">
Wow, damn lucky Stanford students! For 365 days a year I do NOT want to be a Stanford student, but this year it's only 364 days! <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=":D"/>

(Oh don't get nitpicky about leap years, you nitpicker! <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=";)"/> )
</post>
<post author="Sophipod" datetime="2005-06-14T19:29:00" id="p25">
Genius

What a smart guy, he really deserves everything he has accomplished.
</post>
</doc>
