<doc id="ENG_DF_001503_20160421_G00A0GOBD">
<headline>
Brexit consequences?
</headline>
<post author="Davita" datetime="2016-04-21T05:37:00" id="p1">
It is well known that UK has a referendum planned for 23 June 2016 to determine whether to stay in EU or exit (Brexit). The UK media is full of info but not much debate from expats....except those living in EU.
There are estimated between 1-2 million UK expats living around the EU countries and I just read a number have legally challenged the UK Gov't as they have been excluded from the referendum vote. Apparently the law states if non-resident UK for over 15 years a UK citizen loses his vote...I didn't know that.
If this challenge is accepted by the court in UK the date for the referendum cannot be met.
All expats on UK's Old Age Pension (OAP), living in EU, have their pensions index-linked while others, living in other countries (i.e. Indonesia; Malaysia; Australia; Canada) are denied. I haven't heard anything about the consequences of this ruling...and how UK, after exiting EU, will deal with perhaps millions of EU expats returning and demanding their pension rights if they are treated similarly to non-EU expats.
If UK exits EU it is likely the pound will devalue significantly..and so will the value of pensions paid in sterling but usually converted to expats residency currencies...this will significantly impact expats but I haven't heard any debate on this either.
Any comments?
</post>
<post author="Fenella" datetime="2016-04-24T03:32:00" id="p2">
Doesn't sound like anyone's too worried about it :-)

We're not receiving a pension from the UK so no thoughts on that. We have sometimes considered that when we're ready to settle down, we might want to go to South of France or Greece. Should UK leave the EU this will no longer be so easy <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/sad.gif"/>

Anyway, I refuse to believe that that it will come to this <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/fingerscrossed.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="InVinoVeritas" datetime="2016-04-24T04:16:00" id="p3">
There's s big discussion going on here, Davita. Join it at you peril!

<a href="http://britishexpats.com/forum/take-outside-67/leaving-eu-857607/">Leaving the EU</a>
</post>
<post author="Davita" datetime="2016-04-24T04:30:00" id="p4">
Thanks Fenella...I agree the Brits (at least the media) seem more concerned that Obama has the audacity to mention the issue than deal with the issue.

Boris Johnson knows how to stir the ploretariat...much like Stalin and Hitler.
Trump applies the same type nationalism rhetoric in the USA Primaries.

Anyone notice that Donald and Boris are look-alikes! Strangely, Boris was born in Manhatten as was Donald.

If Trump becomes President he has vowed USA will become Great America.
If Johnson leads UK to Brexit, and the consequent dissolution when Scotland leaves, there will be no Great Britain... <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/amen.gif"/>

If I were a UK expat living a retired life in EU I'd be very worried...in fact, I'd consider returning and claiming all benefits like NHS and welfare etc.
If millions of expats did that...the UK economy would bankrupt... <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/nod.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Davita" datetime="2016-04-24T04:34:00" id="p5">
<quote orig_author="InVinoVeritas">
There's s big discussion going on here, Davita. Join it at you peril!

<a href="http://britishexpats.com/forum/take-outside-67/leaving-eu-857607/">Leaving the EU</a>
</quote>
See my post a couple of days ago....on the German forum as many UK expats live there...the Take-it-Outside forum isn't my type of debate.
Deathly silence is the response so far but, even here in Bali, I can hear the sucking of false teeth as my question is germinating thought... <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/rofl.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Fenella" datetime="2016-04-24T06:22:00" id="p6">
I do still believe that Boris is the lesser of two evils:-)

The problem is the whole the whole "Great" in "Great Britain". Too many Brits still believe this is the case and that's why they'll be much better off out of the EU. The days of the great British Empire are long gone but not everyone sees it.
</post>
<post author="ex reg" datetime="2016-04-24T08:55:00" id="p7">
<quote orig_author="Davita">
If Johnson leads UK to Brexit, and the consequent dissolution when Scotland leaves, there will be no Great Britain... <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/amen.gif"/>
</quote>
Although I don't follow things closely anymore I can't understand why Scotland will ever again even think about leaving the UK.

Shirley after the plunge in oil prices Scotland's economy would have nose dived to zilch if the Scots had voted to leave the UK last time. They would then have had to get out the begging bowl to Westminster.
</post>
<post author="Davita" datetime="2016-04-24T09:12:00" id="p8">
<quote orig_author="ex reg">
Although I don't follow things closely anymore I can't understand why Scotland will ever again even think about leaving the UK.
</quote>
I suggest searching anything about Scotland leaving UK, if UK leaves EU, and you'll find lots of news on that subject....mainly to the effect United Kingdom would collapse.
</post>
</doc>
