<doc id="ENG_DF_001471_20131205_G00A0FP3R">
<headline>
Tom Merritt Fired from TWiT
</headline>
<post author="MacNut" datetime="2013-12-05T20:41:00" id="p1">
So it looks like Leo's ego got in the way again as he fired Tom today.
<a href="http://inside.twit.tv/blog/2013/12/5/changes-at-twit-part-1.html">http://inside.twit.tv/blog/2013/12/5/changes-at-twit-part-1.html</a>
</post>
<post author="d4rkc4sm" datetime="2013-12-05T20:42:00" id="p2">
i broke up with my girlfriend of 2 years, she admitted to having feelings for someone else. the pain!
</post>
<post author="Jessica Lares" datetime="2013-12-05T21:20:00" id="p3">
Nooooooo! Tom was the only reason why I even tuned into TWiT! <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=":("/> <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=":("/> <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=":("/>
</post>
<post author="MacNut" datetime="2013-12-05T21:35:00" id="p4">
<quote orig_author="Jessica Lares">
Nooooooo! Tom was the only reason why I even tuned into TWiT! <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=":("/> <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=":("/> <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=":("/>
</quote>

More from Leo. He wants a full time in house news director. And has hired Mike Elgan.
<a href="http://inside.twit.tv/blog/2013/12/5/changes-at-twit-part-2.html">http://inside.twit.tv/blog/2013/12/5/changes-at-twit-part-2.html</a>
</post>
<post author="Rogifan" datetime="2013-12-06T02:43:00" id="p5">
<quote orig_author="MacNut">
More from Leo. He wants a full time in house news director. And has hired Mike Elgan.
<a href="http://inside.twit.tv/blog/2013/12/5/changes-at-twit-part-2.html">http://inside.twit.tv/blog/2013/12/5/changes-at-twit-part-2.html</a>
</quote>

Mike Elgan? Seriously?
</post>
<post author="maflynn" datetime="2013-12-06T03:34:00" id="p6">
It sounds like that the Tom not working in the same studio was hampering the production of the show. Skype can only go so far, at least it seems for this situation.

I can't say this is a good or bad move until things shake out a bit more.
</post>
<post author="urkel" datetime="2013-12-06T07:07:00" id="p7">
Tom Merritt - Understands tech and genuinely loves talking about it.
Sarah Lane - Boring, distracted, Nearly clueless about tech and seems to only work at TWiT to fund her globetrotting vacations

I'm sad that Tom was let go but I understand why they had to do it. But what has always been a puzzle is why they continue to keep Sarah Lane on board. I'm sure she's a nice girl (well, not really because she seems pretty condescending) but for a Tech commentator then she just seems so disinterested in everything tech.
</post>
<post author="SandboxGeneral" datetime="2013-12-06T07:16:00" id="p8">
It doesn't sound like Tom was fired per se, but that his contract wasn't renewed and the fact that his distance and therefore lack of presence in the studio had more to do with it than Leo's ego. This of course is based on what Leo wrote in those two blog posts. Call it what you will, but I don't view it as he's be 'fired' as in let go because of wrong-doing. Unless Tom speaks out and gives a different story, that's what I choose to believe.

As for Mike joining the team I'm sure he'll do a good job. I'm not a huge fan of his, but I don't dislike him either.

Sarah is fine host IMO, but I only watch her on iPad Today and no other shows.
</post>
<post author="MacNut" datetime="2013-12-06T09:15:00" id="p9">
Leo said he wants a real news division. So far all they do is read stories off the web. Elgan is supposedly a great journalist so will they do more in house reporting and investigative stories now?

I agree that Sarah is dead weight there, she would make a decent host but has no business reporting on tech.
</post>
<post author="rhett7660" datetime="2013-12-06T10:32:00" id="p10">
<quote orig_author="MacNut">
So it looks like Leo's ego got in the way again as he fired Tom today.
<a href="http://inside.twit.tv/blog/2013/12/5/changes-at-twit-part-1.html">http://inside.twit.tv/blog/2013/12/5/changes-at-twit-part-1.html</a>
</quote>

To me it sounds more like he let him go, since he wasn't in house and wasn't local. The Skype thing was only going so far. Doesn't sound like a firing to me at all.
</post>
<post author="ggibson913" datetime="2013-12-06T11:30:00" id="p11">
<quote orig_author="urkel">
Sarah Lane - Boring, distracted, Nearly clueless about tech and seems to only work at TWiT to fund her globetrotting vacations
</quote>

Though I think she does prep for her shows I would agree that she is not Twit Tv's strongest hosts technically.

----------

It just sounds like they want someone a bit more full time I am sure Tom will do well.
</post>
<post author="MacNut" datetime="2013-12-06T11:52:00" id="p12">
I think Tom wanted out long ago, he saw the direction TWiT was going in and how he could be more successful elsewhere. Leo really is tanking his own network just to make more money.
</post>
</doc>
