<doc id="ENG_DF_001503_20140130_G00A0GI0L">
<headline>
Asylum IN USA
</headline>
<post author="Immi24500" datetime="2014-01-30T17:44:00" id="p1">
Hello people, I am wondering what happens when somebody claims asylum at the US port of entry?
</post>
<post author="sir_eccles" datetime="2014-01-30T18:02:00" id="p2">
I doubt anyone here would have much direct experience. A quick look on Google turned up the following:

<a href="http://www.nolo.com/legal-encyclopedia/when-can-you-apply-asylum.html">http://www.nolo.com/legal-encycloped...ly-asylum.html</a>
</post>
<post author="crg" datetime="2014-01-30T18:22:00" id="p3">
<quote orig_author="Immi24500">
Hello people, I am wondering what happens when somebody claims asylum at the US port of entry?
</quote>
It depends on where attempt is made and the person's citizenship/nationality. The person is almost always detained either for a threshold screening before an asylum officer or to appear directly before an immigration judge. There is generally no right to bail/bond for arriving aliens.
</post>
<post author="Immi24500" datetime="2014-01-30T18:52:00" id="p4">
<quote orig_author="crg">
It depends on where attempt is made and the person's citizenship/nationality. The person is almost always detained either for a threshold screening before an asylum officer or to appear directly before an immigration judge. There is generally no right to bail/bond for arriving aliens.
</quote>

Okay that's good information to know, thank you for your help.

<quote orig_author="sir_eccles">
I doubt anyone here would have much direct experience. A quick look on Google turned up the following:

<a href="http://www.nolo.com/legal-encycloped...ly-asylum.html">http://www.nolo.com/legal-encycloped...ly-asylum.html</a>
</quote>
Hey I read what was on that page, I'm still a little confused though...

Would someone be detained in a detention facility then whilst waiting for their asylum to be granted or denied?
</post>
<post author="crg" datetime="2014-01-30T19:56:00" id="p5">
There are a lot of variables such as claims at a border and the interior including affirmative claims and defensive claims.
</post>
<post author="Boiler" datetime="2014-01-30T20:08:00" id="p6">
<quote orig_author="Immi24500">
Would someone be detained in a detention facility then whilst waiting for their asylum to be granted or denied?
</quote>
Seems to vary, more likely if they are from a T Country.
</post>
<post author="Noorah101" datetime="2014-01-30T20:58:00" id="p7">
<quote orig_author="Immi24500">
Would someone be detained in a detention facility then whilst waiting for their asylum to be granted or denied?
</quote>
It might depend on whether you're trying to enter the USA with or without inspection.

My brother in law entered the USA without inspection and then claimed asylum. He was sent to a detention facility but bail was posted and we paid it. He's been out on bail now, with his asylum case pending since January 2007. He finally got "the final" hearing in May 2009. We got a different lawyer and filed an appeal, which is still pending. He has not yet had a first court date with the new case.

It is not an easy or quick process, and is very expensive.

Rene
</post>
<post author="Boiler" datetime="2014-01-30T21:03:00" id="p8">
Not sure if this is still the case but at Heathrow they had signs up what to do if you were claiming Asylum.
</post>
<post author="S Folinsky" datetime="2014-01-30T21:10:00" id="p9">
<quote orig_author="Immi24500">
Hello people, I am wondering what happens when somebody claims asylum at the US port of entry?
</quote>
They are set up for a "credible fear" interview. There is a set procedure for it. If one has a quarter-decent claim, they will be enlarged into the United States and set up for further proceedings.
</post>
<post author="hungryhorace" datetime="2014-01-30T21:31:00" id="p10">
<quote orig_author="Boiler">
Not sure if this is still the case but at Heathrow they had signs up what to do if you were claiming Asylum.
</quote>
I bet they did. I remember watching the documentary on border control at LHR. There was an African adult came in claiming to be a teenager and claiming ayslum due to having to commit murder or be killed himself. The UKBA officials doubted he was a teenager and surprisingly (not!) he'd lost all his papers so they had no way to find this out.

The utter idiots at the UKBA then released him pending further police investigation. He went on the run and disappeared.

UKBA and LHR appear to actively encourage people to cheat and abuse the asylum system.
</post>
<post author="lansbury" datetime="2014-01-30T22:20:00" id="p11">
<quote orig_author="hungryhorace">
The utter idiots at the UKBA then released him pending further police investigation. He went on the run and disappeared.
</quote>
and pray what were they meant to do? With very limited detention space for immigration holds, there are strict guidelines about who can be detained. If the person didn't meet the guidelines the detention facilities will not take them.
</post>
<post author="hungryhorace" datetime="2014-01-30T22:29:00" id="p12">
<quote orig_author="lansbury">
and pray what were they meant to do?
</quote>
Detain him until his age could be proven via a medical test. Instead they just let him go with the proviso he report to the police. And we wonder why the UK has been flooded with asylum seekers.
</post>
<post author="ian-mstm" datetime="2014-01-30T22:50:00" id="p13">
<quote orig_author="Immi24500">
Would someone be detained in a detention facility then whilst waiting for their asylum to be granted or denied?
</quote>
It's possible, yes. Will it happen to you? No one knows!

Ian
</post>
<post author="rpjs" datetime="2014-01-31T00:33:00" id="p14">
<quote orig_author="hungryhorace">
And we wonder why the UK has been flooded with asylum seekers.
</quote>
I don't. There were less than 20,000 in 2011, the latest year I can find figures for. That's about 1/3 of 1/10 of 1% of the population of the UK. Hardly "flooded".
</post>
</doc>
