<doc id="ENG_DF_001503_20140619_G00A0ACZZ">
<headline>
The Arch criminal in Rome???
</headline>
<post author="Maybe1day" datetime="2014-06-19T07:16:00" id="p1">
What was Berlusca doing in Rome yesterday, His permission to leave Milan Tuesday to Thursday was only for the EU elections. Have the Magistrates gone soft and will they let him save his arse by being elected President.
M
</post>
<post author="Cliftonensis" datetime="2014-06-19T09:04:00" id="p2">
He is making a farse of the Italian justice system. He should be in jail.
</post>
<post author="gioppino" datetime="2014-06-19T14:16:00" id="p3">
<quote orig_author="Cliftonensis">
He is making a farse of the Italian justice system.
</quote>
That's exactly what he wants. Whatever he does, he's a winner, unfortunately.
</post>
<post author="sunnysider" datetime="2014-06-19T16:39:00" id="p4">
Doesn't his sentence add up to 8 days or something if you add the hours?

Folks feel free to correct me/elaborate - memory may be dodgy.
</post>
<post author="Cliftonensis" datetime="2014-06-19T21:16:00" id="p5">
Yes. Instead of 4 years in prison he is doing 6 months at 4 hours a week community service!
</post>
<post author="sunnysider" datetime="2014-06-20T06:37:00" id="p6">
Isn't that just over 4 days?

ie: 52/2 = 26 weeks.

26x4 = 104 hours

= 4.333 days?
</post>
<post author="Maybe1day" datetime="2014-06-20T06:59:00" id="p7">
When It was decided it was 160 hrs, so it is 40Wks at 4 hrs a day. There are also the holiday periods in that time. His pension will also improve due to the public service he is rendering.
</post>
<post author="sunnysider" datetime="2014-06-20T08:09:00" id="p8">
Thanks maybe1day.

So that's 160/24 = 6.666 etc days?

&gt;&gt;There are also the holiday periods in that time.

or are you saying that the sentence is also reduced by holidays?

Which would kind of be a new twist on some folks saying prisoners are in a holiday camp.

Sad thing is:

Whether it's 4, 6 or 8 days that's almost irrelevant really isn't it. That's a maths example/lesson.

The school bell rings and we troop out of the maths lesson to

the government/law/civics class

and very sadly it seems to me that even a 16 year old in remedial studies would figure out that we are dealing with an institutional basket case.
</post>
<post author="Maybe1day" datetime="2014-06-20T08:26:00" id="p9">
becauseof the public holidays the 160 or 162 hours are spread over a longer period like 10 months, if I remember correctly I saw something about it finishing around the beginning of May next year. I'm sure he enjoys relating corny jokes to people who aren't even aware of being in the world.
</post>
<post author="highlander1" datetime="2014-06-20T09:47:00" id="p10">
<quote orig_author="Maybe1day">
becauseof the public holidays the 160 or 162 hours are spread over a longer period like 10 months, if I remember correctly I saw something about it finishing around the beginning of May next year. I'm sure he enjoys relating corny jokes to people who aren't even aware of being in the world.
</quote>
A bit like him, then !? ( in the REAL world, that is ) <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/sneaky.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Maybe1day" datetime="2014-06-20T14:52:00" id="p11">
Quite! <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/sneaky.gif"/>
</post>
</doc>
