<doc id="ENG_DF_001503_20140520_G00A0GK65">
<headline>
Self pack container - Bristol to Sydney
</headline>
<post author="misterman" datetime="2014-05-20T14:51:00" id="p1">
Long time reader, first time writer!

My partner and I are emigrating to Australia from the UK. We've lived in Sydney for a year, and have travelled around the country in a motorhome. We are very much looking forward to making the most of our 175 visas!

I am looking to self pack a container, and ship our personal effects to Sydney, from Bristol. Reasons are cost and trust in handling our effects.

In short, from my research, I can see there are several things we need to do. My reason for posting is to ensure that I have everything covered and to share my research. If I have missed anything, please let me know!

Questions in RED

----------------------------------

Shipping Plan
Bristol, UK to Sydney, Australia
20ft self-pack container

Overview
Arrange Shipping Agent - container delivery and shipping Arrange Marine Insurance - to cover loss during shipping Arrange Clearing Agent - assistance with AQIS and import into Sydney Arrange Delivery Company - collection from Sydney and delivery to new home
Details

Container Delivery

I am to check that the container provided by the shipping company is free of smells and leaks (closing all doors and looking for sunlight / holes). I have read even the smallest leaks can create water problems. Any bad smells are likely to transfer over to our belongings.

The reasons for a sole-use 20ft container are:
I want to pack it myself I don't want to share with someone and increase the chances of mix-ups, loss or damage from excessive handling As soon as the container is packed I want it shipped, I don't want to wait I can easily fill a 20ft container, so any cost savings on sharing will be minimal
Loading Container / Inventory / Bristol Port

I intend to have a 20ft container delivered to a storage facility, where our effects are already packed into boxes. I estimate around 2-3 hours to load everything on properly. I am to ensure that heavy items are at the back, lighter towards the front. Ratchet straps may be required to ensure that items are really secure in the container. I may consider getting hold of some tarp to cover the boxes and furniture.

The boxes/items will be clearly labelled with permanent marker pen (e.g. Box 1) and this labelling will marry up with a full inventory of contents. Items that the AQIS may be interested in will be packed in seperate boxes and labelled accordingly on the inventory. "Fragile", "Heavy" and "Do not open with knives" labels as appropriate.

A sample of this inventory would look like:

BOX | CONTENTS | VALUE | AQIS RISK?
------------------------------------------------------------------
Box 1 | DVDs and CDs - approx 50 | $100 AUD | No Risk
Box 1 | Books | $20 AUD | No Risk
Box 2 | Wicker Basket | $10 AUD | Risk
Box 3 | Bicycle | $200 AUD | Risk - cleaned

I will value the effects, but probably only include the value column for the import declaration value and marine insurance. Do I need monetary values on the inventory?

The container will be collected by the Shipping Agent - most likely the container will remain on the back of the lorry during delivery and packing and be taken away the same day.

The Shipping Agent will be given the required documents and the container will be sealed and taken to port.

Shipping

Shipping can take around 2 months, so if I want items in Australia by October 1st, I ought to have them on a container ship by August 1st.

I will take out marine insurance to cover total loss. I will see if I can get insurance for the expensive singular items (guitars, audio/visual equipment).

I've got recommendations for Letton Percival - any others?
How long did your container take to arrive?

Arrival into Sydney

On arrival all of our effects are unloaded from the container into an AQIS storage facility and checked over by the AQIS. Having an inventory that flags items of interest should greatly help with speeding this process up and reduce the amount of handling and complications.

I have heard that this can take up to 3 weeks. Any ideas / experiences / costs?

The Clearing Agent in Sydney will liase with AQIS to ensure any appropriate charges are paid and arrange the forward delivery from the AQIS holding facility. Potentially I may need to have my effects stored somewhere in Sydney while I find some accomodation - can a Clearing Agent help with this?

Delivery to new home

The Delivery Agent will collect the effects from storage (or potentially straight from AQIS storage) and deliver to our new home.

----------------------------------

Thanks!
</post>
</doc>
