<doc id="ENG_DF_001471_20130626_G00A0FNIS">
<headline>
Where were you when Steve Jobs...
</headline>
<post author="SanJacinto" datetime="2013-06-26T07:32:00" id="p1">
I think this could be a great thread. The choice what Steve did at a specific moment I leave up to you.

Where was I when Steve Jobs...

... announced the original Macintosh:
I was right around the corner to see the light of day.

... resigned as CEO:
I was just 5 min back from a great beach vacation. I was really relaxed and thought this is a great summer.
My MacBook was stored at a friend's home and as we arrived I got the sad news. The music we had listened on that day always reminds me of this day.
Music is a stark "storage media" for memories.

...died:
This was the time when I did my diploma thesis. I got the news by short message when I was at home. "Nonetheless, you have to be productive today" was my girlfriend's message <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=";)"/>

I am eagerly looking forward to your various contributions on this thread.
</post>
<post author="Jessica Lares" datetime="2013-06-26T09:03:00" id="p2">
... announced the original Macintosh: Not born yet. <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=":D"/>

... resigned as CEO: I was at my grandma's. I called my dad when I heard the news.

...died: We had just come back from getting dinner. I actually didn't get to eat most of it because I had this horrible feeling in my stomach after hearing the news. Called my dad then too.
</post>
<post author="cambookpro" datetime="2013-06-26T09:15:00" id="p3">
Where I was when SJ:

...announced the original Macintosh. About minus 14 years old!

...stepped down as CEO. On holiday in France. We had BBC News, and I heard them mentioning SJ as I was still in bed. My first thought was that he had died <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=":("/>

...died. At home, sleeping. Woke up to read the news on my iPhone.
</post>
<post author="roadbloc" datetime="2013-06-26T13:33:00" id="p4">
Wasn't born. Can't remember. Can't remember.
</post>
<post author="MacsRgr8" datetime="2013-06-28T14:29:00" id="p5">
Where was I when Steve Jobs...

... announced the original Macintosh:
I was 12 years old. I had no idea that I would become an Apple addict.

... resigned as CEO:
On holiday in the US. We were in D.C. just before walking to the White House.
That announcement really hit me: the end was nigh.

...died:
At home asleep. I woke up that morning (CET)and 3 friends and colleagues had text me about the horrific news.
</post>
<post author="Nermal" datetime="2013-06-28T14:39:00" id="p6">
1. I was less than a year old at that point.

2. I don't remember.

3. In a crisis at work because a ship had crashed on the same day.
</post>
<post author="dukebound85" datetime="2013-06-28T14:42:00" id="p7">
<quote orig_author="roadbloc">
Wasn't born. Can't remember. Can't remember.
</quote>

same I think. Was it introduced in 84? if so, yea, not born

If so
1) not born
2) DKDC
3) DKDC

Now ask me about 9/11 or the oklahoma city bombings or substantial news, I'd have a different answer <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=";)"/>
</post>
<post author="bruds23" datetime="2013-06-28T14:57:00" id="p8">
where was I when sj introd. the Mac

i was 21 old jobless,did not care,now 50 yrs old,i love the Mac,i have,a few of them,had windows,they suck,love only Mac now
</post>
<post author="A Hebrew" datetime="2013-06-29T21:47:00" id="p9">
Mac - Not alive
Resigned - I don't care
Died - I don't care

9/11 - Elementary school classroom
Oklahoma - I don't care
</post>
<post author="appleguy123" datetime="2013-06-29T23:10:00" id="p10">
Wasn't born

In my calculus class, saw it on MacRumors.

Watching the forum spy, I was hoping that it was a 4chan trick or something when all the threads started to show up.
</post>
<post author="GermanyChris" datetime="2013-06-30T10:58:00" id="p11">
I was 8
I dunno
I was asleep

9-11: was having breakfast with my Platoon leader at Ft. Drum, NY I said how you like to be the guy known for driving his plane into a building October 2nd I was on a plane headed to Afghanistan.

Oklahoma City: Doing final prep for lunch at Old Peninsula Brew Pub in Kalamazoo MI.
</post>
<post author="turtle777" datetime="2013-07-05T20:51:00" id="p12">
1) Exploring Mars
2) Fighting zombies
3) Inventing time travel in 1924

-t
</post>
<post author="yg17" datetime="2013-07-07T09:44:00" id="p13">
1. Not born
2. Don't know, don't care
3. See above

9/11 - at home, playing hooky from high school because I forgot to study for a test that day
OKC - Too young to remember
</post>
<post author="AngryGerbil" datetime="2013-07-08T05:05:00" id="p14">
<quote orig_author="SanJacinto">
I think this could be a great thread. The choice what Steve did at a specific moment I leave up to you.

Where was I when Steve Jobs...

... announced the original Macintosh:
I was right around the corner to see the light of day.
</quote>

On deployment in the Western Pacific for the Navy.

The other events are relatively insignificant in the scheme of things.
</post>
<post author="\-V-/" datetime="2013-07-08T05:09:00" id="p15">
1. Wasn't born yet.

2. Was enjoying the adventurous life of a one year old.

3. I was at home when I switched on the news. Pretty much ruined my day.
</post>
<post author="eawmp1" datetime="2013-07-08T05:10:00" id="p16">
Can't remember x3

While I love all things Apple, these events didn't rise to the occasion of searing a day into my memory like, for example 9/11 did. Sorry.
</post>
<post author="maflynn" datetime="2013-07-08T05:11:00" id="p17">
1. Watching the super bowl <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=":eek:"/>
2. At work
3. At work
</post>
</doc>
