<doc id="ENG_DF_001503_20130522_G00A0GEWX">
<headline>
Soldier hacked to death in London
</headline>
<post author="Kapri" datetime="2013-05-22T18:22:00" id="p1">
Dreadful news today. Looks like a young army cadet was hacked to death with a machete. It's being treated as a terrorist attack.
Sorry, can't post link at the moment - maybe someone could do it for me.
</post>
<post author="Kapri" datetime="2013-05-22T18:57:00" id="p2">
There is footage on the itv news site of the killers. They talk to a camera with the body lying in the background. It looks like they were waiting for the police.
</post>
<post author="bingobob777" datetime="2013-05-22T21:19:00" id="p3">
2 nutters hack somebody to death and the PM is flying back to consider raising the Terrorist Threat Level to serious.

What a ****** joke. Shocking incident, but I'm more likely to get killed by lightning than a terrorist, I hardly consider either as serious.

Manipluating someones death to try and force more monitoring and laws on us.
</post>
<post author="Dreamy" datetime="2013-05-22T21:20:00" id="p4">
This was an absolutely appalling, sickening, barbaric murder.

I can only feel for the family of that soldier if the film clip is being played in the UK as much as it is over here. Media outlets are positively salivating over it, which is almost as disturbing.
</post>
<post author="mikelincs" datetime="2013-05-22T21:23:00" id="p5">
Well ITV have just given the killers several minutes of air time showing one of them talking to someone filming him on a mobile phone. That should never have been shown, the killer has blood all over him and is still carrying the machete and knife
</post>
<post author="Shard" datetime="2013-05-22T21:25:00" id="p6">
<quote orig_author="Dreamy">
This was an absolutely appalling, sickening, barbaric murder.

I can only feel for the family of that soldier if the film clip is being played in the UK as much as it is over here. Media outlets are positively salivating over it, which is almost as disturbing.
</quote>
When the perpetrators are caught red handed, and threatening that their group (Islamists) are going to continue killing, and that the government won't be able to provide protection, locals do take an interest, yes.
</post>
<post author="cresta57" datetime="2013-05-22T21:43:00" id="p7">
<quote orig_author="mikelincs">
Well ITV have just given the killers several minutes of air time showing one of them talking to someone filming him on a mobile phone. That should never have been shown, the killer has blood all over him and is still carrying the machete and knife
</quote>
Do you think the media should have been gagged &amp; the event given no air time?

The footage being bandied about via facebook, Youtube &amp; the rest of the world's news media would have gone viral on the net regardless of any attempt at censorship.
</post>
<post author="Shard" datetime="2013-05-22T22:35:00" id="p8">
<quote orig_author="cresta57">
Do you think the media should have been gagged &amp; the event given no air time?

The footage being bandied about via facebook, Youtube &amp; the rest of the world's news media would have gone viral on the net regardless of any attempt at censorship.
</quote>
+1

It's ridiculous to suggest the media should not be reporting on this. And judging by what every British news channel and newspaper is running this evening, they agree.
</post>
<post author="ozzieeagle" datetime="2013-05-22T22:56:00" id="p9">
Small amount of concern in South London as to whether the EDL will become puppets of what these looneys set out to acheive..... division and fear. We'll know in the next 48 hours.

Hopefully not as the EDL are small in number and reprisals would have happened already.
</post>
<post author="Dreamy" datetime="2013-05-22T23:19:00" id="p10">
<quote orig_author="Shard">
When the perpetrators are caught red handed, and threatening that their group (Islamists) are going to continue killing, and that the government won't be able to provide protection, locals do take an interest, yes.
</quote>
I'm not saying that it shouldn't be reported or that locals wouldn't take an interest- it's the number of times that the footage of a blood dripping murderer has been aired.

In one hour on morning tv here in Australia, that clip was shown pretty much every other news story. Media outlets are pretty much orgasmic about it.
</post>
<post author="Shard" datetime="2013-05-22T23:39:00" id="p11">
<quote orig_author="Dreamy">
I'm not saying that it shouldn't be reported or that locals wouldn't take an interest- it's the number of times that the footage of a blood dripping murderer has been aired.

In one hour on morning tv here in Australia, that clip was shown pretty much every other news story. Media outlets are pretty much orgasmic about it.
</quote>
Probably not what you want to see while you're slurping down your cornflakes but it's quite an image. It's straight out of a horror movie.
</post>
<post author="Amazulu" datetime="2013-05-22T23:55:00" id="p12">
Welcome to your future
</post>
</doc>
