<doc id="ENG_DF_001487_20160420_G00A0AVK1">
<headline>
"Rules?! Boy, now what'choo talkin' bout rules, eh?"
</headline>
<post datetime="2016-04-20T08:51:11" id="p1">
<a href="#comment">Skip to comments.</a>
Posted on 04/20/2016 8:51:11 AM PDT by <a href="/~jpsb/">jpsb</a>
LifeZette has obtained evidence that supporters of Donald Trump and Ted Cruz in Mississippi have been threatened with possible arrest should they refuse to elect pro-Establishment delegates to the state’s GOP convention on April 23.

(Excerpt) Read more at <a href="http://www.lifezette.com/polizette/something-stinks-mississippi/">lifezette.com</a>...
; ; ; ;
Disclaimer: Opinions posted on Free Republic are those of the individual posters and do not necessarily represent the opinion of Free Republic or its management. All materials posted herein are protected by copyright law and the exemption for fair use of copyrighted works.
</post>
<post author="jpsb" datetime="2016-04-20T08:51:11" id="p2">
Hmmmm
</post>
<post author="vette6387" datetime="2016-04-20T08:51:11" id="p3">
When a state has turds line Haley Barbour and Thad Cochran, nothing more need be said. The MS GOP is among the worst of the lot.
</post>
<post author="Psalm 144" datetime="2016-04-20T08:51:11" id="p4">
Lol. Welcome to lawsuit hell if they try.
</post>
<post author="jpsb" datetime="2016-04-20T08:51:11" id="p5">
Once upon a time I liked Haley Barbour, no more.
</post>
<post author="McCarthysGhost" datetime="2016-04-20T08:51:11" id="p6">
Is this against the rules?
</post>
<post author="Savage Rider" datetime="2016-04-20T08:51:11" id="p7">
So this person sending the text says they are going to try to elect Trump and Cruz supporters? I forget, who won Mississippi? Is this something that shouldn’t happen?
</post>
<post author="vette6387" datetime="2016-04-20T08:51:11" id="p8">
“Once upon a time I liked Haley Barbour, no more.”
Once upon a time, I thought the GOP was an honest, conservative political party that was interested in doing good things for our country, but no more!
</post>
<post author="Charles Martel" datetime="2016-04-20T08:51:11" id="p9">
That’s interesting. I’d like the MS state GOP guys to point out the statute that would allow arrests for displeasing political party officials.
</post>
<post author="COBOL2Java" datetime="2016-04-20T08:51:11" id="p10">
</post>
<post author="scooby321" datetime="2016-04-20T08:51:11" id="p11">
Haley thinks Mississippi is his own cash machine Anyone goes there it's like West Virginia with Robert Byrd so many Government projects it will make your head swim
No one complained about Hurricane Katrina in Mississippi they got rebuilt better than ever.
</post>
<post author="vette6387" datetime="2016-04-20T08:51:11" id="p12">
“Haley thinks Mississippi is his own cash machine”
Haley is Mississippi’s “Boss Hogg!” If they ever do a remake of “The Duke’s of Hazzard,” Haley has a role! Just get him a whte hat and outfit. He’s fat enough to fit perfectly!
</post>
<post author="Grams A" datetime="2016-04-20T08:51:11" id="p13">
We took a trip to the Alabama coast three summers ago. Rarely saw any signs that they had even had a hurricane. Then the next summer we went to Mississippi. Not much restored, particularly the wonderful older homes on the Gulf. Evidence of damage from the hurricane remained everywhere. Lots of shells of construction projects that were never finished. We did notice some minimal expansion and rebuilding when we went back last summer. By comparison between the two states in just the Gulf area, Mississippi is way, way behind.
</post>
<post author="Nifster" datetime="2016-04-20T08:51:11" id="p14">
An the Barbour crime family at its best
</post>
<post author="McCarthysGhost" datetime="2016-04-20T08:51:11" id="p15">
Lol...
</post>
<post author="TBP" datetime="2016-04-20T08:51:11" id="p16">
On what basis?
</post>
<post author="Gator113" datetime="2016-04-20T08:51:11" id="p17">
They themselves do not want to go to prison and they know that once the GOP-e organized criminal organization is taken down, that will be their destiny.
</post>
<post author="jmaroneps37" datetime="2016-04-20T08:51:11" id="p18">
The Mississippi GOPe is among the worst bunch of scumbags there are.
</post>
<post author="WKB" datetime="2016-04-20T08:51:11" id="p19">
Mississippi ping
</post>
<post author="Islander7" datetime="2016-04-20T08:51:11" id="p20">
That’s because Katrina did not hit Alabama. Geez...look at map will you?
</post>
<post author="Grams A" datetime="2016-04-20T08:51:11" id="p21">
Well, EXCUSE ME. You might want to chill just a bit.
</post>
<post author="houeto" datetime="2016-04-20T08:51:11" id="p22">
Why in the heck should Islander7 need to chill? Your post was ridiculous. Alabama didn't get hit by Katrina. The eye actually made landfall in Louisiana. Mississippi took the brunt of the storm. It amounts to the difference between being slapped and KNOCKED OUT! Please do your homework before passing judgment.
</post>
<post author="jpsb" datetime="2016-04-20T08:51:11" id="p23">
bump!
</post>
<post author="DrewsMum" datetime="2016-04-20T08:51:11" id="p24">
Have Freepers completely and utterly lost the ability to comprehend what they read?
</post>
</doc>
