<doc id="ENG_DF_001503_20131014_G00A0AUPY">
<headline>
Help in working out with costs of the BIG MOVE!
</headline>
<post author="Irishcop" datetime="2013-10-14T15:53:00" id="p1">
Hey guys, I knowo this has probably been done thousands of times on other threads but unfortunately I am working flat out over the next few days then have a hospital procedure that will knock me out of researching for a while.

Could people give rough estimations of what it will cost for this move. As most of you know I's be travelling solo and so paying only for myself, so I don't have anyone to keep me right or help with the research. My dad is going to help me to work out the best way of financing it all but wants me to bring him rough figures. So far I have the following;

£2000 visa
£350-400 medical
$2000 (ish) bond for accom
$2000 (ish) for first months rent before we start to get paid
£700-800 (ish) for one way flight <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/eek.gif"/>

Im not planning on having anything shipped over at this stage, just me myself and I.

Any help would be great thanks <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/thumbsup.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="christmasoompa" datetime="2013-10-14T17:46:00" id="p2">
You'd be better off asking this in the main country forums for wherever you're going to - you haven't actually said in your post which country that is though!
</post>
<post author="Irishcop" datetime="2013-10-14T17:59:00" id="p3">
Oh yeah right enough!!! Haha oopssss! Hopefully Western Australia <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/smile.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Poitin" datetime="2013-10-14T21:10:00" id="p4">
Just a suggestion - house share at start if its just yourself.

You'll need a car. My friend hired a car via gum tree at a better rate that the hire companies when they first came but that was over in QLD.

Have you got a job to come to? - it will take longer that a month to secure work if you don't have anything lined up.

Heaps of Irish in Perth if that's where your going there.

check out gum tree - but beware lots of scam on that site too.

Good luck with visa etc.

Poitin
</post>
<post author="Irishcop" datetime="2013-10-14T21:11:00" id="p5">
Yeah I would be joining the police, so a guaranteed job
</post>
<post author="old.sparkles" datetime="2013-10-15T03:01:00" id="p6">
<quote orig_author="Irishcop">
Oh yeah right enough!!! Haha oopssss! Hopefully Western Australia <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/smile.gif"/>
</quote>
Your figures don't look far off Irish, maybe a little more on the visa cost <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/smile.gif"/>
Obviously some cash for food and travel before you get paid as well - are you thinking of purchasing a car here or using public?

If you let an airline know you are migrating and have an unvalidated visa, you may get double baggage allowance - we did with Singapore and had 40kg each plus hand luggage which helps <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/smile.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="The Elk" datetime="2013-10-15T06:38:00" id="p7">
I know someone who moved to Canberra and shipped their car over. Is that a feasible option? It certainly seems like it could be much cheaper to ship your car and re register rather than buy/rent when you arrive.
</post>
<post author="Irishcop" datetime="2013-10-15T08:14:00" id="p8">
I was considering shipping the car over but then had heard it cost somewhere in the region of about £3k??
</post>
<post author="old.sparkles" datetime="2013-10-15T08:18:00" id="p9">
<quote orig_author="Irishcop">
I was considering shipping the car over but then had heard it cost somewhere in the region of about £3k??
</quote>
There's a thread around somewhere if you use search.

As a comparison, my 10yr old ford focus cost me $5500 with 3 months rego <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/smile.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="old.sparkles" datetime="2013-10-15T08:22:00" id="p10">
<quote orig_author="old.sparkles">
There's a thread around somewhere if you use search.

As a comparison, my 10yr old ford focus cost me $5500 with 3 months rego <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/smile.gif"/>
</quote>
Edit - found it <a href="http://britishexpats.com/forum/australia-54/car-shipping-roll-roll-off-service-800640/?highlight=import+car">Car Shipping - Roll On Roll Off Service</a>
</post>
<post author="spartaclaus" datetime="2013-10-16T17:00:00" id="p11">
When do you start with wapol mate? I'm applying via the lateral entry route - my wife's an accountant and we're in the final stages of a 189 (independent) visa application.
</post>
<post author="Irishcop" datetime="2013-10-16T18:57:00" id="p12">
I've only just been told I passed all my assessments so doing the police checks etc at the minute. All being well I think April
</post>
<post author="spartaclaus" datetime="2013-10-16T20:03:00" id="p13">
Top stuff! IF all goes according to plan I could be on the same course! Where are you based now?... I'm met. 9 years man and boy <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/wink.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Irishcop" datetime="2013-10-16T20:05:00" id="p14">
Exciting times!! I'm PSNI for the last 5 years. Woman and girl!
</post>
<post author="spartaclaus" datetime="2013-10-16T20:12:00" id="p15">
Excellent! It would be great to stay in touch... I'm obviously a long way behind you in the process but I've been told I should apply and may be able to start April/May if successful.... the application process will not be as long as yours because I''ve already got PR....
</post>
</doc>
