<doc id="ENG_DF_001503_20131126_G00A0GH1O">
<headline>
Domestic Goddess
</headline>
<post author="Bahtatboy" datetime="2013-11-26T14:40:00" id="p1">
This might not turn out so well...

Nigella Lawson 'was so off her head on cocaine that she allowed her assistants to spend £300,000 on credit cards', court hears

Can you be convicted of drug offences in this situation?

<a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2513829/Nigella-Lawson-head-cocaine-allowed-assistants-spend-300-000-credit-cards-court-hears.html">http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/arti...urt-hears.html</a>
</post>
<post author="Autonomy" datetime="2013-11-26T19:36:00" id="p2">
One for you...
</post>
<post author="OleJanx" datetime="2013-11-26T21:41:00" id="p3">
<quote orig_author="Bahtatboy">
This might not turn out so well...

Nigella Lawson 'was so off her head on cocaine that she allowed her assistants to spend £300,000 on credit cards', court hears

Can you be convicted of drug offences in this situation?

<a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2513829/Nigella-Lawson-head-cocaine-allowed-assistants-spend-300-000-credit-cards-court-hears.html">http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/arti...urt-hears.html</a>
</quote>
Makes you wonder about the icing sugar now, doesn't it?
</post>
<post author="Scamp" datetime="2013-11-27T03:41:00" id="p4">
<quote orig_author="OleJanx">
Makes you wonder about the icing sugar now, doesn't it?
</quote>
I'd definitely eat more cake (believe it or not, I don't really like it) if it was powdered with some Colombian bam bam.
</post>
<post author="Ethos83" datetime="2013-11-27T07:12:00" id="p5">
The press is all over this in the UK at the mo.

I hope it's only slander but I have a sad feeling it's true and that Saatchi, instead of the barbarous abuser, was only an angry husband confronting his wife about a ten year drug habit and £300K down the drain. One of the photos from the restaurant scene last summer even shows him holding Nigella's nose and probing it as if looking for evidence of a coke habit.

His public silence on the drug habit till forced out by the courts only makes him look better.

But can someone really keep a major drug habit a secret from a spouse for ten years?
</post>
<post author="shiva" datetime="2013-11-27T07:27:00" id="p6">
<quote orig_author="Ethos83">
The press is all over this in the UK at the mo.

I hope it's only slander but I have a sad feeling it's true and that Saatchi, instead of the barbarous abuser, was only an angry husband confronting his wife about a ten year drug habit and £300K down the drain. One of the photos from the restaurant scene last summer even shows him holding Nigella's nose and probing it as if looking for evidence of a coke habit.

His public silence on the drug habit till forced out by the courts only makes him look better.

But can someone really keep a major drug habit a secret from a spouse for ten years? if the spouse is a self deluding idiot yes.
</quote>
anyway you look at it grabbing her by the throat and forcibly examining her nostrils is assault and a move only an abusive dick would undertake
</post>
<post author="Ethos83" datetime="2013-11-27T07:33:00" id="p7">
Sure.

But how many of us have been in a situation where we've just found out that the wife hid a hugely expensive drug habit for a decade?

It's hard to gauge the effect such a discovery would have on a person if we haven't experienced it. As Mrs. Ethos said to me, 'I really don't know what my immediate reaction would be but you'd better hope there isn't a handy cast iron frying pan lying around'.

<quote orig_author="shiva">
anyway you look at it grabbing her by the throat and forcibly examining her nostrils is assault and a move only an abusive dick would undertake
</quote>
</post>
<post author="co durham boy" datetime="2013-11-27T07:40:00" id="p8">
<quote orig_author="Bahtatboy">
This might not turn out so well...

Nigella Lawson 'was so off her head on cocaine that she allowed her assistants to spend £300,000 on credit cards', court hears

Can you be convicted of drug offences in this situation?

<a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2513829/Nigella-Lawson-head-cocaine-allowed-assistants-spend-300-000-credit-cards-court-hears.html">http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/arti...urt-hears.html</a>
</quote>
No, she can be questioned relating to information and cautioned but to charge someone you need evidence. The charge of possession or possession with intent to supply doesnt apply.

They tried to charge Kate Moss a few years ago with evidence of mobile phone footage but possession needs to be proved.

Another TV celeb who like a bit of toot, no real big story. She's the darling of the Daily Mail readers though.

They'll be choking on their Granola this morning. <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/wink.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="weasel decentral" datetime="2013-11-27T07:49:00" id="p9">
<quote orig_author="Ethos83">
'but you'd better hope there isn't a handy cast iron frying pan lying around'.
</quote>
Part of a matching set too I hope, with a nice embossed handle design, nestling beside the Aga.
</post>
<post author="flares" datetime="2013-11-27T07:49:00" id="p10">
Mr Roger Quimbly ‏@RogerQuimbly 9h
It must have come as quite a shock for Charles Saatchi to see someone taking cocaine after his sheltered life in advertising.
</post>
<post author="OleJanx" datetime="2013-11-27T07:58:00" id="p11">
<quote orig_author="saudiflares">
Mr Roger Quimbly ‏@RogerQuimbly 9h
It must have come as quite a shock for Charles Saatchi to see someone taking cocaine after his sheltered life in advertising.
</quote>
<img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/rofl.gif"/>
</post>
</doc>
