<doc id="ENG_DF_001471_20060626_G00A0FF5Z">
<headline>
Should we punish Apple for its Chinese Labour Law Abuse?
</headline>
<post author="jacobj" datetime="2006-06-26T12:33:00" id="p1">
I would really love to know what people think of Apple using a company in China that has abused its staff by overworking them. Please answer honestly and remain anonymous if you like.
</post>
<post author="jsw" datetime="2006-06-26T12:36:00" id="p2">
(1) Please provide links to articles describing the abuse.

(2) How would you expect people to respond anonymously? [edit: never mind... wasn't a poll when I responded]
</post>
<post author="Applespider" datetime="2006-06-26T12:39:00" id="p3">
My answer depends on what measures Apple had taken to ensure that the company were following Apple's supplier guidelines (ie any monitoring or just laissez-faire) and what measures they take now that lapses have been admitted - both against this company and to ensure that similar problems aren't happening at any other supplier.
</post>
<post author="Josh" datetime="2006-06-26T12:39:00" id="p4">
<quote orig_author="jsw">
(1) Please provide links to articles describing the abuse.

(2) How would you expect people to respond anonymously?
</quote>

<a href="http://www.chinacsr.com/2006/06/26/foxconn-admits-breaking-labor-laws-in-china/">here's the link</a>.

Not sure how we could "punish" them... <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=":confused:"/>

Not a good situation though, for sure.
</post>
<post author="yg17" datetime="2006-06-26T12:50:00" id="p5">
China has labor laws? It doesn't seem like Apple is abusing anything.
</post>
<post author="jsw" datetime="2006-06-26T12:54:00" id="p6">
I chose "NO: I don't really care" because, honestly, I don't. I could have picked "NO: I am concerned but will let others punish them" but I suppose what's closest to what I really feel is "NO: I don't really care because others will punish the OEM suppliers if need be."

I think it's naive to assume that any other manufacturer doesn't use OEM suppliers which do the same thing. I won't stop buying Apple products because of it. If they were grinding small children up to make the casings or whatever, then, yes, maybe I'd care, but, as it stands, nothing I do will stop those workers from being abused by that company. If I stop buying Apple and buy some other supplier's system, then I have no proof whatsoever that such a purchase will in any way reduce any sort of labor abuse.

To think that not buying Apple products will (a) alter Apple's opinion at all and/or (b) will in any way positively affect those workers is wishful thinking.
</post>
<post author="FleurDuMal" datetime="2006-06-26T12:54:00" id="p7">
<quote orig_author="yg17">
China has labor laws? It doesn't seem like Apple is abusing anything.
</quote>

Actually, there's a really interesting article in the Guardian last Saturday which proposes that Chinese labourers actually have better labour rights than British workers!!
</post>
<post author="princealfie" datetime="2006-06-26T12:57:00" id="p8">
I would stop buying Apple products if nothing changes. Globalization is bad... <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=":eek:"/>
</post>
<post author="CanadaRAM" datetime="2006-06-26T13:18:00" id="p9">
<quote orig_author="princealfie">
I would stop buying Apple products if nothing changes. Globalization is bad... <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=":eek:"/>
</quote>

Ummm... OK. You realize of course that almost every electronic device you own has Foxconn components inside it? That'll include your TV, your clock-radio, your microwave, certainly your car and possibly your washing machine as well. Generally, wherever a cable plugs into a socket, the likelihood is that Foxconn made the socket. Look at the label on the inside collar of your shirt - it will say Malaysia, Vietnam or China... made under the same or worse factory conditions. Even if you choose sustainable forest lumber from North America, the nails you use to build your house out of likely came from China.

Unless you want to return to horse-drawn transport and barter locally for your food and clothes, you may want to reconsider.
</post>
<post author="geese" datetime="2006-06-26T13:43:00" id="p10">
<quote orig_author="jacobj">
I would really love to know what people think of Apple using a company in China that has abused its staff by overworking them. Please answer honestly and remain anonymous if you like.
</quote>

A rather vague and emotive way of putting it.

Apple doesn't own any of its factories in China, it sub-contracts to them. The allegations made in the press have been that Apple have been using sub-contractors who under-pay and over-work their employers. These sub-contractors also are also used by other electronics companies. A subtle difference but an important one.

This does not excuse Apple from taking any action if it hears of any unethical practice by any of its sub-contractors however. I would like to think that Apple would take action agaist any contractors that abuse human rights.

Remember that Foxconn isnt just based in China- it also has a factory in Czech republis, where Mac-minis are made.
</post>
<post author="yellow" datetime="2006-06-26T13:46:00" id="p11">
I'd say Apathy Rules, but I don't really care...
</post>
</doc>
