<doc id="ENG_DF_001503_20130522_G00A0GEWU">
<headline>
Machete attack in London
</headline>
<post author="kittycat1" datetime="2013-05-22T17:19:00" id="p1">
Reports saying this a terror attack- sounds like a horrific attack.

<a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-22630304">http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-22630304</a>
</post>
<post author="britexpat76" datetime="2013-05-22T18:00:00" id="p2">
<quote orig_author="kittycat1">
Reports saying this a terror attack- sounds like a horrific attack.

<a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-22630304">http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-22630304</a>
</quote>
Beheaded infront of a school. Words are failing me...........
</post>
<post author="shiva" datetime="2013-05-22T18:47:00" id="p3">
Go here

<a href="http://www.helpforheroes.org.uk">http://www.helpforheroes.org.uk</a>

Buy a tshirt
</post>
<post author="britexpat76" datetime="2013-05-22T19:20:00" id="p4">
Seems 2 Somali terrorists. I fear revenge attacks for this as by the time the BNP spout all their bollocks they will whip up a hate mob.
</post>
<post author="Boomhauer" datetime="2013-05-22T19:54:00" id="p5">
<quote orig_author="britexpat76">
Seems 2 Somali terrorists. I fear revenge attacks for this as by the time the BNP spout all their bollocks they will whip up a hate mob.
</quote>
I see online sources say they are Somali, but they really don't look Somali.
</post>
<post author="kittycat1" datetime="2013-05-22T20:07:00" id="p6">
if you watch the video of one of the guys on camera he sounds suspiciously London, maybe born elsewhere but certainly has grown up in London. Doesn't really matter where they are from though, the fact they are referencing Allah is going to cause yet another backlash to the peaceful muslims living in UK. Sad times indeed.
</post>
<post author="Irishbeekeeper" datetime="2013-05-22T20:10:00" id="p7">
That's murder, plain and simple!
An eye for an eye! I say hang them!
My thoughts to the person's poor family going through such a horrible time right now!
</post>
<post author="britexpat76" datetime="2013-05-22T20:15:00" id="p8">
<quote orig_author="Irishbeekeeper">
That's murder, plain and simple!
An eye for an eye! I say hang them!
My thoughts to the person's poor family going through such a horrible time right now!
</quote>
And practically seeing the death on TV. Truly awful. It is times like this that we could learn from the ME laws as I guarantee they would be dead inside a year.

Though as fundamentalists are we better to keep them alive (and let leroy and his jail boys say hello everyday) so they do not die a martyr to other fundamentalists?
</post>
<post author="Boomhauer" datetime="2013-05-22T20:22:00" id="p9">
<quote orig_author="Irishbeekeeper">
That's murder, plain and simple!
An eye for an eye! I say hang them!
My thoughts to the person's poor family going through such a horrible time right now!
</quote>
Death is too good for them; I am all for letting them rot in jail for life.
</post>
<post author="Uncle_Bob" datetime="2013-05-22T21:26:00" id="p10">
So sad, what a way to die. My thoughts are with his family and friends.

My only hope is that this is one off situation? But i doubt it, here is a little bit of background information on islamic terrorist activity in the woolwich area of south London.

<a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/10455915">http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/10455915</a>
</post>
<post author="nateusa" datetime="2013-05-22T23:55:00" id="p11">
rip, bizarre the way the murderer comes back on camera and tries to apologize and explain himself.
</post>
<post author="flares" datetime="2013-05-23T03:01:00" id="p12">
<quote orig_author="kittycat1">
the fact they are referencing Allah is going to cause yet another backlash to the peaceful muslims living in UK. Sad times indeed.
</quote>
Maybe the peaceful Muslims should distance themselves from these nutcases and their nutcase preachers and the places of worship where the hatred is spouted and let the backlash begin.

That sermon that was held in the street that time by Abu whatisface. Beggars belief
</post>
<post author="Millsyisland" datetime="2013-05-23T04:23:00" id="p13">
Speechless. Utterly despicable.
</post>
<post author="mikewot" datetime="2013-05-23T04:32:00" id="p14">
To my mind this is no different (assuming it was a member of HM Forces who was attacked) than when the IRA were murdering members of HM Forces in the UK and Germany &amp; Holland. The only difference being the weapon used, an axe instead of guns &amp; bombs.

<a href="http://www.nytimes.com/1988/05/02/world/3-british-servicemen-are-killed-in-ira-attacks-in-netherlands.html">http://www.nytimes.com/1988/05/02/wo...therlands.html</a>
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nick_Spanos_and_Stephen_Melrose">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nick_Sp...tephen_Melrose</a>
<a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2058731/IRA-killers-charged-death-British-soldiers-2009.html">http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/arti...iers-2009.html</a>
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Corporals_killings">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Corporals_killings</a>

And on and on and on goes the list.
</post>
<post author="Millhouse" datetime="2013-05-23T04:49:00" id="p15">
Pretty rough stuff. All home-grown too. The You-Tube videos do not make easy viewing.
</post>
</doc>
