<doc id="ENG_DF_001471_20060426_G00A0FF0Z">
<headline>
Jobs and Robespierre...connection?
</headline>
<post author="jamesi" datetime="2006-04-26T19:17:00" id="p1">
This prolly only applies to history fanatics but....

Does anyone see the correlation between Steve Jobs and Robespierre?
In that, Robespierre essentially became the French Revolution and Steve Jobs is the same way with Apple computer. id rather see if anyone posts something before i keep talking.

cheers
</post>
<post author="mjstew33" datetime="2006-04-26T19:28:00" id="p2">
Now that you mention it - yeah, it does sorta seem that way, doesn't it. <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=":confused:"/>
</post>
<post author="Macaddicttt" datetime="2006-04-26T19:47:00" id="p3">
Umm, the French Revolution was an ideological movement, in which Robespierre went overboard and enforced it violently. Apple Computer is a company that was co-founded by Steve Jobs, kicked Jobs out, and then got him back as CEO. How are they related at all? <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=":confused:"/>

I honestly can't think of anyway in which they're related, even distantly.

And by the way, I'm a history major.
</post>
<post author="jamesi" datetime="2006-04-26T20:15:00" id="p4">
lol oh no the history major has spoken. i enjoyed the brief recap you gave about the revolution and apple's history but that wasnt what i was going for. im strictly talking about the two men themselves.

As the french revolution proceeded, Robespierre came to associate himself more and more with the essence of the conflict at hand. In the revolutions worst years, Robespierre was often noted to speak of an illness he acquired, he said that his life was not interwoven with the revolution. through the massacres and even the terror, Robespierre defended these acts b/c he was convinced that they were needed for the revolution to really come to fruition. i believe Robespierre compromised himself to become this greater cause, and went to extreme lengths to excuse the revolution and allow it to proceed uncontrolled. extreme? yes. but i feel robespierre really did come to represent the cause and errors that were the revolution

now i say robespierre and jobs are alike b/c jobs seems to be apples own "personal representative". Like robespierre, jobs is known for being difficult to work for. strictly b/c jobs refused to compromise the goal of apple in any way, and robespierre did the same by excuses the murders. the two characters persist in thier cause and like wise meet opposition from within thier own cabinet. thats some of what i think

oh and btw im a history major two, well double major with biochem.cheers
</post>
<post author="AvSRoCkCO1067" datetime="2006-04-26T20:20:00" id="p5">
<quote orig_author="Macaddicttt">
Umm, the French Revolution was an ideological movement, in which Robespierre went overboard and enforced it violently. Apple Computer is a company that was co-founded by Steve Jobs, kicked Jobs out, and then got him back as CEO. How are they related at all? <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=":confused:"/>

I honestly can't think of anyway in which they're related, even distantly.

And by the way, I'm a history major.
</quote>

Yeah...I'm no history major, but I am a student of AP European History and...

...Robespierre = bad. You think the French would invite Robespierre back after he was gone 5 years? No. I hope Jobs isn't guillotined!!! <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=":rolleyes:"/> <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=":D"/>
</post>
<post author="Macaddicttt" datetime="2006-04-26T20:23:00" id="p6">
I still don't think that the two are that similar, although I do see what you're saying now. Robespierre became the French Revolution, whereas I think it's more that Apple Computers became Steve Jobs. Robespierre wouldn't do anything to compromise the Revolution, whereas Jobs has to do everything his way.

The Revolution was an ideology, so one could subscribe oneself to its inerrancy. Apple Computers is a company and has no ideology. Jobs cannot believe that Apple Computers is inerrant because Apple Computers is whatever he makes of it. Instead, Jobs, if he believes in the inerrancy of anything, believes in the inerrancy of himself.

EDIT: You know, I probably should mention that I haven't done French history since high school, so... If you have any comparisons of Apple Computers to, say, Eastern Europe between 500 and 1800 or the Byzantine Empire, I'd be much better at responding. <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=":D"/>
</post>
<post author="jamesi" datetime="2006-04-26T20:53:00" id="p7">
<quote orig_author="AvSRoCkCO1067">
Yeah...I'm no history major, but I am a student of AP European History and...

...Robespierre = bad. You think the French would invite Robespierre back after he was gone 5 years? No. I hope Jobs isn't guillotined!!! <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=":rolleyes:"/> <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=":D"/>
</quote>

i think he was somewhat necessary in the early stages of the revolution but its just so disapointing how he didnt use his power as he should. not that he played the dictator (altho there is a clique of historians who do believe so) but that he didnt stop the atrocities around him.
</post>
<post author="amateurmacfreak" datetime="2006-04-26T21:12:00" id="p8">
I get what you mean, but I don't think it's the best analogy. <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=";)"/>
First Jobs has to massacre thousands of people?? <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=":confused:"/> <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=":eek:"/>

Yeah, see the difference? <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=":p"/>

But I do get it's basis... not a bad thought, in the regard you mentioned. <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=":)"/>
</post>
</doc>
