<doc id="ENG_DF_001471_20050703_G00A0FCXB">
<headline>
Steve Jobs To Retire?
</headline>
<post author="deanbo" datetime="2005-07-03T03:57:00" id="p1">
Now that I've got your attention...

He's currently 50? Like someone else said, how long do you want to spend making sure more transistors go onto a chip? I believe that the move to Intel is a sign that retirement is impending, guessing within the next 5 years.

Moving to Intel was a bold move in anyones book, and probably the best chance Apple has to become the world's biggest computer company. After all as Steve Jobs said himself, it's about the software, and who gives a better software experience then Apple? And what better note to retire on? Call it the final stand, swansong, whatever. Which is why I think the switch to Intel has a little more to do with Steve Jobs himself than IBM's roadmap.
</post>
<post author="mad jew" datetime="2005-07-03T04:11:00" id="p2">
Maybe but I don't think the Intel switch has anything to do with it. Steve's a pretty unique CEO so it's pretty difficult to say how far he'll go age-wise but I'm guessing he'll still have a presence at 60. If only to see a pay rise from his single dollar income. <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=";)"/>
</post>
<post author="skubish" datetime="2005-07-03T05:33:00" id="p3">
<quote orig_author="deanbo">
Now that I've got your attention...

He's currently 50? Like someone else said, how long do you want to spend making sure more transistors go onto a chip? I believe that the move to Intel is a sign that retirement is impending, guessing within the next 5 years.

Moving to Intel was a bold move in anyones book, and probably the best chance Apple has to become the world's biggest computer company. After all as Steve Jobs said himself, it's about the software, and who gives a better software experience then Apple? And what better note to retire on? Call it the final stand, swansong, whatever. Which is why I think the switch to Intel has a little more to do with Steve Jobs himself than IBM's roadmap.
</quote>

50 is pretty young to retire. 50 is pretty young to even be a CEO. I doubt it will happen in 10 years. I don't think his ego will allow him to retire.
</post>
<post author="iGary" datetime="2005-07-03T05:40:00" id="p4">
He enjoys what he does too much and has said so. He's not interested in retiring, as he has too many things he still wants to accomplish.

In other words: No. Time. Soon.
</post>
<post author="eva01" datetime="2005-07-03T05:47:00" id="p5">
his chances of retiring are the same as the chances of theo epstein retiring <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=":p"/>
</post>
<post author="Benjamin" datetime="2005-07-03T05:54:00" id="p6">
This sounds sorta like Netcraft confirming that Apple been dying for the last 20 years. Apple isn't about money for Steve its about ego, I doubt he will retire before 65.
</post>
<post author="miloblithe" datetime="2005-07-03T05:59:00" id="p7">
While he could step back a little at some time in the next couple decades, like stop doing the keynotes, barring a major health issue, I can't see him retiring either. If there was some new challenge for him I could see him jumping ship and taking on a new company, but just retiring bacause he's old? Not a chance. He's not.
</post>
<post author="Abstract" datetime="2005-07-03T06:09:00" id="p8">
I doubt he would voluntarily retire before 75. <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=":p"/>
</post>
<post author="Dagless" datetime="2005-07-03T06:25:00" id="p9">
<quote orig_author="skubish">
50 is pretty young to retire. 50 is pretty young to even be a CEO. I doubt it will happen in 10 years. I don't think his ego will allow him to retire.
</quote>

im only 19 and CEO of my very own company <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=":cool:"/> but does that count for a 1 man freeware game making company? AND i earn significantly less than $1 per year. try nothing <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=":)"/>

but seriously. i doubt Jobs will retire for a while yet. he's hoisted Apple up and i doubt they'd let him go quietly.
</post>
<post author="JeffTL" datetime="2005-07-03T06:41:00" id="p10">
He's got it pretty easy, I'd say, even with the international travel <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=":p"/>

My money's on the 65-70 range if Apple stays in the black, and I can't say about Pixar.
</post>
<post author="Artful Dodger" datetime="2005-07-03T06:41:00" id="p11">
When you love doing something it's never work or a job but a way of life for those people and hardly about money, more an idea being brought to life. Since he still has things to accomplish (what they might be?) he will be around for a long time to come with Apple, after all it was his in the first place and now it's the second time around <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=":)"/>
</post>
<post author="katie ta achoo" datetime="2005-07-03T11:36:00" id="p12">
I can't see Steve Jobs retiring anytime soon.

I'd like to see him giving a keynote at MacWorld 2018, wheeling around the stage in his wifi-enabled PowerChair, using mind control to use the PowerMac P39.

That'd be so cool...
</post>
<post author="ham_man" datetime="2005-07-03T14:17:00" id="p13">
Nah. Just speculation. Assuming he isn't fired for some reason, it will not happen as long as he can walk onto the stage and give a Keynote...
</post>
</doc>
