<doc id="ENG_DF_001503_20160121_G00A0GN6O">
<headline>
If Trump becomes President
</headline>
<post author="jjmb" datetime="2016-01-21T21:01:00" id="p1">
will you still be here next year? Or will you be looking for opportunities elsewhere?

I was talking to my 26 yr youngest daughter yesterday and it appears she is considering upping sticks and moving back to the UK. Actually that is just the excuse she wants as she has expressed the desire to move back for a while now but it appears, a Trump presidency would the last straw. Not sure going back to the UK is brilliant idea but I understand the sentiment.
</post>
<post author="sir_eccles" datetime="2016-01-21T21:09:00" id="p2">
People of various political leanings in many countries have promised to leave should "X" be elected for years, decades even. I have yet to ever see one who actually followed through.

Hang on, according to this Phil Collins really did leave. But apparently no one noticed. <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/newsbeat/article/32590242/do-celebrities-leave-the-country-after-a-general-election-no---not-really">http://www.bbc.co.uk/newsbeat/articl...o---not-really</a>

Trump is unlikely even to get the GOP nomination let alone the big prize.
</post>
<post author="thinbrit" datetime="2016-01-21T21:11:00" id="p3">
I heard the same rhetoric when Obama was first elected.

There will be lots of talk and teeth gnashing with very little action.

It could be worse, what if that woman gets elected <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/sneaky.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="jjmb" datetime="2016-01-21T21:13:00" id="p4">
<quote orig_author="sir_eccles">
Trump is unlikely even to get the GOP nomination let alone the big prize.
</quote>
Hope you are right, we begin to find out soon but I suspect it might be a convention nomination for at least the GOP and if Sanders can get the momentum really rolling, the Dems as well. Just hope its not Cruz or Trump.
</post>
<post author="anotherlimey" datetime="2016-01-21T22:23:00" id="p5">
<quote orig_author="sir_eccles">
People of various political leanings in many countries have promised to leave should "X" be elected for years, decades even. I have yet to ever see one who actually followed through.

Hang on, according to this Phil Collins really did leave. But apparently no one noticed. <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/newsbeat/article/32590242/do-celebrities-leave-the-country-after-a-general-election-no---not-really">Do celebrities leave the country after a general election? No - not really - BBC Newsbeat</a>

Trump is unlikely even to get the GOP nomination let alone the big prize.
</quote>
I thought he was leading the polls and favorite with the bookies?
</post>
<post author="sir_eccles" datetime="2016-01-21T22:24:00" id="p6">
<quote orig_author="anotherlimey">
I thought he was leading the polls and favorite with the bookies?
</quote>
Which is essentially meaningless right now.
</post>
<post author="dc koop" datetime="2016-01-22T01:29:00" id="p7">
I'm too settled here to think about leaving. My wife wouldn't want to leave the US anyway since she was born here. California is a strongly Democrat State and Trump's policies wouldn't interfere much with the internal running of this State.

The main thing to remember also is that he's got 4 years.. no more. If he nominates Palin for his VP he wont even get that
</post>
<post author="kimilseung" datetime="2016-01-22T01:40:00" id="p8">
Why would you leave? If certain things changes, then maybe that would be a time to think about it, but an election may change who is in power, but can they do anything with that power, whether via the system or the inclination.
</post>
<post author="Jsmth321" datetime="2016-01-22T02:40:00" id="p9">
If Trump did win, I'd venture he will calm down and realize he won't have the powers he thinks he will to willy nilly change things.

Candidates always seem to talk big, then realize once they win, how much they actually cannot do.
</post>
<post author="dc koop" datetime="2016-01-22T04:54:00" id="p10">
<quote orig_author="Jsmth321">
If Trump did win, I'd venture he will calm down and realize he won't have the powers he thinks he will to willy nilly change things.

Candidates always seem to talk big, then realize once they win, how much they actually cannot do.
</quote>
He'll fire anyone who gets in his way !
</post>
<post author="Pulaski" datetime="2016-01-22T10:39:00" id="p11">
<quote orig_author="Jsmth321">
If Trump did win, I'd venture he will calm down and realize he won't have the powers he thinks he will to willy nilly change things.

Candidates always seem to talk big, then realize once they win, how much they actually cannot do.
</quote>
It really depends what happens to Congress. Without the support of both the House and Senate it is difficult for the President to do much, with the support of neither the task becomes much harder. This has been the pattern for most of the past 23 years - Bill Clinton faced a hostile congress for much of his presidency, George W Bush was out of step with his own party and achieved relatively little, and since the Tea Party revolution in 2010 President Obama hasn't been able to do much either - his landmark achievement of the Affordable Care Act is pretty much his only memorable achievement. <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/rolleyes.gif"/>

FWIW I left the UK as soon as I could after Tony Blair's hapless mob took over. <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/rofl.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="scot47" datetime="2016-01-22T14:12:00" id="p12">
Tony Blair did a good job of enriching himself and some of his cronies !
</post>
</doc>
