<doc id="ENG_DF_001503_20131008_G00A0A9P3">
<headline>
Hi from South Carolina - 'Evidence Response Review
</headline>
<post author="PeteHardy27" datetime="2013-10-08T19:01:00" id="p1">
Hi I'm Pete originally from Durham, England but now living near Myrtle Beach, South Carolina with my American wife Yolanda. We applied for my Green Card in August, had my biometrics done in September and just found out that my I-765 is approved (Oct 4th) and I should have the card within 30 days. My I-485 has been stuck on 'Evidence Response Review' for weeks and my I-130 is stuck at Initial review. Anyone else at this stage or knows roughly how much longer it will take ? I am hoping to be done soon so I can plan a trip back home to see my family for Christmas. I didn't bother filing a I-131 as I didn't want to complicate things, I think the best thing is to stay here until it's complete.
Thanks in advance for any advice/info and I hope everyone else's immigration experiences are as straightforward as mine <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/biggrin.gif"/>
Pete
</post>
<post author="civilservant" datetime="2013-10-08T21:20:00" id="p2">
No comments except to say that I know Conway/M.Beach well - in fact we intend to live there in a couple of years (Conway)

<img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/welcome.gif"/> to BE <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/smile.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Noorah101" datetime="2013-10-08T21:36:00" id="p3">
<quote orig_author="PeteHardy27">
Anyone else at this stage or knows roughly how much longer it will take ?
</quote>

In general, it should take around 6 months from start to finish for an AOS process.

<quote>
</quote>

If you also applied for AP, you should receive a "combo card" with combined EAD and AP so you can use that to visit back home while waiting for your AOS to be adjudicated.

<quote>
</quote>
Ah, in that case...never mind. Filing I-131 for AP doesn't complicate anything unless you are not eligible to use AP (you're in an overstay situation, for example). Now you might as well wait until you have your green card in hand.

Filing the AOS package in August will put you at around Feb 2014 for AOS approval...unless you get an RFE, or unless the government shutdown affects you, in which case it could be longer.

Rene
</post>
<post author="PeteHardy27" datetime="2013-10-08T21:37:00" id="p4">
Give me a shout when you get here, I know of another 3 Brits living here we can have a little Ex Pats club lool
</post>
<post author="PeteHardy27" datetime="2013-10-08T21:39:00" id="p5">
Thanks for the info Rene
</post>
<post author="PeteHardy27" datetime="2013-10-15T04:43:00" id="p6">
Just got an Email from USCIS, my I-765 has been mailed, unfortunately because of the shutdown I wont be able to get my SSN straight away. On the bright side I'm one step closer
</post>
<post author="ian-mstm" datetime="2013-10-15T12:02:00" id="p7">
<quote orig_author="PeteHardy27">
... because of the shutdown I wont be able to get my SSN straight away.
</quote>
You don't need a SSN to look for work, accept a job, or start working. Although, it comes in quite handy if you need a driver's license... or want to get paid! <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/smile.gif"/>

Ian
</post>
<post author="PeteHardy27" datetime="2013-10-17T03:27:00" id="p8">
Another Email today, my I-485 interview is being scheduled within 30 days, everything is starting to happen now !!!
</post>
<post author="PeteHardy27" datetime="2013-10-25T04:33:00" id="p9">
I now have my SSN
</post>
</doc>
