<doc id="ENG_DF_001471_20100604_G00A0FJ1P">
<headline>
How Apple can transform Foxconn's iPhone factories
</headline>
<post author="MacBytes" datetime="2010-06-04T08:22:00" id="p1">
Category: Opinion/Interviews
Link: <a href="http://www.macbytes.com/link.php?sid=20100604112203">How Apple can transform Foxconn's iPhone factories</a>
Description: : The wave of suicides among workers at Apple partner Foxconn cannot be excused by weak comparisons of meaningless statistics -- not when so much of the world's attention is focused on Apple. This is a chance for Apple to change the world -- again...

Posted on <a href="http://www.macbytes.com">MacBytes.com</a>
Approved by Mudbug
</post>
<post author="itsjared" datetime="2010-06-04T08:23:00" id="p2">
Why should it be Apple's problem? Will it stop you form buying an iPhone?
</post>
<post author="markcres" datetime="2010-06-04T08:44:00" id="p3">
<quote orig_author="itsjared">
Why should it be Apple's problem? Will it stop you form buying an iPhone?
</quote>

That's like saying, "One of my slaves has gone lame because of his bad treatment on my plantation...what has it got to do with me?"
</post>
<post author="zombitronic" datetime="2010-06-04T09:04:00" id="p4">
<quote orig_author="itsjared">
Why should it be Apple's problem? Will it stop you form buying an iPhone?
</quote>

No, it won't stop most people from buying an iPhone. But it is indirectly Apple's problem.

<quote orig_author="markcres">
That's like saying, "One of my slaves has gone lame because of his bad treatment on my plantation...what has it got to do with me?"
</quote>

Not exactly. It's not Apple's factory, or as your analogy calls it, "plantation." It's Foxconn's. But they do produce goods for Apple, which is why Apple should get involved.
</post>
<post author="supercaliber" datetime="2010-06-04T09:17:00" id="p5">
If any of us really gave a flying s*** about sweat shops we wouldn't buy the iPhone or any products made in factories like foxconn.

But get real, every one of you and myself included will line up, put down our credit card and without thinking twice spend more in 5 minutes than those poor schleps make in an entire month.

We rant an rave about the atrocities of slave labor and the abhorrent history of our country and plantations, but then we have no problem whatsoever supporting the fleecing of human life in China and elsewhere in the world, with our own personal dollars, yes you are perpetuating this type of human pillaging even today.

I don't have a problem calling myself a hypocrite, because unless I stop spending my money on this crap, then I am a hyporcrite.

That goes the same for every one of you, especially if you call yourself a liberal. I am conservative, but I think liberals buying iPhones are actually even more hypocritical than me, cheers!
</post>
<post author="Lord Vader" datetime="2010-06-04T09:43:00" id="p6">
<quote orig_author="zombitronic">
No, it won't stop most people from buying an iPhone. But it is indirectly Apple's problem.

Not exactly. It's not Apple's factory, or as your analogy calls it, "plantation." It's Foxconn's. But they do produce goods for Apple, which is why Apple should get involved.
</quote>

It's also a problem for other companies making stuff there.
</post>
</doc>
