<doc id="ENG_DF_001471_20130411_G00A0FN18">
<headline>
What do you think about Google's Privacy Policy?
</headline>
<post author="Manicmonday" datetime="2013-04-11T19:51:00" id="p1">
I'm an IOS user because I value the quality of Apple's products, and the security they offer. I'm afraid that Google is following us more than they should be allowed to. Every website has Google Ads, and it occurred to me that Google can make a map of everything we do on the internet. Google ads are on almost every website, and the only way we can opt out of Google altogether is to not use the internet. It's almost impossible to avoid using something made by Google. I've always wondered what kind of data Google collects, and have been trying to learn about this kind of thing, by reading all news that I find on this topic. I was wondering what you guys think. Do you mind Google recording everything you do online? Do you think France and Germany should ban Google's services that violate our privacy rights? Should we be protected from this kind of tracking? The articles below talked a lot about this topic, and I wonder what fellow Apple owners think. I wish Apple would release a search engine and computer advertising so we wouldn't have to worry about this stuff =/

<a href="http://seekingalpha.com/article/1289181-google-s-project-glass-a-huge-threat-to-privacy">Google's 'Project Glass': A Huge Threat To Privacy?</a>
<a href="http://www.counterpunch.org/2013/04/11/how-europes-fight-with-google-over-privacy-ignores-real-privacy/">How Europes Fight with Google Over Privacy Ignores Real Privacy</a>
<a href="http://www.pcworld.com/article/2033375/google-must-defend-privacy-policies-to-6-european-agencies.html">Google must defend privacy policies to 6 European agencies</a>
<a href="http://seekingalpha.com/article/1327131-google-s-legal-problems-in-europe-could-hurt-earnings">Google's Legal Problems In Europe Could Hurt Earnings</a>
<a href="http://www.computing.co.uk/ctg/opinion/2260579/googles-privacy-woes">Google's privacy woes are just the beginning</a>
</post>
<post author="tech4all" datetime="2013-04-12T00:58:00" id="p2">
You seem to be making Google out to be a bad guy and Apple to be the hero. I think it's naive to think Apple is all innocent or any company for that matter. Plenty here have too must trust in Apple. Don't get me wrong, I like Apple...OS X. And Google with Android. Works great despite what you'll hear from some users.

Honestly, I think you're being a bit paranoid. Yea it we're being tracked. Call it Google, call it Facebook (aka: Big Brother). Heck look at your iPhone, how do you know nobody's listening to you or watching you? It has a built in mic and camera! Just because it's off doesn't mean it's off. You don't know who has connections to your phone and who's doing what with that data.

Is that possible? I think so. But technology comes at a price and I don't mean money... <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=";)"/>

No I don't wear a tin foil hat. <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=":cool:"/>
</post>
<post author="rocknblogger" datetime="2013-04-12T01:09:00" id="p3">
Personally I think this is ridiculous. Every single company that is involved with software, the Internet, mobile devices, search and advertising is tracking you. I have never heard of a single case where someone was harmed because of this. Whether from Google or any other big company like Apple, Microsoft, Yahoo or Bing (MS). I just haven't seen it. I think you should be careful with your information but other than that, I don't worry about it.
</post>
<post author="ChristianJapan" datetime="2013-04-12T01:15:00" id="p4">
Use Bing for search and give Microsoft some piece of your information. Finally we will not avoid that kind of tracking as Google and others mainly generate income from ads.

Not that I'm feeling too comfortable with it and for example don't log in to Google when I search with them. And I use privacy setting etc. finally nothing to hide...

Or we say by-by to free Internet and pay for each search and email ? <img src="styles/default/xenforo/clear.png" alt=":eek:"/>
</post>
<post author="DesertEagle" datetime="2013-04-12T02:15:00" id="p5">
Privacy policy?? I wish they had one!

Just wait until the day when the insurance companies demand information on what kind of diseases you have googled over the past few years. "Nothing to hide"?
</post>
<post author="Jessica Lares" datetime="2013-04-12T02:21:00" id="p6">
<quote orig_author="rocknblogger">
Personally I think this is ridiculous. Every single company that is involved with software, the Internet, mobile devices, search and advertising is tracking you. I have never heard of a single case where someone was harmed because of this. Whether from Google or any other big company like Apple, Microsoft, Yahoo or Bing (MS). I just haven't seen it. I think you should be careful with your information but other than that, I don't worry about it.
</quote>

This. I've been surfing the internet since the mid-90's. And I have used it pretty much everyday since. You think there's an issue now? How about when there wasn't even very much regulation on the internet?

All this information is just for research purposes and nothing more. They care about the keywords and nothing more.
</post>
</doc>
