<doc id="ENG_DF_001503_20140520_G00A0GK5U">
<headline>
First world problems
</headline>
<post author="sir_eccles" datetime="2014-05-20T20:05:00" id="p1">
Having to update the wiki article on same sex marriage on an almost daily basis to list those states who have had their bans overturned by a judge.

Round of applause for the most recent entrants to the 21st Century, Oregon and Pennsylvania.
</post>
<post author="Michael" datetime="2014-05-20T20:54:00" id="p2">
Actually I am very surprised that the decisions have been overturned quickly without much of a struggle from the right. With the religious right in control of the republican party, I suspected much greater resistance with rioting in the streets but opposition has been more like a whimper than a bang.

However in liberal France, riots have occurred putting fear into the government about making gay marriage legal. In France I guess it's ok to have a mistress but not ok to be gay. <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/wink.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="robin1234" datetime="2014-05-20T21:06:00" id="p3">
Is it possible the right have quietly decided to give up on the defence of marriage and anti-gay issues? Maybe the Republicans eying up $$$ they are losing from potential gay &amp; lesbian donors?
</post>
<post author="Michael" datetime="2014-05-20T21:22:00" id="p4">
<quote orig_author="robin1234">
Is it possible the right have quietly decided to give up on the defence of marriage and anti-gay issues? Maybe the Republicans eying up $$$ they are losing from potential gay &amp; lesbian donors?
</quote>
It's against their character. They are still fighting Obamacare as the work of the devil and there are a lot more votes they could pick up from the center and left if they supported Obamacare.
</post>
<post author="sir_eccles" datetime="2014-05-20T21:41:00" id="p5">
<quote orig_author="Michael">
Actually I am very surprised that the decisions have been overturned quickly without much of a struggle from the right. With the religious right in control of the republican party, I suspected much greater resistance with rioting in the streets but opposition has been more like a whimper than a bang.
</quote>
I don't know. In a couple of places at least the judge has been very strict on who has standing to defend the laws much to the dismay of organizations like NOM. It comes down to Governors wary of a tide against them in an election year plus noting the SCOTUS ruling against DOMA, how can they in all conscience defend it.
</post>
<post author="rpjs" datetime="2014-05-20T21:49:00" id="p6">
<quote orig_author="Michael">
However in liberal France, riots have occurred putting fear into the government about making gay marriage legal. In France I guess it's ok to have a mistress but not ok to be gay. <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/wink.gif"/>
</quote>
It's not that "likely to cause a riot in France" is a particularly high bar though. We were on holiday in Avignon when Sarko was elected President and the next morning the breakfast news very matter-of-factly reported the "manifestations anti-Sarkozy" that had broken out across the country the night before when the results came in.
</post>
<post author="WEBlue" datetime="2014-05-22T20:22:00" id="p7">
<quote orig_author="Michael">
However in liberal France, riots have occurred putting fear into the government about making gay marriage legal. In France I guess it's ok to have a mistress but not ok to be gay. <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/wink.gif"/>
</quote>
This doesn't surprise me. "Liberal France" is Roman Catholic. So yes, a mistress is fine, being gay is not... yet.
</post>
<post author="civilservant" datetime="2014-05-22T22:10:00" id="p8">
Explain something to me - how can a Federal judge overturn a state ban? Or have I been reading shoddy reporting?
</post>
<post author="Michael" datetime="2014-05-23T02:01:00" id="p9">
<quote orig_author="civilservant">
Explain something to me - how can a Federal judge overturn a state ban? Or have I been reading shoddy reporting?
</quote>
The federal courts are empowered to rule on anything pertaining to the US constitution. There is a system in place for rulings and appeals until the issue is brought before the supreme court. If the supreme court elects to hear the case, then their ruling will be final. If they don't elect to hear the case, the last ruling is final.

Since DOMA was struck down by the supreme court, many of the state bans may be in conflict with DOMA. Therefore when someone appeals to a federal judge, that judge's ruling (in his/her opinion) is just a reflection of the ruling made by the supreme court. However the attorney general of the state can appeal that decision but often the decision is left in place before it gets to the supreme court and the supreme court refuses to hear that appeal.
</post>
<post author="jeepster" datetime="2014-05-23T05:10:00" id="p10">
<quote orig_author="civilservant">
Explain something to me - how can a Federal judge overturn a state ban? Or have I been reading shoddy reporting?
</quote>
The courts have the authority to rule on the constitutionality of any legislation and are invoking the 14th Amendment, equal protection under the law. They can appeal but they're not, probably because it's an election year and they figure it's a losing issue.
</post>
</doc>
