<doc id="ENG_DF_000354_20160220_G00A04O3N">
<headline>
Get stripped searched in Wisconsin
</headline>
<post author="6556" datetime="2016-02-20T19:03:00" id="p1">
Plan Expanding Police's Ability To Conduct Strip Searches Passes Assembly

..."regardless of whether the target of the search has been charged with a misdemeanor or felony."...

On our local NPR station I heard comment that this includes "suspects detained"
any by definition a person stopped for a burnt out tail light is "being detained"

Our state government is about to allow our law enforcement officers to conduct "Strip searches".

<a href="http://www.wpr.org/plan-expanding-polices-ability-conduct-strip-searches-passes-assembly">http://www.wpr.org/plan-expanding-po...asses-assembly</a>
</post>
<post author="last1standing" datetime="2016-02-21T08:07:00" id="p2">
admit it....you want it
</post>
<post author="Xshot" datetime="2016-02-21T09:59:00" id="p3">
As long as we have bloated, full-time, career legislators they will pander to all special interest groups - no matter how small or large.
</post>
<post author="catmando" datetime="2016-02-21T10:33:00" id="p4">
wonder if they will throw in a spanking too?
</post>
<post author="TachMed" datetime="2016-02-21T10:35:00" id="p5">
And if the citizens stand by and say nothing, once it goes through you can't complain after
</post>
<post author="Cabinet Maker" datetime="2016-02-21T10:38:00" id="p6">
That could be quite a show on the side of the road. In the winter.

Check your tail lights! <img src="http://www.survivalistboards.com/images/smilies/biggrin.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="catmando" datetime="2016-02-21T10:44:00" id="p7">
wonder if they'll take into consideration "the shrink factor" for the males when its cold outside?
</post>
<post author="WestTennWoodsman" datetime="2016-02-21T11:01:00" id="p8">
<quote orig_author="catmando">
wonder if they'll take into consideration "the shrink factor" for the males when its cold outside?
</quote>

Just tell em "I'm a grower, not a show-er"
</post>
<post author="Cabinet Maker" datetime="2016-02-21T11:10:00" id="p9">
Of course, if it's a good looking female officer doing the pat down... <img src="http://www.survivalistboards.com/images/smilies/biggrin.gif"/>
Ok, this thread is gonna go south pretty quick.....
</post>
<post author="6556" datetime="2016-02-21T18:56:00" id="p10">
Will scooter sign this bill?

Do the scooter supporters think that scooter should sign this bill?

Do the scooter supporters expect scooter to sign this bill?

Think scooter would allow this bill to be passed around if he was still in the presidential race?
</post>
<post author="240Geezer" datetime="2016-02-21T19:27:00" id="p11">
I don't think it's s good idea.
On so many levels.
</post>
<post author="6556" datetime="2016-03-02T17:11:00" id="p12">
Well, scooter signed the bill.

<a href="http://www.wpr.org/governor-inks-dozens-more-bills-tuesday-including-strip-search-expansion">http://www.wpr.org/governor-inks-doz...arch-expansion</a>

----The strip search bill expands on an existing policy that said anyone arrested or detained on suspicion of a crime that isn't a felony could be strip-searched only if the person would be held with others for at least 12 hours. The updated policy removes the 12-hour requirement----

Detained is anytime a law officer has stopped you. If you're walking down the street and an officer stops you to ask a question (did you see something?)
Stopped for a brake light? you "are being detained". And they now have the right to strip search you.

I guess this is what the supporters of Scott Walker want!

Thank god he dropped out of the presidential race!
</post>
</doc>
