<doc id="ENG_DF_001503_20160404_G00A0GO41">
<headline>
Black lives matter
</headline>
<post author="magnumpi" datetime="2016-04-04T22:37:00" id="p1">
So I was watching a protest just now on CBC were Wynne was stood amonst "Black Lives Matter" protesters.

Can anyone explain why only black lives matter? Is this not like reverse racism? Sammy Yatim wasn't black what about his life?

I know it's about police v minority's but black people are not the only ones, what about the rest of the comunity!!

Should it not be a "civilian lives matter demonstration" ?

<a href="http://m.thestar.com/#/article/news/gta/2016/04/04/kathleen-wynne-meets-with-black-lives-matter-protesters.html">http://m.thestar.com/#/article/news/...rotesters.html</a>
</post>
<post author="bats" datetime="2016-04-05T01:23:00" id="p2">
Nothing in BLM says that other lives don't matter too.

From Wikipedia.

"United States President Barack Obama spoke to the debate between Black Lives Matter and All Lives Matter.[138] Obama said, "I think that the reason that the organizers used the phrase Black Lives Matter was not because they were suggesting that no one else's lives matter... rather what they were suggesting was there is a specific problem that is happening in the African American community that's not happening in other communities." He also said "that is a legitimate issue that we've got to address." "
</post>
<post author="BritInParis" datetime="2016-04-05T01:40:00" id="p3">
It's not "Only Black Lives Matter", rather "Black Lives Matter Too".
</post>
<post author="magnumpi" datetime="2016-04-05T01:47:00" id="p4">
<quote orig_author="BritInParis">
It's not "Only Black Lives Matter", rather "Black Lives Matter Too".
</quote>
The hash tag #BLMTO u mean? The TO means Toronto

I do agree tho that Black Lives Matter Too would be a better slogan.
</post>
<post author="Alan2005" datetime="2016-04-05T02:18:00" id="p5">
<quote orig_author="BritInParis">
It's not "Only Black Lives Matter", rather "Black Lives Matter Too".
</quote>

This.

<quote orig_author="magnumpi">
I do agree tho that Black Lives Matter Too would be a better slogan.
</quote>
If you think about the campaign in a positive manner rather assuming the worst about people then the "too" is implicit.

(btw, there's no such thing as reverse racism. It's just racism)
</post>
<post author="Oink" datetime="2016-04-05T04:43:00" id="p6">
<quote orig_author="magnumpi">
So I was watching a protest just now on CBC were Wynne was stood amonst "Black Lives Matter" protesters.

Can anyone explain why only black lives matter? Is this not like reverse racism? Sammy Yatim wasn't black what about his life?

I know it's about police v minority's but black people are not the only ones, what about the rest of the comunity!!

Should it not be a "civilian lives matter demonstration" ?

<a href="http://m.thestar.com/#/article/news/gta/2016/04/04/kathleen-wynne-meets-with-black-lives-matter-protesters.html">http://m.thestar.com/#/article/news/...rotesters.html</a>
</quote>

Its because in the US black lives don’t matter and have never mattered. They've been and continue to be, a brutalized, subjugated and tortured people. Historically white lives have mattered whereas black ones haven't. To even suggest that the two (white and black lives in the US) are comparable shows at best a scant understanding of the reality...
</post>
<post author="Siouxie" datetime="2016-04-05T04:49:00" id="p7">
<img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/popcorn.gif"/>

Lets make sure we keep it civilised peeps...

<img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/smile.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Oink" datetime="2016-04-05T04:58:00" id="p8">
<quote orig_author="Siouxie">
<img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/popcorn.gif"/>

Lets make sure we keep it civilised peeps...

<img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/smile.gif"/>
</quote>
Fair enough. I'm not racist some of my best friends are white.
</post>
<post author="magnumpi" datetime="2016-04-05T11:54:00" id="p9">
<quote orig_author="Oink">
Its because in the US black lives don’t matter and have never mattered. They've been and continue to be, a brutalized, subjugated and tortured people. Historically white lives have mattered whereas black ones haven't. To even suggest that the two (white and black lives in the US) are comparable shows at best a scant understanding of the reality...
</quote>
This actually makes sense, I presumed it's more a response to the US division regarding black and white folks. So why did Wynne came out and agree that Toronto had issues. Is it getting that bad here too?
</post>
<post author="MillieF" datetime="2016-04-05T12:08:00" id="p10">
Surely the problem is that visual and identifiable minorities do matter tremendously as they serve a central role as the ones we wish to vilify and blame for our socio economic woes. I've never spent much time in the warmer near Mexico bits of the States, but I believe the Mexicans are very poorly regarded there and not just by Trump.

I don't like the term 'Black lives Matter' either. 'People Matter' might be adopted in North America gererally, but they don't....'normal' black, white, indigenous men and particularly women are poorly regarded individually unless they have money, or are loud and energetic enough to defend themselves. It's a shame there isn't a magic wand that could homogenize the lot of us, one sex only, and then we'd be bound to get along, wouldn't we <img src="http://britishexpats.com/forum/images/smilies/unsure.gif"/>

North American policing in general seems appalling, but I suppose we only hear the bad bits, I really hope there might be good bits too?
</post>
</doc>
